Younes Basil
Muhammad, from Mosul
I am 24 years old
I am not studying or
working at the moment
Interviewer: Are you married?
Witness: No, I’m not married
Tell me about your first
detention experience
Where were you arrested,
and where did they take you?
How long did you stay in the place where you
were detained, and what happened to you there?
They took me from the house
To the Dawasa Center
I stayed with them there
And I was tortured, and so on
Then I was transferred to the
Qaimaqam Prison
I stayed there for a week
Then they transferred
me back here
Two days after I was transferred
there, the place was bombed
A plane bombed it
I came and spent one
month and twenty days here
Interviewer: Alright
When they took you there,
what day was it and at what time?
And what was the date when they
came and took you from the house?
What conversation
took place between you?
They took me before Ramadan
They said, We just
need you for a question
We only want to ask you something,
then we’ll return you home
When we reached the
center, they didn’t let me leave
And they told my father, Go, we’ll
keep your son and we won’t let him out
So I stayed two days
Ramadan was near
Ramadan was approaching
I spent the whole
month of Ramadan here
On Laylat al-Qadr,
they cut off my hand
They took me out of here
and amputated my hand
I was put alone in a
room at the Dawasa Center
From morning until evening
Later they put me in a
car — me and three others
They seated us in the car
They shackled our hands
and blindfolded our eyes
And they covered us so
we couldn’t see the place
And we were
transferred to a house
Interviewer: Was the interrogation
and torture carried out in that house?
Yes
Alright, continue the story
We were transferred
there, to the house
Those others — I didn’t
know what their charge was
And my charge was theft, so they
brought me and put me in the room
And they started
interrogating me
About how I’d entered,
what I took, and what I did
I stayed two to three
days in the house
Then I was transferred
afterwards to Qaimaqam
I stayed for about a week,
maybe eight days, at the Qaimaqam
Or a week, roughly
ten days in total
I left there, and they also
brought me before a judge there
He asked me about my
charge too, and I said–Theft
I heard sounds of
flogging and beating
When I went in to see him
they took me back again
When I entered, he was sitting
behind me and I was sitting like this now
I was also sitting on a chair
And he sat behind
me asking questions
But he was lying on a bed
He asked me a
number of questions
About my charge
And I answered him
After that they took
me back to the hall
They brought me into a large hall
that had once been for weddings
At the Qaimaqam, it
used to be a wedding hall
Huge, over there
I reckon it held
300 to 400 people
A large hall
With a stage for parties and
a spot for the bride and groom
This hall was
turned into a prison
So we stayed there, and whoever wanted to
walk could walk inside because it was so big
They dressed us in
dishdashas, robes about this long
At prayer time anyone who wanted to
do wudu [ablution] could go to the toilets
There were three or four toilets
Whoever went into the
toilets could take his time
The Hisba [religious police] car
came and they took us out of there
They put us in the Hisba vehicle
and brought us here afterward
They brought us here
and I didn’t know the place
They took me in through
here—there was a parking lot
They had seized it
We stood in the yard after they
unloaded us from the vehicle
There were about seven to
eight of us when they brought us
They had brought
people from another hall
They made us enter with our heads lowered,
our hands shackled, and our eyes blindfolded
They brought us
in through this door
They led us from here and took
us up the stairs to the hall above
I served my sentence in the hall
Interviewer: When you
entered this courtyard
Did you enter the yard and corridor
while your eyes were blindfolded?
And your hands were shackled?
If your eyes were blindfolded, what
sounds could you hear around you?
They brought me in with my eyes
blindfolded and my hands shackled
They took us in through here and I could
hear the sounds of flogging and their chatter
But I didn’t know what
they were talking about
The sound of cleaning weapons
and the click of their walkie-talkies
Which they used to call with
They made us go up a bit here,
then continued with us to the hall
Interviewer: Okay
Do you remember the ISIS members
present, their names and nationalities?
Their appearance?
They were all masked
I don’t remember them or know
their names, they were all masked
Even their hands weren’t visible
Interviewer: Have you
heard about women’s cells?
Or cells for ISIS members
being punished inside this prison?
There weren’t any in this place.
Interviewer: There
were no women’s cells?
There were cells for women, but not
for ISIS members themselves.
This room was for
women, and that room too.
Interviewer: And the rest of the
rooms, do you recall their purpose?
No, I only remember
there was a hall here.
In this hall, for major charges.
For example, someone was caught
with a Kia truck transporting cigarettes
And other materials they
used to bring from outside Mosul
Interviewer: Can you describe the sound
you heard from the women’s cells?
I heard their children’s
voices, I mean
Their children crying
From that window over there
Interviewer: Do you have a memory
related to this spot in this corridor?
With ISIS?
I only remember that I entered this place
normally and left with my hand amputated.
Interviewer: Did you notice display
screens showing ISIS videos in this yard?
No, in the yard there weren’t
any, only in their official’s room.
There was a screen
Interviewer: The sharia judge’s room?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Regarding
the three cells you were in...
How did you spend
your time in them
Is there a particular memory
from those cells you can’t forget?
How did you feel when
we walked in them?
I felt that when I entered my hand
was there, and when I left it wasn’t
I spent the time sleeping
Only when prayer time came, I
prayed and went back to sleep
Interviewer: How did
the ISIS jailers treat you?
At prayer times...
Did they act violently to
make you stand up for prayer?
They came at prayer time and
knocked on the door, on the bars
Shouting—It’s prayer
time, get up, pray, get up
Interviewer: Did they supervise your performance of the prayer?
Witness: What do you mean?
Interviewer: Meaning they came to
make sure you were praying and then left?
Yes, one of them
stood at the door
Everyone performed wudu
[ablution] and the prayer was collective
They prayed and finished,
then each returned to his place
Interviewer: What sounds did you
hear from inside the detention room?
And how was the smell
of the three rooms?
I mean, the smell wasn’t good
And we heard the voices
of those they were flogging
And the crying of those
children I talked about
Whose mothers were
here and being flogged
I mean, I heard many things
And sounds
Interviewer: Was
the talk between you
Or talk in general, was it
forbidden inside the cell?
Between you and
the prisoners with you?
No, no, it wasn't forbidden
We would talk and chat
But only a little
We couldn't talk
about other things
Only about prayer matters
Anyone who wanted to
learn the prayer and its details
Interviewer: Until what
hour did you talk together
Did they come tell
you to stop and sleep?
Or was it okay to
talk at other times?
At night after the prayer
We chatted, then the
jailer came and yelled
Enough, it's time to sleep
And everyone slept
No one stayed
awake—lights off, all slept
If they heard anyone
talking or making a sound
They would come up immediately
They knocked—Who was
shouting? Who spoke?
They checked,
then went back down
I only remember someone
standing here with a sword
I looked at him from above
He was standing
here, in this spot
That's what I remember
It never leaves my mind
Interviewer: What
did that man look like?
He was huge and masked;
you couldn't see his face
Even his hands were
hidden because of tattoos
So no one would recognize him
It was Ramadan—at suhoor we
got samoon [finger roll] and tahini
The samoon bread was stale
It crumbled when you held it
And they brought the tahini dip
And a pot of tea
Everyone ate suhoor,
prayed, and slept
At iftar they brought soup
Or rice, or bulgur
That's the food
Interviewer: And was everyone forced to fast?
Witness: Yes
Anyone who didn't
fast was punished
And anyone who didn't pray too
Even long pants got you punished
Interviewer: Punished while inside the cell?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Were the iftar
and suhoor meals in Ramadan
Enough and filling?
Half the people didn't eat
because it wasn't enough
They brought a small
pot for 70 to 80 people
So who would it be enough for?
It isn't only one or two people
Interviewer: Seventy to eighty people inside each room?
Witness: Yes
So who would it be enough for?
They brought a small pot, threw it by the
door, turned their backs, and walked away
From their own food and drink
Interviewer: When you were inside the room,
you mentioned there were many jars of tahini
Were all the jars in your room
They used to
bring five to six jars
And distribute them to the rooms
So whoever got hungry
would take some and eat
And when it was time for
iftar and they brought the food
They would eat,
finish, and then sit
And at night, whoever
was hungry or hadn't eaten
Would eat tahini,
samoon, and tea
Interviewer: Was the food
they brought clean and healthy?
Or was it, for
example, old and stale?
It was the leftovers
of their own food
From what they ate themselves
They brought the
leftovers up to us
Interviewer: Did you notice any
obvious diseases among the prisoners?
They didn’t complain, but did
you see anyone with itching or lice?
Anyone in pain or suffering
from an illness, like a fever
No, there was no illness at
all, no scabies or anything else
Interviewer: Was there any medical care for you?
Witness: No
There was absolutely
no medical care
Interviewer: If you asked
for more food or health care
Or for clean water
Interviewer: Did they respond to you?
Witness: No
We drank water from the toilets
We filled it and
drank from there
There were all ages,
boys fifteen to twenty
And elderly men, like the one
arrested for assaulting a woman
Some had fired guns
Another was there
over cigarettes
And another for a
mobile phone charge
There were many charges inside
Interviewer: How were the relations
in the three cells you stayed in...
In each one for a
few days at a time?
How did you see the
relationships among the prisoners?
Were their relationships good?
Was there help among them,
did they talk to one another?
There was some
talking but not much
They could ask
about certain things
About the charges and
reasons for detention
Or whether you had
been before the judge
What they had done to you
and what they would do
And whether the judge
had spoken to you or not
That kind of question
Interviewer: Did ISIS plant any spies
among you in these three rooms?
No
Interviewer: Did any of your
companions die here or get tortured?
Do you recall a name—someone
you heard was tortured and later died...
Or was tortured, died, and
never returned to the cell?
No, no, none
They took someone out on a
theft charge, stealing a motorcycle
They took him down, flogged him,
then brought him back to the hall
Two days later they removed
him—they did nothing else to him
Interviewer: How did you receive him
when he came back from the torture room...
Flogged?
Did you take care of him?
Yes, I and two
others looked after him
We cared for him
His back was almost
black from the torture
We comforted him,
saying, You’ll get out later
And this beating is better
than having your hand cut off
We encouraged him—he rested and
slept, and next day they took him out
Regarding ISIS videos,
did they show you any?
Did they gather you
and make you watch?
Their execution videos
Or hand amputations
If they showed them,
how did you feel?
No one could speak
They made us watch things
outside, not in the prison
They gathered people and
showed how they amputated hands
Or stoned people
And threw them off buildings
We saw all of that because
our house was in Dawasa
When they threw
people, I could see them
I also saw the stonings
And the hand amputations too
They forced people
to gather and watch
They did it in the street
so people would gather
So aircraft wouldn’t
spot and bomb them
Interviewer: At age
fifteen, a minor child
Forced to see these
scenes every day
Right at your doorstep
That tall Orzdi Bak building
they pushed people off
A famous building in Mosul
How did you feel
at that young age?
Well, honestly
Absolutely no one
could talk to them
They gathered crowds—why
did they do it in the street?
So everyone would gather
And it would be
a lesson to others
When they amputated my
hand, it was to warn the rest
So no one would do it
Or would fear doing it
They did it in the
street to scare people
To terrify children and women
Interviewer: While
you were in this prison
Was this prison shelled
while you were inside?
Did they leave you
alone at night and go out?
Because they feared an
airstrike so they wouldn't die
At night only a
few people stayed
Three to four people
And the rest all
left, they didn't stay
A small number stayed so
the place wouldn't be empty
So no one could mess with them
As for the rest
The senior officials didn't
stay in the same place
They were afraid
it might be bombed
When we were here there
was no shelling on this prison
They didn't stay here—they
were afraid and went elsewhere
They hid in houses
among families
And in shops
That's how it was
Interviewer: Did you or any of your
companions try to escape from the prison?
I wanted to escape
I reached the side of the door
With a small move I could
have opened it and escaped
But fearing they would kill
me, I stayed and didn't escape
Interviewer: If you had known your
fate and the sentence you would receive
Would you have escaped?
Yes I would have escaped and not stayed
Showering happened
every three to four days
There was no shampoo, only soap
And no scrubber or towel
Whoever showered
Finished and put on his clothes
in the bathroom while still wet
He put on his
clothes and went out
The bathrooms were for anyone
who needed to relieve himself and so on
Very few things
Because someone sat
next to the bathroom door
So the foul smell reached them
The smell reached the
last room, the third room
So only a few went
to the bathroom
Interviewer: Did you
take turns cleaning it?
Yes we cleaned it
Interviewer: Did that
lessen the odor in the place?
No, it made no difference
Interviewer: Were you harassed
by the prisoners who were with you
When you used the toilet?
Yes
Interviewer: What happened?
What did they bother you about?
I wanted to shower
And one prisoner was inside
He said, Why do
you shower daily?
And the water splashes onto us
We sleep here at the
door and you don't care
You sit at the other end
He kept talking
So I didn’t speak
then, I remained silent
To avoid trouble
Otherwise they’d take
us out and beat us outside
So I stayed silent and didn’t speak, and he kept
talking alone until he’d finished and then he fell silent
Interviewer: Some
of the people we met
Said they would
go to the washrooms
They’d use the toilet
or go to the showers
Just to get some
time to themselves
Away from the prison
atmosphere and the other prisoners
Away from the atmosphere of fear
So did you do that to feel
some privacy with yourself?
Nothing like that, at the
end of the day it’s a prison
Even if someone goes into
the bathroom, he’s still in prison
That bathroom is
in the prison
A person doesn’t leave the
cell and go somewhere else
It’s in the same cell
They came up to us
They said anyone under
16 years old should come out
He’ll be released, he won’t stay
I went out along with
three or four others
They took us down from
upstairs with our eyes blindfolded
They led us down these
stairs and up from here
There were civilians standing
Prisoners too
Each person went in to
see the judge separately
The judge questioned him, then
they flogged him and released him
My turn came and I went in
He asked me–What’s
your charge? I said–Theft
He said–Motorcycle theft?
I said, No, house theft
It was written on it
that it was confiscated
He told them—Return this one, the
sentence will be carried out on him
Interviewer: Did he say that in front of you?
Witness: Yes
They took me back and
took me upstairs to the room
Interviewer: And when you went
back upstairs, did you know your fate?
Since you hadn’t been
released from prison
He gave me hope
by taking me upstairs
What I understood was
that he would cut off my hand
He took me upstairs
Two of them came to us, and we
were three or four prisoners there
When they took us out, but
those had different charges
They came to us and said...
The judge felt sorry for you
when he saw that only you were left
So he will release you
He pardoned you
and will let you out
But don’t do again what you did
So I and those with me
cried with joy
It was six o’clock at
sunset, during Ramadan
So I started thinking to myself that I
would leave here and go to my family’s house
Where I would eat and
break the fast with them
They left us, everyone
left and only we stayed here
In this prison, everyone left
Then it became Laylat al-Qadr
They came to us
and said—Let’s go
We’ll take you out
They blindfolded our eyes,
shackled our hands, and took us out
Interviewer: What
time was it then?
They took us out at six
o’clock, around sunset
They took us out
and I was barefoot
Barefoot, without shoes
They took us out and
put us in a Hisba vehicle
And they put a cannula—a
tourniquet—on my hand
When they put the cannula on my
hand I knew they would cut off my hand
Interviewer: You and those with you?
Witness: Yes
They put the cannula on my hand
Interviewer: Who was the person
responsible for this?
Who put the
Cannulas and the tourniquets on?
Did they put them on
you in the vehicle?
Did they talk to you? Didn’t you ask
them why they were putting cannulas on you?
As for me, when they put
the cannula on my hand
I didn’t know why
I said, Uncle, are you going to cut off my
hand? He said, No, uncle, we won’t cut your hand
We will only take
you to the hospital
When they put the cannula on my
hand I knew they would cut off my hand
Then one of them called out
He told him—Stay here with them,
I’ll go get something and come back
He went to get the
things and came back
And what were the
things he brought!?
He brought rubber tubing
He ties it here on the arm
He tightens it on the
arm here and ties it here
He placed it at this spot
So the blood would stop
So blood wouldn’t
flow when they cut it
He placed the cannula and injected
me through it, and I couldn’t feel it
I sat and moved it on the
ground like this and couldn’t feel it
I pinched it and
still couldn’t feel it
They took us out and took
us to the Cairo neighborhood
They took us to the
Cairo neighborhood
They got out and unloaded the
loudspeakers, the device, and the generator
They started calling on their
loudspeaker and gathered the people
They took us down from the
vehicle and sat us on the curb
They started talking
to us and so on
And at the moment they
were going to cut off our hands
Interviewer: What did
they talk to you about?
It was ISIS itself
Interviewer: When they
got you out of the car
When they took us out they
told us to sit and not move
When it became certain
they would cut off our hands
Then he came and pulled
me, but how did he pull me?
He yanked me with force
He said—Come, stand
But I stayed scared and seated
He grabbed me here, told
me–Stand, and he made me stand
He sat me on the chair
And he brought a
table and set it there
And they tied my
hand with a rope here
Three or four of them grabbed
me here by the shoulders
And one of them held me here
And another grabbed me here
And one of them stood in
front of me behind the table
He kept pulling my hand with
the rope until it would tear off
He brought a cleaver and
placed another cleaver on top of it
With a single blow it
was severed instantly
Interviewer: Did you feel it?
Witness: No
After that they wrapped my hand
in cloth and put me into the car
When they put me in the car, they
removed the blindfold from my eyes
Interviewer: What about the
two people who were with you?
They also amputated
one man's hand
They took him with me
to the hospital as well
They placed us in the hospital
The other one whose leg they
cut—I don't know where they took him
They brought him with us to the
place where they amputated our hands
But I don't know—after they cut off our hands,
they took us in one car and he went in another
They went and amputated
his leg somewhere else
Interviewer: Were you the only one whose sentence
was carried out in the Cairo neighborhood?
Yes, plus another person with
me but on a different charge
I mean, his charge
wasn't the same as mine
Interviewer: Did they carry
out your sentence before his?
I was the first person whose
sentence was carried out
Interviewer: It was close to iftar
time—was there a crowd of people?
Yes
Interviewer: What did you see in
front of you upon your first arrival?
You mean when they
amputated my hand?
Interviewer: Yes, when
you reached the place?
People were busy buying what
they needed from the market
It was a public market
They were buying from
clothing shops and other stores
So when they saw
the Hisba vehicle stop
And when they unloaded the items, people
knew a sentence was about to be carried out
People gathered little by little
Until there were a lot of people, and
they carried out the sentence on us
Interviewer: During that time were you
crying and begging them to let you go?
And were you talking to
them, or were you resigned?
There was no way
back then–I surrendered
There was nothing
at all to stop them
Once they made a decision, there
was no turning back—they'd carry it out
I was scared and sitting then
Sitting on the curb
Interviewer: Didn't you try to run away?
Witness: No
Because they were all
gathered in the same place
And here, in our
community, I mean
While ISIS was present
They called them
lawkiyya, their hypocrites
Anyone who tried to escape
People would catch
him and not let him flee
That’s why I didn’t
Interviewer: Were your family there?
Witness: No
My family didn’t know about it
My family didn’t know because I had sent
them word that I would get out safely
Interviewer: What was the situation
in the hospital, who was there?
They didn’t know until I
went to them at home myself
They cut off our hands
and put us in a car
They brought us
to Saddam Hospital
Salam Hospital
They let us out
The first person was taken to the operating
room, his hand was stitched, and he was sent out
I was the second person
to enter the operating room
He asked me, do you have any
illnesses or allergies? I said, no
The doctor was asking me
I told him, no, I
don’t have any of that
He said to me—Sit here, so I sat
Then he said again, No, stand
I stood, and he laid
me on a hospital bed
He put a cannula in my hand
I don’t know what he injected
me with—seconds later I felt nothing
When I opened my eyes,
I found my hand bandaged
Interviewer: You lost consciousness?
Witness: Yes
When I woke up
I found my hand bandaged
I thought to myself, could it be they are
tricking us and didn’t really cut off our hands
When I became a little more
aware, I measured my hands together
And when I saw one was shorter, I knew
they had cut off my hand and I started crying
They gave me a booklet
I don’t know what was written in
it—right-hand amputation and so on
I took it and I still
keep it to this day
And they gave me slippers
And they gave me injections to treat
my hand, and said I had to take them
I left
They took us out of the hospital
They left— they
brought us and then left
Only one of them stayed
with us until we woke up
He gave us these
booklets and left
We left the hospital, and
at the door I hired a taxi
He asked me–Where do you want me
to take you? I said, to the Dawasa area
He said–Where exactly in Dawasa? I
told him, by the governorate building
The man I rode with, I didn’t know
him, but he was my father’s friend
When we left the hospital, he started
asking me what had happened and so on
So I told him my story
The taxi driver started crying
He drove me home
And I had no money with me
I said to him—Wait a moment
so I can bring you the fare
He said—No, no, I don't want it,
this is from me, a reward for God
When I stepped out of the
car, I saw my older brother
He said to me—Younes, what happened
to your hand?" I told him—They cut it off
He didn’t stop, he started
crying and ran toward the house
While running home he
shouted—Mom, Mom, Younes has come
My mother was overjoyed
And my father came, and she told him—Hajji,
didn’t I tell you he’d return safe
Because that young man came
and told us he’d be released
My brother told them—They
freed him, but they’ve cut off his hand
At that moment my father
began hitting his head
As for my mother, I
don’t know what to tell you
Thank God in any case
And that’s my story
After I left prison I didn’t step outside
the house for about a year and a half
I was ashamed in front of people
People don’t know the truth
Even my uncle,
my mother’s brother
Says to me—If you hadn’t done something,
they wouldn’t have cut off your hand
So what will strangers say
For that reason
I didn’t even mix with my
brothers and sisters at home
I went out and came back alone
In the days of ISIS, when
there were no cell phones
At that time I desperately wanted
some relief, I was looking for ease
Because of what I saw in
detention and the injustice
And my brother had a cell phone
I took it from him
and kept using it
For two or three months,
then I gave it back to him
I stayed at home all the
time until I met a friend
This is my friend
More than a brother
When I started going out to the
street after that year and a half
When I went out, I
didn’t raise my head
I kept my head down
toward the ground
And my hand was in my pocket
So he began encouraging
me, walking with me
He walked with
me wherever I went
Many of his friends told
him—Don’t walk with him
He’s suspicious and
will ruin your reputation
He told them—It’s
none of your business
This is my affair and I
want to accompany him
And he’s still with me,
always encouraging me
Because of him I started
taking my hand out in the street
I walk proudly and don’t
pay attention to anyone
And I don’t listen to
this one or that one
And thank God