Younes Basil
Muhammad, from Mosul
I am 24 years old
I am not studying or
working at the moment
Interviewer: Are you married?
Witness: No, I’m not married
Tell me about your first
detention experience
Where were you arrested,
and where did they take you?
How long did you stay in the place where you
were detained, and what happened to you there?
They took me from the house
To the Dawasa Center
I stayed with them there
And I was tortured, and so on
Then I was transferred to the
Qaimaqam Prison
I stayed there for a week
Then they transferred
me back here
Two days after I was transferred
there, the place was bombed
A plane bombed it
I came and spent one
month and twenty days here
Interviewer: Okay
When they took you there,
what day was it and at what time?
And what was the date when they
came and took you from the house?
What conversation
took place between you?
They took me before Ramadan
They said, We just
need you for a question
We only want to ask you something,
then we’ll return you home
When we reached the
center, they didn’t let me leave
And they told my father, Go, we’ll
keep your son and we won’t let him out
So I stayed two days
Ramadan was near
Ramadan was approaching
I spent the whole
month of Ramadan here
On Laylat al-Qadr,
they cut off my hand
They took me out of here
and amputated my hand