I was put alone in a
room at the Dawasa Center
From morning until evening
Later they put me in a
car — me and three others
They seated us in the car
They shackled our hands
and blindfolded our eyes
And they covered us so
we couldn’t see the place
And we were
transferred to a house
Interviewer: Was the interrogation
and torture carried out in that house?
Yes
Alright, continue the story
We were transferred
there, to the house
Those others — I didn’t
know what their charge was
And my charge was theft, so they
brought me and put me in the room
And they started
interrogating me
About how I’d entered,
what I took, and what I did
I stayed two to three
days in the house
Then I was transferred
afterwards to Qaimaqam
I stayed for about a week,
maybe eight days, at the Qaimaqam
Or a week, roughly
ten days in total
I left there, and they also
brought me before a judge there
He asked me about my
charge too, and I said–Theft
I heard sounds of
flogging and beating
When I went in to see him
they took me back again
When I entered, he was sitting
behind me and I was sitting like this now
I was also sitting on a chair
And he sat behind
me asking questions
But he was lying on a bed
He asked me a
number of questions
About my charge
And I answered him
After that they took
me back to the hall
They brought me into a large hall
that had once been for weddings
At the Qaimaqam, it
used to be a wedding hall
Huge, over there
I reckon it held
300 to 400 people
A large hall
With a stage for parties and
a spot for the bride and groom
This hall was
turned into a prison
So we stayed there, and whoever wanted to
walk could walk inside because it was so big
They dressed us in
dishdashas, robes about this long
At prayer time anyone who wanted to
do wudu [ablution] could go to the toilets
There were three or four toilets
Whoever went into the
toilets could take his time
The Hisba [religious police] car
came and they took us out of there
They put us in the Hisba vehicle
and brought us here afterward