They brought us here
and I didn’t know the place
They took me in through
here—there was a parking lot
They had seized it
We stood in the yard after they
unloaded us from the vehicle
There were about seven to
eight of us when they brought us
They had brought
people from another hall
They made us enter with our heads lowered,
our hands shackled, and our eyes blindfolded
They brought us
in through this door
They led us from here and took
us up the stairs to the hall above
I served my sentence in the hall
Interviewer: When you
entered this courtyard
Did you enter the yard and corridor
while your eyes were blindfolded?
And your hands were shackled?
If your eyes were blindfolded, what
sounds could you hear around you?
They brought me in with my eyes
blindfolded and my hands shackled
They took us in through here and I could
hear the sounds of flogging and their chatter
But I didn’t know what
they were talking about
The sound of cleaning weapons
and the click of their walkie-talkies
Which they used to call with
They made us go up a bit here,
then continued with us to the hall
Interviewer: Okay
Do you remember the ISIS members
present, their names and nationalities?
Their appearance?
They were all masked
I don’t remember them or know
their names, they were all masked
Even their hands weren’t visible
Interviewer: Have you
heard about women’s cells?
Or cells for ISIS members
being punished inside this prison?
There weren’t any in this place.
Interviewer: There
were no women’s cells?
There were cells for women, but not
for ISIS members themselves.
This room was for
women, and that room too.
Interviewer: And the rest of the
rooms, do you recall their purpose?
No, I only remember
there was a hall here.
In this hall, for major charges.
For example, someone was caught
with a Kia truck transporting cigarettes
And other materials they
used to bring from outside Mosul
Interviewer: Can you describe the sound
you heard from the women’s cells?
I heard their children’s
voices, I mean
Their children crying
From that window over there
Interviewer: Do you have a memory
related to this spot in this corridor?
With ISIS?
I only remember that I entered this place
normally and left with my hand amputated.
Interviewer: Did you notice display
screens showing ISIS videos in this yard?
No, in the yard there weren’t
any, only in their official’s room.
There was a screen
Interviewer: The sharia judge’s room?
Witness: Yes