Interviewer: Regarding
the three cells you were in...
How did you spend
your time in them
Is there a particular memory
from those cells you can’t forget?
How did you feel when
we walked in them?
I felt that when I entered my hand
was there, and when I left it wasn’t
I spent the time sleeping
Only when prayer time came, I
prayed and went back to sleep
Interviewer: How did
the ISIS jailers treat you?
At prayer times...
Did they act violently to
make you stand up for prayer?
They came at prayer time and
knocked on the door, on the bars
Shouting—It’s prayer
time, get up, pray, get up
Interviewer: Did they supervise your performance of the prayer?
Witness: What do you mean?
Interviewer: Meaning they came to
make sure you were praying and then left?
Yes, one of them
stood at the door
Everyone performed wudu
[ablution] and the prayer was collective
They prayed and finished,
then each returned to his place
Interviewer: What sounds did you
hear from inside the detention room?
And how was the smell
of the three rooms?
I mean, the smell wasn’t good
And we heard the voices
of those they were flogging
And the crying of those
children I talked about
Whose mothers were
here and being flogged
I mean, I heard many things
And sounds
Interviewer: Was
the talk between you
Or talk in general, was it
forbidden inside the cell?
Between you and
the prisoners with you?
No, no, it wasn't forbidden
We would talk and chat
But only a little
We couldn't talk
about other things
Only about prayer matters
Anyone who wanted to
learn the prayer and its details
Interviewer: Until what
hour did you talk together
Did they come tell
you to stop and sleep?
Or was it okay to
talk at other times?
At night after the prayer
We chatted, then the
jailer came and yelled
Enough, it's time to sleep
And everyone slept
No one stayed
awake—lights off, all slept
If they heard anyone
talking or making a sound
They would come up immediately
They knocked—Who was
shouting? Who spoke?
They checked,
then went back down