It was Ramadan—at suhoor we
got samoon [finger roll] and tahini
The samoon bread was stale
It crumbled when you held it
And they brought the tahini dip
And a pot of tea
Everyone ate suhoor,
prayed, and slept
At iftar they brought soup
Or rice, or bulgur
That's the food
Interviewer: And was everyone forced to fast?
Witness: Yes
Anyone who didn't
fast was punished
And anyone who didn't pray too
Even long pants got you punished
Interviewer: Punished while inside the cell?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Were the iftar
and suhoor meals in Ramadan
Enough and filling?
Half the people didn't eat
because it wasn't enough
They brought a small
pot for 70 to 80 people
So who would it be enough for?
It isn't only one or two people
Interviewer: Seventy to eighty people inside each room?
Witness: Yes
So who would it be enough for?
They brought a small pot, threw it by the
door, turned their backs, and walked away
From their own food and drink
Interviewer: When you were inside the room,
you mentioned there were many jars of tahini
Were all the jars in your room
They used to
bring five to six jars
And distribute them to the rooms
So whoever got hungry
would take some and eat
And when it was time for
iftar and they brought the food
They would eat,
finish, and then sit
And at night, whoever
was hungry or hadn't eaten
Would eat tahini,
samoon, and tea
Interviewer: Was the food
they brought clean and healthy?
Or was it, for
example, old and stale?
It was the leftovers
of their own food
From what they ate themselves
They brought the
leftovers up to us
Interviewer: Did you notice any
obvious diseases among the prisoners?
They didn’t complain, but did
you see anyone with itching or lice?
Anyone in pain or suffering
from an illness, like a fever
No, there was no illness at
all, no scabies or anything else
Interviewer: Was there any medical care for you?
Witness: No
There was absolutely
no medical care
Interviewer: If you asked
for more food or health care
Or for clean water
Interviewer: Did they respond to you?
Witness: No
We drank water from the toilets
We filled it and
drank from there