Showering happened
every three to four days
There was no shampoo, only soap
And no scrubber or towel
Whoever showered
Finished and put on his clothes
in the bathroom while still wet
He put on his
clothes and went out
The bathrooms were for anyone
who needed to relieve himself and so on
Very few things
Because someone sat
next to the bathroom door
So the foul smell reached them
The smell reached the
last room, the third room
So only a few went
to the bathroom
Interviewer: Did you
take turns cleaning it?
Yes we cleaned it
Interviewer: Did that
lessen the odor in the place?
No, it made no difference
Interviewer: Were you harassed
by the prisoners who were with you
When you used the toilet?
Yes
Interviewer: What happened?
What did they bother you about?
I wanted to shower
And one prisoner was inside
He said, Why do
you shower daily?
And the water splashes onto us
We sleep here at the
door and you don't care
You sit at the other end
He kept talking
So I didn’t speak
then, I remained silent
To avoid trouble
Otherwise they’d take
us out and beat us outside
So I stayed silent and didn’t speak, and he kept
talking alone until he’d finished and then he fell silent
Interviewer: Some
of the people we met
Said they would
go to the washrooms
They’d use the toilet
or go to the showers
Just to get some
time to themselves
Away from the prison
atmosphere and the other prisoners
Away from the atmosphere of fear
So did you do that to feel
some privacy with yourself?
Nothing like that, at the
end of the day it’s a prison
Even if someone goes into
the bathroom, he’s still in prison
That bathroom is
in the prison
A person doesn’t leave the
cell and go somewhere else
It’s in the same cell