There were all ages,
boys fifteen to twenty
And elderly men, like the one
arrested for assaulting a woman
Some had fired guns
Another was there
over cigarettes
And another for a
mobile phone charge
There were many charges inside
Interviewer: How were the relations
in the three cells you stayed in...
In each one for a
few days at a time?
How did you see the
relationships among the prisoners?
Were their relationships good?
Was there help among them,
did they talk to one another?
There was some
talking but not much
They could ask
about certain things
About the charges and
reasons for detention
Or whether you had
been before the judge
What they had done to you
and what they would do
And whether the judge
had spoken to you or not
That kind of question
Interviewer: Did ISIS plant any spies
among you in these three rooms?
No
Interviewer: Did any of your
companions die here or get tortured?
Do you recall a name—someone
you heard was tortured and later died...
Or was tortured, died, and
never returned to the cell?
No, no, none
They took someone out on a
theft charge, stealing a motorcycle
They took him down, flogged him,
then brought him back to the hall
Two days later they removed
him—they did nothing else to him
Interviewer: How did you receive him
when he came back from the torture room...
Flogged?
Did you take care of him?
Yes, I and two
others looked after him
We cared for him
His back was almost
black from the torture
We comforted him,
saying, You’ll get out later
And this beating is better
than having your hand cut off
We encouraged him—he rested and
slept, and next day they took him out
Regarding ISIS videos,
did they show you any?
Did they gather you
and make you watch?
Their execution videos
Or hand amputations
If they showed them,
how did you feel?
No one could speak
They made us watch things
outside, not in the prison
They gathered people and
showed how they amputated hands
Or stoned people
And threw them off buildings
We saw all of that because
our house was in Dawasa
When they threw
people, I could see them
I also saw the stonings
And the hand amputations too
They forced people
to gather and watch
They did it in the street
so people would gather
So aircraft wouldn’t
spot and bomb them
Interviewer: At age
fifteen, a minor child
Forced to see these
scenes every day
Right at your doorstep
That tall Orzdi Bak building
they pushed people off
A famous building in Mosul
How did you feel
at that young age?
Well, honestly
Absolutely no one
could talk to them
They gathered crowds—why
did they do it in the street?
So everyone would gather
And it would be
a lesson to others
When they amputated my
hand, it was to warn the rest
So no one would do it
Or would fear doing it
They did it in the
street to scare people
To terrify children and women
Interviewer: While
you were in this prison
Was this prison shelled
while you were inside?
Did they leave you
alone at night and go out?
Because they feared an
airstrike so they wouldn't die
At night only a
few people stayed
Three to four people
And the rest all
left, they didn't stay
A small number stayed so
the place wouldn't be empty
So no one could mess with them
As for the rest
The senior officials didn't
stay in the same place
They were afraid
it might be bombed
When we were here there
was no shelling on this prison
They didn't stay here—they
were afraid and went elsewhere
They hid in houses
among families
And in shops
That's how it was
Interviewer: Did you or any of your
companions try to escape from the prison?
I wanted to escape
I reached the side of the door
With a small move I could
have opened it and escaped
But fearing they would kill
me, I stayed and didn't escape
Interviewer: If you had known your
fate and the sentence you would receive
Would you have escaped?
Yes I would have escaped and not stayed