They came up to us
They said anyone under
16 years old should come out
He’ll be released, he won’t stay
I went out along with
three or four others
They took us down from
upstairs with our eyes blindfolded
They led us down these
stairs and up from here
There were civilians standing
Prisoners too
Each person went in to
see the judge separately
The judge questioned him, then
they flogged him and released him
My turn came and I went in
He asked me–What’s
your charge? I said–Theft
He said–Motorcycle theft?
I said, No, house theft
It was written on it
that it was confiscated
He told them—Return this one, the
sentence will be carried out on him
Interviewer: Did he say that in front of you?
Witness: Yes
They took me back and
took me upstairs to the room
Interviewer: And when you went
back upstairs, did you know your fate?
Since you hadn’t been
released from prison
He gave me hope
by taking me upstairs
What I understood was
that he would cut off my hand
He took me upstairs
Two of them came to us, and we
were three or four prisoners there
When they took us out, but
those had different charges
They came to us and said...
The judge felt sorry for you
when he saw that only you were left
So he will release you
He pardoned you
and will let you out
But don’t do again what you did
So I and those with me
cried with joy
It was six o’clock at
sunset, during Ramadan
So I started thinking to myself that I
would leave here and go to my family’s house
Where I would eat and
break the fast with them
They left us, everyone
left and only we stayed here
In this prison, everyone left
Then it became Laylat al-Qadr
They came to us
and said—Let’s go
We’ll take you out
They blindfolded our eyes,
shackled our hands, and took us out
Interviewer: What
time was it then?
They took us out at six
o’clock, around sunset
They took us out
and I was barefoot
Barefoot, without shoes
They took us out and
put us in a Hisba vehicle
And they put a cannula—a
tourniquet—on my hand
When they put the cannula on my
hand I knew they would cut off my hand
Interviewer: You and those with you?
Witness: Yes
They put the cannula on my hand
Interviewer: Who was the person
responsible for this?
Who put the
Cannulas and the tourniquets on?
Did they put them on
you in the vehicle?
Did they talk to you? Didn’t you ask
them why they were putting cannulas on you?
As for me, when they put
the cannula on my hand
I didn’t know why
I said, Uncle, are you going to cut off my
hand? He said, No, uncle, we won’t cut your hand
We will only take
you to the hospital
When they put the cannula on my
hand I knew they would cut off my hand
Then one of them called out
He told him—Stay here with them,
I’ll go get something and come back
He went to get the
things and came back
And what were the
things he brought!?
He brought rubber tubing
He ties it here on the arm
He tightens it on the
arm here and ties it here
He placed it at this spot
So the blood would stop
So blood wouldn’t
flow when they cut it
He placed the cannula and injected
me through it, and I couldn’t feel it
I sat and moved it on the
ground like this and couldn’t feel it
I pinched it and
still couldn’t feel it
They took us out and took
us to the Cairo neighborhood
They took us to the
Cairo neighborhood
They got out and unloaded the
loudspeakers, the device, and the generator
They started calling on their
loudspeaker and gathered the people
They took us down from the
vehicle and sat us on the curb
They started talking
to us and so on
And at the moment they
were going to cut off our hands
Interviewer: What did
they talk to you about?
It was ISIS itself
Interviewer: When they
got you out of the car
When they took us out they
told us to sit and not move
When it became certain
they would cut off our hands
Then he came and pulled
me, but how did he pull me?
He yanked me with force
He said—Come, stand
But I stayed scared and seated
He grabbed me here, told
me–Stand, and he made me stand
He sat me on the chair
And he brought a
table and set it there
And they tied my
hand with a rope here
Three or four of them grabbed
me here by the shoulders
And one of them held me here
And another grabbed me here
And one of them stood in
front of me behind the table
He kept pulling my hand with
the rope until it would tear off
He brought a cleaver and
placed another cleaver on top of it
With a single blow it
was severed instantly
Interviewer: Did you feel it?
Witness: No
After that they wrapped my hand
in cloth and put me into the car
When they put me in the car, they
removed the blindfold from my eyes
Interviewer: What about the
two people who were with you?
They also amputated
one man's hand
They took him with me
to the hospital as well
They placed us in the hospital
The other one whose leg they
cut—I don't know where they took him
They brought him with us to the
place where they amputated our hands
But I don't know—after they cut off our hands,
they took us in one car and he went in another
They went and amputated
his leg somewhere else
Interviewer: Were you the only one whose sentence
was carried out in the Cairo neighborhood?
Yes, plus another person with
me but on a different charge
I mean, his charge
wasn't the same as mine
Interviewer: Did they carry
out your sentence before his?
I was the first person whose
sentence was carried out
Interviewer: It was close to iftar
time—was there a crowd of people?
Yes
Interviewer: What did you see in
front of you upon your first arrival?
You mean when they
amputated my hand?
Interviewer: Yes, when
you reached the place?
People were busy buying what
they needed from the market
It was a public market
They were buying from
clothing shops and other stores
So when they saw
the Hisba vehicle stop
And when they unloaded the items, people
knew a sentence was about to be carried out
People gathered little by little
Until there were a lot of people, and
they carried out the sentence on us
Interviewer: During that time were you
crying and begging them to let you go?
And were you talking to
them, or were you resigned?
There was no way
back then–I surrendered
There was nothing
at all to stop them
Once they made a decision, there
was no turning back—they'd carry it out
I was scared and sitting then
Sitting on the curb
Interviewer: Didn't you try to run away?
Witness: No
Because they were all
gathered in the same place
And here, in our
community, I mean
While ISIS was present
They called them
lawkiyya, their hypocrites
Anyone who tried to escape
People would catch
him and not let him flee
That’s why I didn’t
Interviewer: Were your family there?
Witness: No
My family didn’t know about it
My family didn’t know because I had sent
them word that I would get out safely
Interviewer: What was the situation
in the hospital, who was there?
They didn’t know until I
went to them at home myself