They cut off our hands
and put us in a car
They brought us
to Saddam Hospital
Salam Hospital
They let us out
The first person was taken to the operating
room, his hand was stitched, and he was sent out
I was the second person
to enter the operating room
He asked me, do you have any
illnesses or allergies? I said, no
The doctor was asking me
I told him, no, I
don’t have any of that
He said to me—Sit here, so I sat
Then he said again, No, stand
I stood, and he laid
me on a hospital bed
He put a cannula in my hand
I don’t know what he injected
me with—seconds later I felt nothing
When I opened my eyes,
I found my hand bandaged
Interviewer: You lost consciousness?
Witness: Yes
When I woke up
I found my hand bandaged
I thought to myself, could it be they are
tricking us and didn’t really cut off our hands
When I became a little more
aware, I measured my hands together
And when I saw one was shorter, I knew
they had cut off my hand and I started crying
They gave me a booklet
I don’t know what was written in
it—right-hand amputation and so on
I took it and I still
keep it to this day
And they gave me slippers
And they gave me injections to treat
my hand, and said I had to take them
I left
They took us out of the hospital
They left— they
brought us and then left
Only one of them stayed
with us until we woke up
He gave us these
booklets and left
We left the hospital, and
at the door I hired a taxi
He asked me–Where do you want me
to take you? I said, to the Dawasa area
He said–Where exactly in Dawasa? I
told him, by the governorate building
The man I rode with, I didn’t know
him, but he was my father’s friend
When we left the hospital, he started
asking me what had happened and so on
So I told him my story
The taxi driver started crying
He drove me home
And I had no money with me
I said to him—Wait a moment
so I can bring you the fare
He said—No, no, I don't want it,
this is from me, a reward for God
When I stepped out of the
car, I saw my older brother
He said to me—Younes, what happened
to your hand?" I told him—They cut it off
He didn’t stop, he started
crying and ran toward the house
While running home he
shouted—Mom, Mom, Younes has come
My mother was overjoyed
And my father came, and she told him—Hajji,
didn’t I tell you he’d return safe
Because that young man came
and told us he’d be released
My brother told them—They
freed him, but they’ve cut off his hand
At that moment my father
began hitting his head
As for my mother, I
don’t know what to tell you
Thank God in any case
And that’s my story