After I left prison I didn’t step outside
the house for about a year and a half
I was ashamed in front of people
People don’t know the truth
Even my uncle,
my mother’s brother
Says to me—If you hadn’t done something,
they wouldn’t have cut off your hand
So what will strangers say
For that reason
I didn’t even mix with my
brothers and sisters at home
I went out and came back alone
In the days of ISIS, when
there were no cell phones
At that time I desperately wanted
some relief, I was looking for ease
Because of what I saw in
detention and the injustice
And my brother had a cell phone
I took it from him
and kept using it
For two or three months,
then I gave it back to him
I stayed at home all the
time until I met a friend
This is my friend
More than a brother
When I started going out to the
street after that year and a half
When I went out, I
didn’t raise my head
I kept my head down
toward the ground
And my hand was in my pocket
So he began encouraging
me, walking with me
He walked with
me wherever I went
Many of his friends told
him—Don’t walk with him
He’s suspicious and
will ruin your reputation
He told them—It’s
none of your business
This is my affair and I
want to accompany him
And he’s still with me,
always encouraging me
Because of him I started
taking my hand out in the street
I walk proudly and don’t
pay attention to anyone
And I don’t listen to
this one or that one
And thank God