I was afraid when I arrived
Because we heard about them, that they execute and behead
And other such things
So I was more afraid than usual
They interrogated me
And they said, You will now go inside
And the hajji is the one who knows what he will do to you
So I became more terrified than usual
That is what happened to me
Interviewer: This person who received you
And the other who took your belongings
How did they treat you, was their manner soft?
No, no, their manner was soft
He said, What brought you here
I said, I don’t know, the hajji brought me and I don’t know the reason
And I told you that I had medicine I’d distributed for free to people
Because of medicine, meaning I was going to him because of the medicine
But if there is something other than medicine I don’t know
They took me inside
Interviewer: After you walked from the caravan and entered the interrogation room
The one who took you and led you into the interrogation room
Did he blindfold you when he brought you to the judge or not?
No, they brought me in normally and did not blindfold me
And I knew the judge
He was sitting outside drinking tea
He had a mole, and his name was Ayoub
Interviewer: Was he from Mosul?
Witness: No, he was from Diyala
From Diyala, and his nom de guerre was Abu Yahya
Interviewer: About how old was he?
He was in his forties, about 45, or 43
Interviewer: Was he the judge of this court?
Yes, and he was the one who conducted the interrogation
Inside the hall