I felt fear and terror
They brought me into the cell
My mattress was here in this spot
And we hung our clothes here in this place
And I was alone
But every day or two they brought someone
He stayed here an hour or two, a day or two
Then they transferred him
I don’t know where they took him
I was afraid to ask, I couldn’t because they listened to us
They brought a Christian man named Edmond
That was because he became Muslim
They brought him and we didn’t know his story
He stayed two nights with me, two days
Then they took him away
Interviewer: Where did Edmond sleep?
Witness: He slept in that corner
When he was here we were afraid to talk to each other
Afraid they’d hear us, because you couldn’t trust them
Interviewer: Can you give me Edmond’s description?
And how old was he? And why was he detained?
I don’t know exactly
He was someone who’d converted to Islam
Edmond used to sleep in this place
He was about 22 or 23, a young man
Once I asked him, Where are you from?
He said, From the Aden neighborhood
I still remember he told me he lived in the Aden neighborhood
Interviewer: Didn’t you ask him about his family and why he stayed here?
His family had gone to Erbil
Interviewer: Didn’t you ask him why he hadn’t gone with them?
I couldn’t ask him these questions
I was afraid he’d tell them I was asking
Interviewer: The food they brought you and the Christian who became Muslim
Was it in one dish or did each of you have his own?
No, each of us had his own dish
They brought us sammoun [bread roll] and tahini too
And the food was ready on plastic plates
Bread, broth, and a spoon with it, and we ate
Interviewer: The people they brought for two or three hours then took out
What were their charges exactly?
One of them was because of cigarettes
And one of them because of a satellite dish
They had been charged with many things
Interviewer: Did these prisoners sleep with you in this prison?
Edmond and one or two others slept here, I think a day or two
Most of the time those they brought stayed only a few hours
At most until the evening
Interviewer: You said you spent 28 days in this room
Didn’t you think of sending a message with someone who went in and out
To tell your family where you were?
I was afraid to do that
Afraid they would ask him, What did this prisoner say to you?
That was fear and terror
Interviewer: While you were here did a jailer come in and beat you?
Or beat someone who stayed here for a while with you?
Did torture happen in this place?
No, not here
But we heard screams from the yard when they flogged someone
Interviewer: For relieving yourself, where were the toilets?
They were there, when we wanted the toilet we called and knocked on the door
Then the jailer came and took us
We relieved ourselves then he brought us back here
Interviewer: Was there a set time to go out or was it when you needed to?
No, they knew I was a bit sick
So they let me go whenever I needed
They told me, Knock on the door
The jailer was there, he’d take us, we relieved ourselves, washed, then came back
Interviewer: Did something happen while you were here for 28 days?
With a jailer, a prisoner, or someone who came and left?
Just that man named Edmond
I was afraid to ask him
We were afraid because the jailer outside might hear us
One of the ISIS members
We feared he’d hear us talking and shout at us
Interviewer: The people they brought in temporarily then took out
Did any of them ask why you were here?
Yes, they asked me and I told them I was here because of medicine
They asked, What was your charge?
I said they brought me because of medicine, and my stay here dragged on
Interviewer: Was this place furnished?
Was there a carpet?
Yes, in the middle
A nylon mat
Here was my mattress, and a hanger
And whoever came brought his own mattress
Interviewer: You mean the temporary one brought his own mattress?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And when he left, did they take it?
No, he took it with him
Interviewer: Do you think there were prisoners in those other rooms?
And did you hear them?
Yes, in that room there were prisoners
But I don’t know what kind
Interviewer: When you went to the bathroom
Did you see other prisoners going at the same time?
No, they never let one meet another
Interviewer: Do you remember how many jailers stood at the door?
One stood here on duty
Interviewer: You mean they rotated?
Witness: Yes
Each one took over for two or three hours
Interviewer: Do you remember the name of one of the jailers?
Abu Hafsa, we called him that
Interviewer: Who was Abu Hafsa?
Abu Hafsa was from al-Hadar
Interviewer: From Tikrit?
Witness: Yes, from Tikrit, from al-Hadar
They called him Abu Hafsa, but I didn’t know his real name
Because Abu Hafsa was a nom de guerre
Interviewer: What did you talk about, did you ask him for anything?
No, I just asked him to bring me water, for example
Or to buy me something from outside
Sometimes I gave him money
So he could go buy what I wanted from the grocery in the street
Interviewer: So he could deal with you if you gave him money?
Yes, they bought me what I wanted
Interviewer: Did the money stay with you or was it in custody?
No, the money was in my pocket
My ID card and watch were in custody
Interviewer: So they took your ID and watch?
Yes, only those, the money stayed with me
Interviewer: Was it normal for them to take money and buy things for you?
Yes, and he gave me the change
Interviewer: Did he take anything in return?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Didn’t he take bribes or anything?
Witness: No, he didn’t
Interviewer: How long did you stay in this room?
28 days
Interviewer: Are these windows the same and in this state?
Yes, they had glass panels
And were covered with metal from outside
Interviewer: Were there cameras pointed at you?
No, there weren’t any cameras
There was this fan, it’s still here now
And two light bulbs
Interviewer: Wasn’t there one of their flags on the walls?
Yes, there was a flag here
Interviewer: Did they use a screen to show their videos?
No, the screen was downstairs
Interviewer: Here there wasn’t one?
Witness: No, there wasn’t