When the call to prayer came, we prayed two rakaas [a unit of prayer]
After the interrogation ended, we prayed two rakaas
And after the prayer they took me down this path
There was an opening here
That led to the bishopric
We went there, and stayed until they held the obligatory prayer
We all prayed together
After that, and after the obligatory prayer, the interrogation started
Interviewer: When you prayed the sunnah here, were you in wudu [ablution]?
Or did you tell them you wanted to do wudu?
No, I was already in wudu since they’d taken me from my shop
Interviewer: The prayer you did together there
Interviewer: Was the imam one of their men or one of you?
Witness: One of their men
Interviewer: Can you describe the prayer for me?
Was it a normal prayer? Was there any special duaa [supplication]?
No, there was no duaa, just a normal sunnah prayer
Interviewer: The obligatory or the sunnah?
Witness: Sorry, the obligatory
It was just a normal noon prayer
Interviewer: Didn’t he make a duaa of qunout for example?
No, he didn’t as far as I remember
Interviewer: What happened after the prayer?
Witness: After the prayer we sat
For a bit, then they took us to the interrogation
And during the interrogation he started asking me about the medicine
Where was the source of the medicine I was bringing
I told him it was from people who wanted good deeds
They brought it to me and asked me to distribute it for God’s reward
And there were women who came to me at the shop
It turned out those women were from them
They brought me a prescription and said they were in need
They said to me, Can you provide us with this medicine?
They thought I was selling it
What I had with me I gave them
Interviewer: For money or free?
Witness: Free
Free, even an inhaler for asthma treatment was marked for free distribution
Tenorfin for high blood pressure was marked for free distribution
Isordin and Angised, the tablet under the tongue for heart disease
These were what I gave them
I suspected them before I was detained
It was clear they were sending them to me
And the ones who came were women
They wanted to see if I sold or bought or gave for free
But I gave it for free to the poor, for the sake of God
Interviewer: Was the person who interrogated you there
The same one who interrogated you here?
No, a different person
Interviewer: How was his style and the way
he treated you during the interrogation?
His style was harsh with me
I mean his way of speaking was terrifying
As if he wanted to slaughter me
Interviewer: Did they ask you the same questions here and there?
Yes, almost the same questions there
Interviewer: Did he ask you for something specific there?
Like, join us or support us so we can release you?
No, he didn’t ask me that
He asked me, What do you think of ISIS?
And out of fear I told him, ISIS and you are right
And so on, just out of fear
I told him, You are right and you are this and that
Interviewer: When you were saying out of fear that they were right
Witness: Yes, out of terror
Interviewer: Do you think he believed you?
As he wished, if he believed me or not
But I knew they were criminals
Interviewer: I understand your words
But when you told him they were right while you were scared
Do you think he believed you?
No, I don’t think he believed me
Interviewer: Did you feel that they knew they were in the wrong?
They were wrong, that’s certain
Interviewer: Did they know that?
Yes, they knew they were wrong
They were wrong, without a doubt