When we come to the toilets, we go in to relieve ourselves
And showering on Monday or Thursday takes place here
Yes, we used to come in and shower in this place
They bring us a bucket of water
They let us in and give us 15 minutes to shower
Interviewer: Was there soap and cleaning products?
Witness: Yes, there were
Interviewer: Was there hot water in this place, or only cold water?
No, they heated the water for us and mixed it with cold water in the bucket
They gave us one full bucket to shower with, nothing more
Interviewer: Who brought it to the showers?
Witness: He carried it here
Interviewer: You showered with it and gave it back?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Was there a specific time limit for showering?
Yes, he told us, Don’t take longer than 15 minutes
Interviewer: And were you allowed to shower anytime you wanted?
No, it was only allowed on Monday and Thursday
Interviewer: During the 28 days you stayed here
Did it ever happen that the toilets or showers got clogged
And did they fix them, or you?
No, we were the ones who cleaned them
Interviewer: Didn’t they ever get clogged?
Witness: No, we cleaned them
Meaning when we finished, we cleaned them, organized them, and then left
Interviewer: Was water available, or did it ever get cut off?
No, they used to bring us water
Interviewer: Didn’t the water ever get cut off?
Sometimes, when there was shelling, the water was cut off
They would bring water with a truck
And transfer the water from it to here
They brought one of the prisoners to carry
the water and bring it to us in this place