They brought me in here to this place
The judge sat on a chair here, with a table in front of him
And I was in this spot
Interviewer: Were you sitting or standing?
Witness: No, I was standing
I was standing, and he was sitting
He started asking me questions
What is your name? Are you from this area?
And what do you know about the Christians here?
I told him, They are peaceful, simple people
They are our neighbors, and we have spent our lives together
He asked me, Do they like you or not?
I told him, They like us; they are good people, and we have lived with them for years
We sleep at one another’s houses, we share food, and things like that
Then he asked me about medicine
Where do you get the medicine from? And why do you distribute it?
And to whom do you distribute it? Do you sell it?
I told him, I do not sell it
It is all labeled, “Distributed for free”
If they are inhalers for asthma treatment, it says on them “Distributed for free”
And also Tenormin tablets for blood pressure
And Isordil for the heart, that is what I had
I distribute it to people for free
Because some people are poor and cannot afford to buy it
I give it to them for free
He said, We asked about you, and your reputation is good
But we will interrogate you as well, because we have many questions for you
And when it was time for the noon prayer, they took me upstairs
To the archbishopric
Interviewer: In the other building?
Witness: Yes, the one in back
We went to the archbishopric and prayed there
There is a place designated for prayer
It was time for the noon prayer, so we prayed
We finished, then he interrogated me
Interviewer: What did he interrogate you about there?
He asked me about the Christians
He said, Since you used to enter these churches
What do you know about what is inside the churches?
I told him, I do not know everything about the inside of the church
This was a burial place reserved for the priests
In the Church of Mary
When the priests died, they were buried there
That is what I know
I told him, There was a library
That is what I had known before
So he nodded his head
He said, We will transfer you to the rooms upstairs
Then we will bring you back later
Interviewer: During his interrogation of you in this place or in the archbishopric
Did he say harsh words or insult you—no offense, or did he beat you?
Yes, they spoke to me with a tone of intimidation and terrorizing
Interviewer: How so? Tell me the words and describe the situation?
Tell us, or we know what we will do to you
Interviewer: Tell us?
Yes, tell us, or we know what to do with you
As if he was threatening me, a threat
And when he threatens me, fear strikes me more
That is what was happening to me
Interviewer: And did he sense your fear?
Yes, he sensed my fear—I was afraid
Because they cannot be trusted
Because their work is beheading, killing, and flogging
And I have a family, and my mind was preoccupied with my children and my wife
Because they did not know where I was
Interviewer: During the interrogation with
you in this place or in the archbishopric
Did he make a threat like, Speak, or I will
extend your prison term, or I will kill you?
Yes, that is exactly what he said
If you do not speak, we will keep you with us,
and no one will know where you are except God
He kept repeating this sentence
Interviewer: And what did you say?
I told him, Ask me, and I will tell you what I know
I told him, What else shall I tell you; should I tell you that these are walls
You asked me about such-and-such a priest
About Father Ishaq, may God have mercy on him
He was our neighbor, and he did his duty in the church
He was my friend, and I used to sit with him
And he asked me about the priests
About the priest of one church, and the priest of another church
I told him what I knew, and I did not tell him what I did not know
Interviewer: Why did he ask you specifically about the priests?
Because he knew that I was from this area
They asked about me and learnt that I was from this area
And we have been living here for 50 years
Interviewer: Regarding this place
I want you to describe this place to me when you arrived as a prisoner
What was in it, and what furniture was there?
Was there one of their banners hanging? Tell me about these details
Yes, there was their black flag
It had written on it, “There is no God but God, and Muhammad is the Messenger of God”
And there was a white curtain
And there was a place for prayer where they prayed
Interviewer: Did you pray there?
I prayed two rakaas here, then I went and prayed the noon prayer there
Interviewer: Do you mean you prayed the sunnah prayer?
Witness: Yes, the sunnah
Interviewer: And the obligatory prayer—where?
Witness: The obligatory prayer was there
Interviewer: What does this place you are in now remind you of?
And is there a particular smell present until now?
When you entered, did you smell it and did it
remind you of the incident that happened to you?
And did these details remind you of that situation you were in?
Do you feel today the same fear you felt back then?
So describe to me your feeling now since you entered the same place
I am afraid to this moment although I am here with you
The fear is still inside me
Interviewer: So you were afraid of the interrogation
And of the unknown, meaning they might kill you
Why are you afraid now since you entered this place?
Because when they used to speak to me
Their words were harsh and frightening
And I am still afraid
Even though you are filming me
Because I suffered a psychological problem
A very severe psychological problem
And I am still taking psychiatric medications
And now that we entered here, I will need medicine to calm my nerves
Interviewer: So since you entered the place and remembered the incident
Witness: Yes, I am still afraid
Interviewer: So the feeling of fear came back to you again?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Do you mean you now feel emotions and remember painful memories?
Yes, it is so
Interviewer: Did we exhaust you psychologically by standing here?
Yes, I am tired
I have been worn out psychologically
Interviewer: Do you want us to talk outside or stay here? What do you think?
Outside is better
Interviewer: Has being in this place exhausted
you to the point that you want to leave?
Yes, I have become tired
Interviewer: Is the place that frightening?
Yes, I remember painful events that happened to me
Interviewer: Did anything happen here in front of you
besides the interrogation, like beatings, for example?
They were talking among themselves that
they had taken so-and-so and killed him
And so-and-so they took to another place, and so on
And we brought so-and-so from that place
They mentioned names when they spoke with each other
Interviewer: During the interrogation?
Yes, I would hear them when they talked among themselves
When they spoke like that, I felt that what
happened to others would happen to me
Interviewer: Are the colors of these
walls the same, or did anything change?
Yes, they are the same
Interviewer: Was there nothing else in here?
No, there was not—only their flags
And there was a white curtain
And two black flags of ISIS, one there and the other there
Interviewer: When you entered this place
And you said that you now recall the fear and terror you felt
And you had a reaction from that while you were talking with us
Is there a particular smell you still remember?
Interviewer: Or do you now smell a scent that was here?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: What is this smell?
The smell of fear and terror
Because I know that their work is with blood, beheading, and killing