My name is Aladdin Khaled Ahmad
I live in the Nabi Jirjis area
I used to work as an assistant in a pharmacy
And I had a shop with a lot of secondhand medicine
People would bring it to me, and I distributed it for free
This medicine was in my shop during the time of ISIS
I distributed it for free to the poor
Those who called themselves the Islamic State arrested me
They brought me from this street and took me into the church
Interviewer: Tell me your date of birth
I was born in 1973
I am married and I have five children, three sons and two daughters
Interviewer: Did anything happen before they detained you?
Did they do something specific or give you a warning?
No, earlier they caught me twice because of cigarettes, and I was released
After that they interrogated me, then a few days later they came and took me
Interviewer: When they detained you, do you think someone informed on you?
Or do you think you were being watched, or something else?
I think I was being watched
Maybe I was monitored, but I didn’t do anything
Interviewer: When they arrested you at your house and they brought you here
They took me from the shop, not from the house
Interviewer: Sorry, from the shop
When they brought you, did they put you in a car?
Or since the place was close, did they bring you on foot?
Interviewer: And when they brought you, did they tie your hands and blindfold you?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Did they use bad words or insults with you?
And did they deal with you angrily?
Did they beat you while arresting you and bringing you to this prison?
The beating happened inside the church
Interviewer: And did that happen on the way here?
No, they didn’t beat me in front of people
Interviewer: Can you describe the appearance of the two who came to you?
What were their ages? Were they from Mosul?
Or from its outskirts, or from outside it?
They were from Mosul
Interviewer: What were their ages?
One of them was about 38 years old
And the other was about 30
Interviewer: Do you remember what clothes they were wearing?
The Kandahari outfit
Interviewer: And they brought you here
Yes, they brought me here
Interviewer: Around what time?
Around 11 in the morning
Interviewer: When they brought you here, did they come inside the prison with you?
Or did they hand you over to other people?
They handed me over to other people
To people from security