My name is Samer Elias Saeed, born in Mosul in 1974
I work as a Syriac language teacher
At Christian community schools in Mosul
The Tahdhib School and the Tahira School
And Maouna School
And Shamoun Safa School
And Ghassaniya School
As for my work in Mosul, I documented the churches and their history
I specialized in researching the history of how the churches were founded
I have many articles about these churches
And about the rituals and celebrations held there
In addition, I archived Christian heritage and history in Mosul
From 2008 up to the present
Regarding the Armenian Orthodox Church, I documented it in articles
Especially about the rituals and celebrations that were held
I also covered the celebrations that took place for Christmas
Which differ from the other Christian denominations
Which usually occurred on December 25 each year
Except the Armenian Orthodox Church, which celebrated it on January 6
Unlike the other Christian denominations