This church was built in 1857
This church was originally a plot of land purchased by two families
One was the Syriac Orthodox Sarsami family, a well-known clan
The other was the Armenian Chakmakjian family
They partnered to buy the land
And it was built in 1857
Before that year, Armenians used to perform their prayers and rituals
In the Citadel Church near this one
The Tahira Inside Church of the Syriac Orthodox
Which had been built earlier
But after 1857
The Armenians in Mosul had this church of their own
And as is known
The Armenians were subjected to many attacks
Which led them to migrate from their areas of settlement in Turkey
Their numbers reached thousands in Mosul in particular
And they needed a church where they could hold their rituals