The architectural style of the Armenian Church relies on tall towers
And on the spacious interiors that differ from other churches
In addition to the conical dome present in the Armenian Church
Which is similar in form to the Armenian Church in Baghdad
Near Tayaran Square
And many other Armenian churches
I think this style is the one followed in the churches of the capital Yerevan
The churches of the Republic of Armenia
In terms of design, it is a European style adopted in this architecture
Interviewer: We are now outside the church. Can
you tell us about those carvings behind you?
Can you describe them a little?
These carvings reflect Moslawi architecture
There is no specific Armenian feature in these engraved leaves
And the distinctive decorations
They belong to the Moslawi architectural tradition
But these inscriptions are in the Armenian language, along with the cross
And this is the Armenian cross
ISIS distorted these inscriptions
As well as the cross on the church façade
But overall, the distinctive feature is that this is based on Moslawi architecture
Known for its marble stone
In the Moslawi architectural style
Interviewer: What do these inscriptions mean?
These inscriptions indicate that this is the Etchmiadzin Armenian Church
Etchmiadzin is one of the well-known saints in the church
Armenians always use the names of saints
For their churches
Like Etchmiadzin and Grigor
And other names of saints known in Armenian history