The church was built in partnership with a Syriac Orthodox family
That family was the Sarsab family
And the Chakmakjian family, known for its charitable works
And for providing many donations
Not only to the Armenians
But to the whole city of Mosul
It was a very well known family
Along with other families
That contributed much support
And left their mark
Such as Grigor Astarjian
This well known doctor, whose palace stood beside the Prophet Younes Mosque
It was one of the palaces that hosted many figures
Both Arab and international, when they visited Mosul, due to the lack of hotels
In addition, there were Armenians who contributed
In the field of sports, where there was the Armenian Homenetmen Club
Many of its athletes became prominent in the Mosul sports scene