We are now in the priest’s room
The late priest Arakel used to sit here
I met him two or three times
In this room
There was a desk and a chair here
And here were chairs or couches where church guests sat
Christian parties also used to meet the priest here
In this room, which served as the parish office
Or the priest’s office, through which church services were provided
Such as issuing baptism certificates
Or marriage certificates
That is, wedding records as they are called
And also in this room, funeral arrangements for any Armenian were made
To agree on the rituals
And ceremonies for burying any member of the Armenian parish