If I go back in memory, the celebration I attended on January 6
In 2010
There was a table
For the church agents who received donations
The amounts given to needy families
The church priest was Father Raquel Kasparian
He invited me that day
I attended the Christmas celebration on that date I mentioned
There were special seats for the believers
They sat on them
And that main altar where rituals and celebrations were held
Armenian celebrations have their own distinctive character
They are held in the Armenian language
Unlike other Christian denominations
Which hold their celebrations in Syriac
Or in Arabic so that others can understand
But the Armenian church celebrations were held in Armenian
And always focused on much of what is in the Gospel
Stories of the Nativity and the Resurrection
The celebrations, for example Christmas
Or the commemoration of the Armenian genocide on April 15
Or Easter, which usually falls in April every year