This room is called the baptism room
Or the baptismal font
Shaped like this, in the form of a cup
Here the ceremony is held for a child’s first entry into the church
This is where the baptism ritual takes place, where children are baptized
In this font or this water-filled place
So that the child receives this sacrament and enters Christianity
In this room
In the opposite room
The priest is prepared there
The priest enters from these rooms
The priest’s vestments were kept in these rooms
For celebrating the Mass
Along with the deacons who served the church
They had their own special attire, which they wore here
This, as is clear, is the altar
Destroyed
These arches were arranged in this way
They were destroyed and overturned like this
They were on this façade, this image
And as we see, there are Armenian inscriptions
It is a verse taken from the Holy Gospel
On the main arch
There were chandeliers here
And also the distinctive Armenian crosses were destroyed
In this form, as is clear
There were many icons, private images painted by Armenian artists
In these empty spaces of the church
Interviewer: Can we talk about the destruction
That ISIS inflicted on this hall in general?
As for the destruction, first this altar that was so tall
And this arch was attached to it
It was covered with cloths used in the Mass
And here there was a curtain, which is not here now
And as we see, all the crosses were tampered with and destroyed
As is clear
So they could erase these symbols
There was this space
Where a select group of the church’s daughters were seated
The church’s daughters who sang hymns and chanted
What is called the choir
That presented the hymns
Alongside the rituals held in the church