As far as I know these places were not used
As much as those halls upstairs
ISIS used them as detention rooms and cells
To hold opponents and people against the group
Look here these metal parts were not there
They show that ISIS used them as cells and detention rooms
For anyone who opposed
Or anyone who went against ISIS decisions and rulings
Now I remember these were ISIS actions
Interviewer: What were these rooms before?
These rooms were used where Armenian children gathered
And Armenian youth
They were given courses in the Armenian language
So they could preserve their language
And their heritage from disappearing
Especially since there is an Armenian church but that church
Did not host Armenian language lessons
Compared with the Syriac language lessons in other schools
But Armenian language teaching was special and limited to the church
It supervised it and the priest was the one who taught
In cooperation with specialists from the parish
To teach their children Armenian in these halls
Special classrooms