Here there was a plaque that mentioned its construction date in 2009
This was part of the reconstruction that happened in 2009
It is clear that modern marble was used and this building style
In 2009 the church was renovated and...
Additional annexes were added to it
This hall used to be spacious
Here the priest would sit at the head of the hall
And there were seats arranged for the parishioners
Even after Mass on Sundays
The parishioners gathered and shared their concerns
And discussed many matters related to Mosul’s community at that time
This was called the church hall
And it hosted special celebrations, whether at Christmas
And the distribution of gifts to children
In addition to Easter when coffee and Armenian food were served
Especially in this hall
So that it would be a shared occasion and a gathering
Interviewer: What was the shape of the hall, and its features?
There were seats here
And in this place there was a chair
Where the church priest would sit
And all of this space had chairs around it
And the members of the Armenian church gathered in this hall
Whether to meet officials for congratulations on January 6
We welcomed well-wishers from figures in the local government
And from other churches
To congratulate on the holidays
And to exchange greetings on this occasion