As is known, ISIS entered Mosul in full control
And imposed its authority over the city
On June 10, 2014
A few weeks later, specifically on June 15 or 20
ISIS members began using churches as their bases
And in the years that followed, these churches became ISIS centers
They carried out fatwas through them
And directives issued by ISIS
As we can see, there are piles of satellite receivers
ISIS took them from residents living near this area
They were confiscated to prevent the people of Mosul from outside contact
And from learning about the efforts of the security forces to reach the city
And liberate it from ISIS’s grip