My name is Sobhan Khalil Ahmad
Known as Abu Ahmad al-Sabbagh
We are currently at the Hisba [morality police] base
The Hisba base prison, in the Souq al-Shaarin area
This prison at the Hisba headquarters was where
they brought people who sold packs of cigarettes
And violators concerning beards, and the izar [long pants]
They enforced sharia punishments here, they called them sharia punishments
Like flogging, beating, and fines
This is the base
They made it a prison and also a storeroom for satellite TV receivers
All these devices belonged to people—they took them and gathered them here
They used to issue receipts here, in this room
This is the Hisba base
This prison
They used to call this prison the light prison
The light prison, meaning the prisoners in it were the ones they deemed violators
He trims his beard, or wears his izar long, or smokes cigarettes
This was called the light prison