Here, they hold prisoners for about
15 days, or 20 days
Then they pay the fines and leave
This is the hall we’re entering now. We were detained in it
This hall we’re entering was a prison, and we were detained in it
This is the hall
These windows. They used to put wooden boards over the windows
So the window couldn’t be opened, and so we
wouldn’t see anyone or be seen, and escape
All these windows were closed and welded
This is the hall
This prison has four halls
This is the first hall, this is the second hall, and the third and the fourth
And there were toilets
They brought us food; in the morning it was cheese and samoon [bread roll]
And at noon, a plate of lentils and a bit of rice
This is the second hall, the second hall prison
And this is the third hall of the prison
The third hall, of course it had doors
When it became afternoon, they would close this door on us
They locked it on us, and we stayed held here
After the afternoon, no escorts or guards stayed with us
And this is the fourth hall
The fourth hall
And there in the first hall, there is a metal bar hanging from the ceiling
This was for anyone who looked out the window, or disobeyed them
Or anyone who did not follow their orders, they would suspend him from the ceiling
For anyone they wanted to take confessions from, they would hang him from behind
A metal bar like this
Up in the ceiling, they used it for torture
They tortured people, they would drop a rope from here
They tied him from behind, like this
Like this, the hands would be behind the back
Then they would pull him up and he would stay hanging until he confessed
And they kept the detained people here to tell them, This is the torture
If you do not confess how much you sold cigarettes for
Why did you trim your beard, who taught you?
And do you have contacts with anyone outside the country?
And they did not mean outside the country, but outside the caliphate
Or outside the land of the caliphate, who were you talking with?
These were the confessions; they extracted them from people by force
These stairs here lead to the second door
To the church, the church’s second door, and it is connected to the prison
These are the facilities and the toilets
And be aware they did not allow anyone to bathe
And if they were saw someone who did not
pray, they would ask him, Why didn’t you pray?
He would say, I am junub [ritually impure],
And they would say, Why didn’t you wash?
He would say to them, There is no hot water. And the weather was cold then
They told him, Wash with cold water
That is how ISIS were
This was their prison
And there was a screen hung in this spot
Where they used to screen their ISIS videos
This is what remains of it, and here is the power socket
They would show horrifying films of beheading and killing
And explosions, IEDs, and car bombs, all shown on the screen
And we were here, and they forced us to watch them
This is the first hall
And next time, we will go to the Thaqila [heavy crimes] Prison
I was also detained there; they call it the Thaqila Prison
It is currently in the Meydan area, the Thaqila Prison is currently in the Meydan area
This is the prison from the outside
These are the windows from the outside and from the inside
They weld the openings so the prisoner will not try to escape
Escape from the prison
They put up sheets of metal and weld them here
They call this the Hisba [morality police] base prison in Souq al-Shaarin
In a Christian church
They used churches as prisons and for torture
And halls for lectures
There was a hall here, a large hall
They gave lectures there to violators