They used to call it the lecture hall
When they released the prisoner, they released him
They told him, The judge sentenced you to 15 days or a month
You have to come and check in, every day you attend the hall
You attend the sermon
And their sermons were...
They didn’t advise people to pray, it was all incitement to fight
They wanted people to join their ranks
But people were aware and knew that what they brought was wrong
And there was no one who took their words about joining or not
This hall wasn’t like this
Here the sheikh stood, their sharia official
And here the judges, and here the prisoners sat in this space
And they delivered the sermon to them
About the beard, about the izar  [long pants], and about prayer
And about smoking, that it’s forbidden
We didn’t know that smoking was forbidden
They said that smoking was forbidden