This is the prison from the outside
From outside the church, this is the back door of the church
They brought the prisoners in here so people wouldn’t see them
This place is empty
So people would not see them, they brought the prisoners in through this door
And this is the prison from outside the church
And these windows are boarded up with wooden planks
And this is from the other side
The windows are also boarded up with wooden planks
And this is the back door of the church
And this address is Block 218, Meydan area
The whole area is called Meydan, but it is known as Souq al-Shaarin
It is called the Meydan area
Here, satellite receiver pickup
From this door they receive the devices
Satellite receiver pickup
No women allowed
This phrase was written by ISIS members
And these are the punishments, they wrote the punishments here
The army erased it during the liberation
And this is the church prison from the outside
Rear section
Which is connected to the church’s back door
This is the Hisba prison
And this church inscription, they smashed it with a hammer
And this is where the cross was; it was destroyed by ISIS