Name: Ahmad al-Haj Abd, 27 years old, married
I used to work in the private business sector
Interviewer: When were you arrested by ISIS?
Can you specify the date, which year and month?
And what were the charges brought against you?
I was arrested in 2014, I don’t remember the exact month
Either the sixth or seventh month,
the charge was possession of a weapon
And also the charge of collaboration, something like that
Interviewer: How many times were you detained by them?
Twice, the first time for one day, and the second time for 20 days
Interviewer: Describe for us what happened when
you were arrested and brought to this place
Did you know that this place was a
prison before? Describe this place for us
They brought us to Bourj Prison. Of course, I knew Bourj
Prison before, everyone knows it, it’s a well-known prison
But no one could know what was inside
There’s a door where they bring in prisoners, but they
brought me in from the other side, from another door
Then they took us inside, to the solitary cells
Interviewer: What did you feel when you entered the prison?
I felt afraid of what might happen to me,
because I didn’t know what my charge was
They called me a collaborator, so honestly, I was very afraid
Of course, anyone who enters this place feels fear
Interviewer: How many ISIS members brought you here?
Witness: Eight
Interviewer: Were your hands cuffed
or your eyes blindfolded? Explain more
When they brought me and took me in through the main gate, I
wasn’t blindfolded from the time they took me until this door
When I entered the solitary rooms, they blindfolded me when I went in
They blindfolded me in that area, and there were eight people
They blindfolded me and took me inside, and they put me in the interrogation room
Interviewer: What changes took place at the entrance of the Bourj Prison?
What was this place like before, and how has it become today?
The tower had not been bombed before,
it didn’t have the destruction it has now
Now, it’s the most heavily bombed building in Tabqa, the Bourj