After they took me out of solitary
confinement, they took me to another prison
They blindfolded me and took me to another
prison, then we walked, and I stayed there
I don’t know exactly where that prison was
because they drove me around for about two hours
They took me to the prison, and after I got out, they drove me home
They said, this is enough, you’ll go home, but
don’t cause any trouble, and things like that
I left, but after some time I couldn’t
stay here, I couldn’t live among them
I left for Turkey, and from there went to Germany
I stayed in Germany for four years,
and after the liberation, I came back here
Interviewer: Tell us what happened to you in Germany?
In Germany, about six months after I arrived there
They filed a lawsuit against me on charges
of possessing a weapon and terrorism
Because I had been here and had fought for the Free Syrian Army
They considered that fighting against the regime was
with Jabhat al-Nusra, not with the Free Syrian Army
I was imprisoned for one and a half
years in Germany, in the city of Dortmund
I was released after being sentenced to three years with
suspension, except for the days I had already spent in prison
I left Germany and returned to Turkey, and stayed there
For about nine months, then I returned to Syria
Interviewer: How do you feel standing
now in the place where you were imprisoned?
My feeling at this moment, in this place
where I was imprisoned, is indescribable
I still feel the awe of this place—I’m still afraid of it to this day