Of course, they didn’t bring me through
this door, they brought me through that one
They brought me in from here, I wasn’t blindfolded yet
They stopped me right here and blindfolded me before taking me
through the main door leading to the solitary cells and the rest
They stopped me right here, exactly here, and blindfolded me
They blindfolded me and took me
inside, and after they’d taken me inside
They took me into the interrogation room while I was still
blindfolded, a room that had a majlis [furniture set]
Here, the first thing I saw was this door,
that’s how I knew I had entered from here
But inside, I didn’t know what was there, I just walked
straight ahead, they didn’t take me right or left
We came out from here, straight
ahead like this, then I walked to the right
Exactly from this spot, we entered through that door
We arrived here, of course I couldn’t hear any sounds, nothing at all
Only their voices beside me, they took me into this room
This is the room on the right, we entered through the door
The door was in this spot, I think, around here
They brought me in and made me sit here, then
they left, after about two or three minutes
Here I slightly lifted the blindfold and looked around,
I saw a majlis [furniture set], the room was tidy
I heard their voices coming, around eight of them approached me
They sat beside me while I was blindfolded
and started asking me several questions
Like, what’s your name? Are you
married or not? And questions like that
Then they started asking questions like, Do you have relatives in the Free
Syrian Army? Do you have relatives in regime areas? Questions like these
Interviewer: How many people were here?
Witness: You mean in the room I was in?
Interviewer: Where were these people from?
Witness: Yes, in this room
In this room, it was me and eight of them, because
each one asked me a question, so I knew they were eight
A little while later, after they’d finished interrogating
me, one of them left and said, Bring him some tea
One or two of them went, I don’t know
exactly how many, I don’t remember
They removed my blindfold and brought me a cup of tea
He told me, Drink the tea. I drank,
and he started asking me questions
Like, Didn’t you go to the Free Syrian Army? Are
your relatives in the Free Syrian Army? And so on
Two of them, I think, knew me, of course they were all masked
After they’d finished asking questions,
they took me back to the solitary cell
Interviewer: Was there an audio or video recording, for example?
There was no video, no, audio recording I’m not sure, but
there was no video, no cameras, and they didn’t film me