We left this room and went into one of the investigation rooms
One of them grabbed my hand and
cuffed me, while the other walked behind me
They took me from here, there were rooms here of course
There were solitary cells, and here
I don’t remember what was there
Here there was a man suspended by his limbs, shackled
like this in this area, he was the one groaning and crying
They brought me in from here. This was the
solitary cell I was in. I stayed in this spot
Interviewer: What did the solitary cell contain?
The solitary cell was large and had a toilet and a sink
This wall ended here. It was clear there was
a wall, and there was a toilet in the corner
And there was a water tap in the solitary cells, that’s it
Interviewer: How long did you stay in this solitary cell?
I stayed in this solitary cell for about a week or more than a week
I don’t remember exactly how many days, I didn’t count
Interviewer: How did you spend your day in the solitary cell?
There were books in this area, like a small
library above, and we would read the books
Interviewer: What kind of books were there?
Books like Sahih al-Bukhari, the Prophet’s
hadiths, the Quran, and other religious books
Interviewer: Did diseases spread in the prison
like lice and scabies, or was there attention to hygiene?
In the solitary cell, there were absolutely
no diseases because I was alone in the cell
And I cleaned it, but in the group cells I don’t know if there
were, though I don’t think so because no one ever mentioned diseases
Interviewer: Did you ever get sick and receive medicine
or see a doctor? Was there any medical care for prisoners?
For me, when I had a headache,
they would give me a painkiller, that’s all
Other than that, I don’t know, but I think if someone got sick, they
would bring him a doctor or give him medicine if it was a mild illness
Interviewer: Were the meals provided regularly—breakfast,
lunch, and dinner—or were they limited?
They served multiple meals regularly
Breakfast, lunch, and dinner, and every day something different
Breakfast was simple, like jam, labneh, and cheese
Lunch was sometimes cooked food, sometimes ready food,
and sometimes sandwiches, and dinner was the same
Interviewer: Did you communicate with other prisoners
in solitary cells since you were alone in your room?
Did you try to talk to anyone or hear someone you knew?
Of course, I was in the solitary cell, and I would
get bored. When they brought people into the next cell
Sometimes I tried to talk to them, but no one
replied, no one could reply, they were afraid
In the end, I stopped trying to talk
for fear someone outside might hear
They didn’t beat me except the first time I was
brought here, when one of them hit my shoulder
Interviewer: We know most prisoners write their names
or memories on the wall, did you write your name?
No, I didn’t write my name, a memory, or anything at all
Interviewer: Who were the jailers that came into your solitary cell?
Who were they, what was their accent, and how did they treat you?
Their treatment of me was normal, not harsh
The jailers who came to me treated me normally
With respect, they didn’t like dealing
with prisoners unless necessary
Interviewer: Did you or any of the prisoners here try
to escape from prison? Was there an escape attempt?
In prison, I heard about an escape attempt, but I
never thought about escaping, not even privately
Interviewer: Did you know the people who
tried to escape or the details of the plan?
I don’t know the escape details, but I know
some people tried to escape from Burj Prison
But they couldn’t, they were caught, and I, in
the solitary cell, never thought about escaping
Interviewer: Was the prison ever bombed while you were there?
No, the prison was never bombed
while I was there, the bombing was outside
In the nearby area, but Burj Prison itself wasn’t bombed
Interviewer: Do you have a story or
memory from your time alone in this room?
Do you have a story or incident that happened to you?
One story that happened to me here was when I was in this solitary
cell and there was a balingo [suspension hoist] outside
They brought people there, and I could hear their voices,
their torture, and their beating, I couldn’t imagine it
They took me for interrogation and brought me
back. I still didn’t know what my charge was
Finally, two days before I was released, they told
me my charge was belonging to the Free Syrian Army
And possessing a weapon, that’s what happened with me
In the solitary cell, the light was on day and night
Because during the day we couldn’t see, there was no light
Interviewer: How did you feel being here in
solitary? What thoughts occupied your mind?
What were you thinking about while in this place?
When I was here in solitary, I thought
every day, what will they do to me?
Will they execute me or release
me? Because they killed many people
I didn’t know what my fate would be, that’s what frightened me
In the solitary cell, I had a toilet, a sink, and cleaning tools
And here I had a sponge, a pillow, and a blanket
And here there were shelves for books. That’s what was there
And here there was a chair, and I
used to entertain myself by reading books
Interviewer: How did they bring
you food? How did they give it to you?
They opened the door normally and gave me the food
They didn’t treat me like the other prisoners. They
used to beat them and shout at them and so on
I heard them shouting at others, but for me, they
brought food regularly with politeness and respect
Interviewer: Do you know the nicknames or
names of the jailers who brought you food?
Those who came to my solitary cell brought
me food or medicine or anything I asked for
One was named Abu Abdullah. He was the one who
came to me. And another whose name I didn’t know
Another one was named Shaqran, but mostly it was
Abu Abdullah and that one whose name I didn’t know
Interviewer: Do you remember their features?
Their features, Abu Abdullah was a bit heavyset
He was full-bodied and taller than me,
and the other one had a Syrian accent
Eastern, his body was similar to mine
in height and build, not thin and not fat
Shaqran was thin, thinner
than me, and a bit taller
Interviewer: Did the prisoners and jailers have a uniform or not?
No, they wore black, the jailers wore black
And they were masked or wore shishaniyat [a knee-length garment], and military clothing
Interviewer: Were there visits? Were your
family allowed to visit you or bring you things?
Of course, here in Burj Prison there were absolutely no visits
My family didn’t visit me, no one did,
my family didn’t even know where I was
Interviewer: In prison, did you stay in your
own clothes or were uniforms distributed?
They distributed uniforms to us, and
in the solitary cell they gave me one
They gave me two uniforms, and they were changed
once a week, and I had my own clothes too
Interviewer: Tell us about the uniform’s
features and color, was there anything on it?
There was nothing on it, the uniform was blue with no writing
No flag, symbol, or anything, it was plain
Interviewer: Were there mediations or connections in the prison?
Were there prisoners who were tortured more than others?
As for mediations in their prison, I don’t think there were any
Whoever was proven guilty was beaten,
tortured, imprisoned, and sentenced
And whoever wasn’t proven guilty wasn’t beaten, that’s how it was
Interviewer: What’s the difference between
the Hisba and the other ISIS branches?
And regarding ISIS security branches,
which one did people fear the most?
During ISIS’s days, what people feared most
were the security officers, especially young men
The young men of our generation were afraid of the security
officers because whoever entered their prisons never came out
This was the norm, but the Hisba (religious
police) also terrorized people in general
Because they forced women to wear the niqab [face veil],
and ordered shops to close during the call to prayer
Everyone had to go to the mosque at prayer time. People feared that,
as well as the rules about the izar [long pants], hair, and beards
Interviewer: Regarding the prison’s cleanliness, you
were in a solitary cell, but what about the group cells?
Were the guards responsible for cleaning, or did the
prisoners share the duties of cooking and cleaning?
As for cleanliness in prison, I can tell you about the
solitary cell. I was the one who cleaned it since I was alone
But regarding the group cells, I’m not sure whether they cleaned
them themselves, brought someone in to clean, or took turns doing it
Interviewer: What did the smell of that place feel like?
The one still linked to your memory until this day
As for that place, there wasn’t any specific smell
But once, I smelled blood. Someone had been beaten severely, and
the smell of blood reached me. I stayed in the room for two days
Interviewer: Were there any new words or expressions used in prison
That you hadn’t heard before in your normal life—new words to you?
The words and expressions there were all familiar
Sometimes they spoke in Standard Arabic. I could hear
them from outside of course—they didn’t come inside
That was all, while the rest I understood normally
Interviewer: Were there any specific words you heard for
the first time inside prison, any particular new ones?
Specific words in prison—I didn’t notice or pay
attention to whether there was a word I didn’t understand
Interviewer: ISIS used certain titles for administrative roles
Like the sharia judge, the
wali [governor], or the emir [commander]
Interviewer: Explain to us what each title means—what was their role?
For example, what was the wali’s job in
Raqqa? And also the emir and the sharia judge
Of course, regarding the sharia
judge, the emir, and the wali
We used to hear about them, and knew there was a wali and
a sharia judge. The sharia judge was the general judge
He was called sharia judge because he ruled
according to God’s law, from the Quran and the Sunnah
As for the wali, I don’t know his exact function, but I think
he was like a district manager or someone in charge of an area
And the emir was the person responsible for a
specific place, like the prison emir or the army emir