They interrogated me about three times
Of course, every two or three days
they would come to interrogate me
Then they would take me not
to this room, but to another one
For interrogation. There was no beating, not once
did they hit me, only question and answer each time
Interviewer: Did they propose that you work with them in exchange for your release?
Yes, they did propose that. They
proposed that I work with them
To bring them news about the Free
Syrian Army since I had relatives there
I told them I had no contact with them.
I told them I had no contact with them
And I couldn’t go to those areas, things like that
They went silent and never brought it up again
Interviewer: Do you remember the names of the
interrogators? Surely they called each other by name?
How did they call each other? Do you remember the names?
There was someone called Abu Abdullah,
Syrian, speaking in a Syrian dialect
Of course they were all masked, and there was another one they called Shaqran
These are the names I remember clearly
Interviewer: What was their dialect and from which country?
Witness: Shaqran’s accent was Saudi, and Abu Abdullah’s was Syrian
Interviewer: During the interrogation, did they have
a lot of information about you or only simple details?
Interviewer: How did he question you to get information from you?
During the interrogation they
already had some information about me
Meaning that before they detained me, they had asked about me
Interviewer: Did they threaten you, for example, with your family?
Or that they would harm your family if you didn’t confess?
Of course, they never threatened me, neither
with my family nor with myself, nor anything
There was no threat or beating during the interrogation
Interviewer: Did the interrogation
involve psychological or physical torture?
During the interrogation they didn’t torture me at all, didn’t hit me,
and didn’t insult me, just a normal question-and-answer interrogation
Interviewer: During your time in prison, what were the
tools or methods they used to torture other prisoners?
I saw here the balingo [hoist for suspension],
where they tie a person’s hands and lift him up
That was one of the torture methods. There were many others, but I didn’t
see them, I only heard about them outside, I didn’t see anything myself
Interviewer: Was the torture applied
to all the prisoners or only specific people?
To specific people, only specific ones were tortured,
depending on the charges brought against them
Interviewer: Did you hear that
there were women imprisoned here?
I heard there were women prisoners
here, but I didn’t see any of them
Interviewer: You didn’t even hear
the sound of women being tortured?
No, I didn’t hear women’s voices, and I didn’t see any women
I didn’t see anyone at all. I used to hear
sounds, but they were men’s voices, not women’s
But I did hear that there were
women here, that they brought women
Interviewer: Did any prisoner die
here under torture during your time?
During my time in prison I didn’t hear that anyone died
But there was a man I heard them say, We’ll execute
him, we’ll execute him, but I didn’t see anything
I wasn’t sure if they were just trying to scare him or not
Interviewer: Can you recall the names
of any prisoners who were held with you?
Names of prisoners held with me... I don’t
remember at all, because I didn’t see anyone
All the time I spent here was in solitary confinement.
I saw one person, but I don’t know his name