Name: Rayan Riyad Khalil
Born in 1987
My clan is al-Sabaawi
By God, our—my situation
I was a driver on the Turkey route
We took people and brought others
And in the meantime
I started having problems
They started monitoring us, and so on
And because of that our situation got worse
The route was closed, and we had a shop in Ras al-Kour
It was a barbershop belonging to my brothers
Being there meant I didn’t have a job
We started transporting people and taking them to…
We took them from here to Raqqa, and from Raqqa they went to Turkey
And during this time
Once or twice I was caught, and so on
So I was being watched closely
They kept following me a lot, I was under surveillance
I felt I was being watched
The detention happened at our shop
In Ras al-Kour we had a shop, a barbershop
The detention happened there
A car with three men arrived, a car from the Hisba
They got out, and I was standing in the street
They arrested me on the spot, took my phones, searched me, and brought me to this place
Interviewer: Was there an informant against you?
Yes, there was a clue, but no proof
In the end
He said, We just want any proof against you
And as for the rest, we know how to deal with you
Interviewer: When they came to arrest you, did they come asking for you by name?
Or was there more than one person?
No, me personally
Interviewer: So there was an informant against you?
Yes, there was some tip, but I don’t know what it was
Interviewer: Was it someone you knew, or one of your friends?
Or someone you dealt with in your life through work?
Honestly, there was a young man, and he’s gone now
We had some problems between us, and he was killed in the shelling
After some time, after the liberation, they said that so-and-so, son of so-and-so, was the one
Who informed, and he had a car, and that kind of thing
And he worked transporting people
Interviewer: When did they bring you to this prison? Was it at maghreb [sunset], isha [evening], or at noon?
No, no, at maghreb
Between asr [afternoon] and maghreb, and it was raining
Interviewer: The three people you mentioned. Were they from Mosul or from outside Mosul?
No, their driver was from Mosul
A young man named Mahmoud, and we
And the other two, one was thin and dark-skinned, tall
He was from the countryside or something like that
He wasn’t from Mosul, but the driver was from Mosul
From his accent and the way he spoke
When they first brought us in through the door, there was a prefab room
He leaves you standing in the prefab room
He takes whatever personal items you have, he takes your belongings
After you are handed to him by a Hisba member
The Hisba member who brought you in the car hands you over to the man in the room
Then other men come, take you, and escort you to the holding area
Inside the prefab room he blindfolded me
And he took me some distance
But I knew I was still inside the church
But where inside it he took me, I don’t know
About 15 to 20 meters on foot
And we went up the stairs and entered the room
And when we entered
The total number there was about seven, eight, or nine, around that
When you go in, you’re terrified, you don’t know what your fate will be
You might be released or kept, die, be executed, or be killed, you don’t know
I saw elderly prisoners
And there were young ones too
And some were brought in for smoking
Or because of their pants
Or for not keeping up with prayer
Or for walking in the street, and so on
For many other things
They kept bringing two or three in and taking others out, nonstop like that
There were two who stayed, I was taken out, and they remained there
Interviewer: What were their charges?
Their charges—I don’t know, they had problems and there was a case against them
Related to women or something like that
As I remember, because their case was very serious
According to what I heard from someone
Interviewer: Do you mean their case was about women?
Witness: Yes, because of women
Interviewer: So the case was among themselves? No one had filed a complaint against them?
No, no, I mean they were caught in the act with women
Interviewer: Do you mean an adultery case?
Yes, an adultery case, and those two were with one woman
And for that reason they were kept here
Interviewer: The woman who was with them, did they tell you which court they took her to?
No, no, they took the woman
But they put her in a different place
Interviewer: Was there a women’s prison in this place?
You can expect anything from them
Because there are many rooms, this one and others
And on the other side, that was also a prison
Interviewer: So you didn’t hear women’s voices?
No, I didn’t, but there were sounds of torture
Mostly at night and at dawn, especially at night
Interviewer: How many days did you stay in this room, which is a cell?
About eight days or nine days
Interviewer: Eight days or nine days
When you entered the room, did they take you straight to the judge for interrogation?
Or did you stay for a while, and then they took you to the Investigative Judge?
No, I stayed until the second day, then they referred me to the judge
Of course, when they took you to the judge, your eyes were blindfolded and they would lift the blindfold in front of the judge
He said, You're before the judge
He started by asking me about prayer and about religion, and there was a group sitting beside him
Interviewer: What kind of questions did he ask you?
About prayer, Do you pray? I answered, Yes
I told him, Yes. He said, Do you know how to recite the call to prayer? I told him, Yes
He said—Get up and recite the call to prayer. I tried the call to prayer, but I didn't do it well
He said—This one didn't use to pray, he was lying to us
He said—He must learn the call to prayer and the prayer, and so on
He would ask you with a hard stare when he spoke to you
In a way that makes you afraid even of yourself
No, he is the one who asks you about this
Interviewer: During your interrogation, especially the first interrogation
Did you feel he knew information about your life?
Did he mention any details that no one knew except you and your family?
No, he knew this, but he didn't say it directly
Interviewer: How did you know that?
I mean, it was obvious, he would ask you questions like, You meet with so-and-so, or you go to such-and-such a place
He had information, but who supplied him with it, I don't know
But he told me at that time—This is your last warning
But next time, the punishment will be different
He threatened me, and after I got out I was under surveillance
Whenever I went anywhere, there were one or two people watching me
And in the end, I was being watched
But in the end, I left Iraq
Interviewer: About the judge who was interrogating you
And since you were the one who shaved his hair
Can you describe his features for us?
And about how old he was, his appearance, and the clothes he wore?
As for clothes, he wore black and a black turban
And his beard was like this, and his age was between forty and forty-one, or about forty-two years
Interviewer: Was his dialect Standard Arabic or the dialect of Mosul?
No, no, the dialect was different, he wasn't from Mosul
Interviewer: Standard Arabic or rural? Witness: No, rural
Interviewer: Meaning from the outskirts?
Yes, from the outskirts
From the outskirts of the city
Interviewer: The other people, about how old were they?
Some were in their thirties and also in their twenties
They were from their group, and they were sitting
Interviewer: From their appearance, were they leaders or ordinary people?
No, no, they were leaders, carrying pistols and walkie-talkies
Interviewer: During the judge's interrogation with you?
Regarding what was said to you directly
Interviewer: Did any of the people there ask you a question, or was it only the judge who asked?
No, only the judge, but later the one who sat next to the judge
When prayer was mentioned, he told the judge that this man does not pray
He said, It is obvious—if he prayed, made the call to prayer, and was observant
He would not be answering this way, hesitating and making mistakes
Interviewer: During the judge’s interrogation, was there someone next to him writing it down?
Yes, he was writing, he was writing on a sheet of paper
On a sheet of paper, he was writing
For example—Why did you answer incorrectly to such and such a question?
And your details—where you go, when you come, whom you meet, and whom you walk with
And which grade I was in, he had a lot of information about me
He asked me about them, and I had forgotten them, I had forgotten
Interviewer: Like what?
For example, he told me, You used to work
On the road to Turkey, transporting people and bringing people, and things like that
He asked me questions—I can tell you he was someone who knew a lot about me
When I went in and he started talking to me, I was surprised by what he said
Like someone who knows you personally
Interviewer: Did he ask questions about your presence in your neighborhood?
He asked me about my home, and about my children, how many children I have
Married or single, and so on
And what I have, where I go, and whom I walk with
Even that I used to sit at my friend’s place and he had an electric generator
He said—So you were mostly at the generator at night
Interviewer: Did he ask about specific people to get information about them, and who were they?
Who? No, he did not ask me that
But I felt inside
That I was under surveillance, and he said this
He said, This time we pardoned you, but the second time
We will execute you immediately when we find anything against you
In the first session, I was sentenced because of prayer
And there was an education center, and they made me go there to learn, and so on
Interviewer: You mean to attend a school and classes?
School and classes, meaning they want to brainwash you
Meaning they say this and that, they want to bring you onto their path
They teach you and tell you that they came here for such and such
And that some of them became martyrs, and that you must do such and such, and that your country is a Muslim country, and things like that
Interviewer: Were the school and the classes in this same building?
Yes, in this building
Interviewer: Were there certain days and specific times and hours for the classes?
The classes were every Sunday and Wednesday
About an hour and a half or two hours, an hour and a half for lessons
So twice a week?
Yes, twice a week
There were people who finished—there was nothing against them
But because of prayer, he was obliged to come back—he would be released but had to keep attending
The first teacher, as usual, was one of them
He wore the same clothes they wore
Yes, he was from Mosul
He was from Mosul—he was the one teaching us
Interviewer: Tell us about how the teaching was done. How was it carried out?
There are seats, people sit, and he teaches you
About religious matters, and we’re like this
We came to fight for you, and you should be with us, your brothers are fighting
He teaches you these things, he wants to convince you
Interviewer: Did he focus on certain topics?
Yes, they had certain things, he says you must apply them and be with the brothers
You must defend your honor and other matters to pull you into many things
Interviewer: Like what? Did they call on you to be among the fighters and the mujahideen as they call them?
While talking to you, if it were up to him, he would say—Come and sign to join us
But he wants to bring you to this path gradually
Interviewer: Did he invite you or someone else directly?
He would say—Go out and come, commit
Be with your brothers, go and fight, and so on
He tells you this
Interviewer: So this was the style of the lesson he taught?
As you said, they sentenced you to be taught prayer, fasting, purification, and the call to prayer
And now you’re telling us about other topics related to what they call jihad or to details of fighting
He was the one who taught us, and the first thing he teaches
First he teaches you prayer, how many units of prayer, and about the call to prayer, and so on
That was the lesson
Then in the second lesson, at the same time, he teaches you these matters
Interviewer: What exactly did he teach you?
He tells you, Go out and fight like the brothers, be with them, and don’t give the enemy a chance to win
And so on, he teaches you these matters
Interviewer: So you didn’t know exactly who the enemy he wanted you to fight was?
I want to ask, did you consider yourselves enemies to them inside the prison?
Yes, that’s right
Interviewer: Were you considered an enemy on the same level as the one they fought?
For him, since you are not with him, he considers you his enemy
There were people they brought in
They kept them blindfolded inside
One day they brought a man
They brought him maybe at night, he stayed blindfolded until the next day
Sitting in a corner, what his story was or his fate, we didn’t know
And you couldn’t ask him
And he couldn’t ask you
And you couldn’t approach him
They sat him there, and the next day they took him
Interviewer: This person they brought blindfolded and you didn’t talk to him
Did you receive an order from the jailer or guard not to approach him?
From the moment they brought him in, they told him—Stay like this
Stay in this position
I don’t want to hear anything from you
Interviewer: Did he order you not to talk to him?
Who? When he was talking to him like this, we, out of fear, didn’t talk to him
And we couldn’t ask him, we didn’t know why they’d brought him here
The next day they came and took him away
There was the sound of screaming, but we didn’t see him after that
Interviewer: While this person was isolated and forbidden to talk to
It was as if he had some kind of special immunity or special guard
After a full night, how did this person relieve himself?
He did not relieve himself, he even left without relieving himself
They did not even give him water
How would he relieve himself?
There was a spy
We knew this, and there was a person who would come and sit
He said these people were bad, and of course he was with them
You were afraid to say a single word
Then he would talk to you about other things, and he would press you with questions
He kept pressing with questions a lot
Interviewer: What did he ask about?
He asked us how they had brought us, what this place was, and how they had humiliated us over a cigarette
And whether it was worth it, and so on
He wanted you to say those people were not good, but he was working with them
He wanted to get new information from you, to entrap you
Sometimes it came in a pot, and sometimes in a bowl, depending on the meal
There was no special food, the food was served to everyone, they did not have specific food for anyone
Interviewer: What kind of food?
Rice, and sometimes in the morning yogurt, and things like that
Interviewer: What was for breakfast?
Yogurt and the like, and bread
Interviewer: What was given to each person or prisoner?
There was no portion for each person, at noon they brought a big platter of rice and meat
Or they brought a pot of food, and everyone ate together
Everyone was the same
Whether you were full, ate, or did not eat
You could not tell him you were hungry, and you could not say, Bring me more food
Interviewer: For example, in the morning did each person have a specific samoon [bread roll]?
No, a bag of samoon would come and everyone sat to eat
Interviewer: How much was your share of samoon, one piece or two?
Some ate three pieces of samoon, some two, and some did not eat out of distress
Interviewer: Was the samoon enough?
Interviewer: Did any samoon remain?
No, none of it was left
Interviewer: In your view, was this food cooked inside this building or did it come from outside?
No, it likely came from outside this building
That is obvious, if it was cooked in this building there would have been a smell of food
It could have been cooked here and we did not know
Because you were in a room and did not know your fate
Because of fear and anxiety, nothing stayed in your head
Interviewer: Was there any change in the food? For example, today rice
Tomorrow bulgur and then chickpeas? Or was it all rice?
No, just rice and beans, and things like that
Interviewer: Was it the same type of food the whole time? Witness: Yes
There was, for example, a time when they had a feast
They would give us whatever was left over from it
They gave their leftovers to the prisoners
Interviewer: Was the rice mixed with the broth, or separate?
No, it was separate
Interviewer: The containers they served in, were they plastic?
Made of plastic, plastic
Interviewer: Did you have tea?
Tea was scarce, it was served only in the morning
Interviewer: Did they serve you tea?
Witness: Only in the morning
Interviewer: A cup for each person?
No, no, it came in a thermos
It was enough if each person drank one cup
Interviewer: Were the cups plastic?
Witness: Yes, plastic
Interviewer: When they brought in the food
Did the jailer open the door and bring in the food?
Or would he open the door and call one of you that the food was outside, come take it?
As soon as he brought the food, he would hand it through the door and anyone would take it from him
And he would leave and close the door
Before he served the food, you had finished the previous meal and collected it in a bag
He would take the bag and give you the second meal
Interviewer: Did you have water available, drinking water?
Water was available, drinking water, and if it was cut off there was water from the tank
Interviewer: Did each person have a specific share, or could you ask at any time?
No, there was no specific share
They brought water for drinking, and there would be some left
In the same room there was a toilet
The toilet door was open twenty-four hours
You could relieve yourself whenever you wanted
But in the morning you had to wake up
For prayer at the right time
After the call to prayer, you prayed
Anyone could be the imam and we would pray
Interviewer: Was the imam one of the prisoners?
Yes, one of the prisoners
Interviewer: Did they come to pray with you? Witness: Who do you mean?
Interviewer: The jailers? Witness: No
The jailers prayed, even those who hadn’t been praying
Interviewer: Not the prisoners? Rather the jailer?
No, we didn’t see him
Only if there was an interrogation with you, or they wanted information from you, he would come to take you
Otherwise you stayed in the prison
But at the dawn prayer he would come to wake you; even if you were asleep he would knock on the door
For prayer… prayer… he calls you to prayer
Interviewer: Regarding the toilet, were you able to take your time when you relieved yourself?
No, we were not comfortable—since we entered we did not feel comfortable
Because you do not know your fate
Someone would tell you they would execute you
Another would say they would kill you, and another would say they would cut off your hand
You do not know what your fate is
Interviewer: The water in the toilet—was it hot, warm, or cold?
No, it was tank water, from the tank
Interviewer: Was it always available, or did it get cut off?
It was from the tank, whenever you opened the tap it was there
Cleaning was required, and what did we even have that needed cleaning in the first place
You didn’t have cigarettes
Only leftover food
And the extra water and food, that was the cleaning they had
You had nothing with you
Interviewer: Was there a garbage container?
There were bags you could tie shut
When they gave you food, you tied the bag and threw it at the door, and he would take it
Interviewer: While you were in this place, did you have cleaning supplies?
Like soap, dishwashing liquid, or disinfectants?
No disinfectants, just soap when leaving the toilet
Interviewer: Was the soap enough for you? Witness: It was enough
There were two bars, one for washing hands
And for whoever wanted, like one time
One prisoner told them, I’m janoub [ritually impure], so they told him, Go shower
It was the same place used as both the shower and the toilet
And there were two towels as well
Interviewer: For showering, was it whenever you wanted?
Not whenever you wanted, maybe every two or three days someone would shower
Interviewer: There was no shower schedule? Witness: No, no
Interviewer: You were inside the cell and the toilet was with you too?
The toilet was the same place for showering
Interviewer: No one had authority over you in this matter, you could do it freely?
Yes, we could do it freely
Interviewer: Were you tortured? Did you experience torture?
Only flogging
Interviewer: Before the flogging, any other torture?
No, they didn’t torture me, just flogging at that time
Interviewer: Were there torture rooms?
Yes, they had torture rooms in this place
Interviewer: Were there prisoners with you who were taken for torture and brought back?
Yes, many prisoners
They took them for torture, and they beat them unbelievably
Interviewer: They were with you in the same room? Witness: In the same room
Some were moved to other rooms, and some were taken again
Interviewer: The people you were close to, when they were taken for torture
And brought back again, didn’t they tell you about the torture methods?
The ones used on them, like the falaqa [foot whipping], flogging, electricity, or the mazaref [body piercing]?
Everything, there were people they used everything on
They would walk in on their feet, and return carried in a blanket
Interviewer: Did they have torture marks?
Yes, they showed torture marks, but as I told you before
You couldn’t ask, What’s your story, what happened to you, and so on
Interviewer: I mean, did they bring them back after torture?
Was it obvious they had been tortured by skinning? Or flogging?
Or with electricity, or hanging, and so on?
No, there was electricity, and they hit them with a stick
I mean their body was crushed, they hit them with a metal pipe
Interviewer: Do you have a story about one of the people who was with you
About the torture method used on him?
They would take him for two or three days
But it never happened to me
Interviewer: It didn’t happen in front of you?
Witness: No, by God
That’s according to what I had heard, that’s how it was
Interviewer: At night, when you were in the room
Did you hear screams of people being tortured?
Yes, that happens, killing and screams
But where did it come from? You don’t know
Interviewer: Were the screams close or far?
No, it wasn’t very far, I mean
Interviewer: So do you think it was from the rooms next to you?
I think so, and I’m sure they had a place for killing and torture
Interviewer: Was the screaming clear?
Witness: Yes, clear, and loud screams
Interviewer: All night or at a specific time?
At night and in the early morning, this happens
I heard about many who died under their torture
Many people died during torture
Interviewer: Are you saying, or did you hear, that they died from torture?
What kinds of torture did they use?
They tortured them in many ways
Many, anything you can think of in torture
Interviewer: About how many people?
They tortured many people
Many died from torture, and many collapsed from torture
And many suffered other things because of torture
There are people to this day who suffer illnesses as a result of torture
Some got diabetes, some got high blood pressure, or had a stroke
And some even got cancer
Interviewer: How did you sleep in the room?
Did you feel comfortable while sleeping?
Honestly, there was no comfort
First, fear, and second, planes all night
And every minute, every moment you say, I’m dead
Why? Because there is a chance we will be bombed
Because of their coming and going
You say, We will be bombed, this place will be bombed
Especially when hearing the sound of airplanes
Terror takes hold in your heart
You sit and recite the shahada, and you brace yourself that you will die
Interviewer: How did you spend the time during the day?
We spent it sitting and reading a verse, and so on
Interviewer: Were there Qurans inside the room?
Yes, there were pages and so on
But I still can’t read or write, I just held it for appearance
Interviewer: The one who could read, did they force him to read or not?
There were some who could read, with the Quran in hand, and they raised their voice
They told him to read so the others with him would listen
Interviewer: When you were inside the detention room
Was there a camera pointed at you so that everything you did was visible?
Were you visible to them inside the room?
I don’t know, maybe there was a camera
Maybe, but I don’t remember whether it was there or not
But I remember there was a camera
I remember, in the corner
Interviewer: Did you think your rooms were monitored?
Monitored, I remember, I swear to God
But I’m not a hundred percent sure right now
Interviewer: While you were in that room?
Was there a display screen there?
Did ISIS show you its videos on that screen?
Execution videos, execution and amputation videos?
And battles, were they shown?
In that room we didn’t have it
But after we left
A young man who had been inside before asked me
He said, They used to put it on a memory card
And show us those things
To keep fear in the prisoner’s heart
Interviewer: In your room it wasn’t there?
No, in our room it wasn’t there
But the same thing was in the halls
It was in other places
They were annoyed with us
But that happens
Because you’re not one of their members
Considering you’re in that place with them
He tells you—We’re fighting for you, doing this and that, and we have martyrs
We’re fighting in battles and you’re sitting here, you’re supposed to be with your brothers
And so on, and he keeps talking, trying to convince you
He wants to get that idea into your head and thinking
Interviewer: How many guards were in the room with you?
For us, there were two
The guys called one Abu... I don’t remember his name
And the other, Abu Shalaan
Interviewer: Did they take shifts or were they together?
No, each one separately, and sometimes both came
And sometimes one would come, knock on the door, and say—We’re not hearing you anymore
You’re not reading the Quran anymore, and so on
Interviewer: During your time there, over twenty-four hours a day
Were they the same ones or did they change?
No, they changed, they changed
Interviewer: How often did they change?
Every two days, they didn’t stay in the same place
Interviewer: Did the guards here participate in battles?
Did they go out, return, and take part in fighting and support?
When would they go out and come back?
Sometimes there were alerts
At times we’d say there’s no one here except us
Especially when the airstrikes came
We’d say only the prisoners might be here, we couldn’t hear their voices
Then after three or four hours
They might come, and you’d hear them moving back and forth
Interviewer; Did you see yourselves as targeted?
We were targeted, targeted one hundred percent
Targeted—if not by them, then by the planes overhead
We didn’t know in which minute we’d be struck
Interviewer: While you were there and the planes arrived, they would withdraw from the whole building
Did you expect that?
Honestly, at times I
Interviewer: Did you have a sense of what was happening outside and so on?
Sometimes we heard the heavy sound of planes
Here we didn’t hear any sound, there was no one
We would say they’d left us here and we would be bombed while they were gone
In that situation you don’t know what you will do, you are terrified
Even when sleeping, you wake up suddenly from the planes, something terrifying
Interviewer: Do they disappear from the building before you hear the planes, or while the planes are overhead do they vanish?
As soon as the planes started flying, you didn’t hear any movement from them
Interviewer: Do you think they knew the planes were coming?
Honestly, I don’t know
In my view, they knew about it
I remember it happened to us two or three times
And I said it was likely this building would be bombed, and they left us alone in it and departed
We were desperate about that situation
Interviewer: If this building, as they thought, was targeted
Why didn’t they try to move you to another place if this building was targeted?
Why didn’t they try to move you?
One time we were here, and during the lesson heavy plane activity started
He said—Immediately end the lesson and return every prisoner to his place
Within a minute they dispersed quickly
Meaning they even ended the lesson
Interviewer: So he ordered them to disperse? Witness: Yes, to disperse
Interviewer: While you were in the detention room, did any of you develop a chronic illness
Or did someone get scabies or a skin disease
Such that he needed special medical care, or to be moved to another place?
No, that did not happen, but one day
As I heard, someone became very ill and they transferred him to the hospital
Interviewer: Did they take him to the hospital, or did a doctor come to you?
No, to the hospital, no doctor came to us
Interviewer: No doctor came to you?
The one whose condition was critical from the start would be transferred to the hospital, as I heard
Interviewer: Was the one taken to the hospital under guard?
We didn’t know if they took him to the hospital or to the clinic
We only knew they moved him to another place
Interviewer: If you or one of the prisoners had a headache or his blood pressure rose
Or got the flu or similar illnesses
Would a doctor or a nurse come to provide you with treatment and health care?
No, no, that didn’t happen with us, and no one asked us
Interviewer: Didn’t you ever ask a jailer for treatment?
No, no, but one day someone was talking and he said
And he had been in the prison before me
He said—There was a person with us, his condition was critical, he got very sick, and he had a chronic illness
He had epilepsy—a nerve disorder—I think, or something like that
He fell ill suddenly, and they came, took him, and transferred him to the hospital
Interviewer: Did they bring him back? Witness: Yes, they brought him back
They brought him the next day—they took him to the hospital or somewhere else, I don’t know
To the hospital or somewhere else, I don’t know
Interviewer: In this prison, were there visits from families and relatives?
No, no
Interviewer: Didn’t anyone visit you?
No one visited me, and even if someone came to ask about me here, they would tell him I’m not here
Interviewer: Anyone else?
As for me, my father came and asked about me, and they told him I wasn’t here
Even though I was detained with them, they said, He’s not with us
Interviewer: There were no visits? Witness: No
They send him to the Faisaliya Center and tell him, Ask about him there, he went and asked
Interviewer: Were there any special visits for other people?
I don’t know—as for me, my family came and asked about me, and they told them–Not here
Interviewer: Tell us how you got out, the method and the form of your release
I signed a pledge
Interviewer: What did the pledge stipulate, what did you commit to?
A pledge that if I was caught committing violations
Like skipping prayer and the like, then my punishment would be tripled
For now that’s what they decided for me—later we don’t know what they’ll decide
Your situation becomes frightening later if they catch you a second time
And anyone who goes in to them becomes monitored afterward, and they know everything about him
Interviewer: When you left, were your deposited belongings complete, or did they take anything?
No, no
I had only a ring, a watch, and a phone, and I took them
Nothing was missing?
No, no, my belongings were in an envelope and my name was written on it
Interviewer: Did they take you home, or did they leave you here?
No, no, they took me to the street and left me
They didn’t use this method with you?
No, no, they left me at 11 p.m.
Interviewer: Did you know that you would be released that day? Witness: No
Interviewer: Did you find out directly and suddenly?
Suddenly, before you know it, he’s calling
I told you, sometimes two come and call someone to take him; they might not bring him back, or they might bring him back
Or they transfer him somewhere else
Interviewer: From the moment they took you out of the room until they took you out of the prison
Were your hands tied, or were you free when they took you out?
When they release you, they only blindfold you until you reach the start of the street
They remove the blindfold and tell you–Go
Interviewer: Tell me about the moment when you met your mother and your wife
And they met you after you had been missing for a long time, and they didn’t know what had happened to you
How did you handle this situation, and how did they receive you?
By God, it was an indescribable feeling
Something indescribable
Is your mother alive? Witness: Yes, thank God
Interviewer: How did they receive you?
The situation at home was like hell
They didn’t know my fate—one person would tell them one thing, and another would tell them I was detained
And another says they killed him, and another says they threw him into Khafsa
And another says they will execute them
So whenever someone is executed, they start thinking about me
So my family’s minds are all scattered
Interviewer: After you served your time in prison, how did your life change?
Is your life the same as before prison?
No, but I’ve started to feel that I’m being watched, and so on
Interviewer: Didn’t you develop a nervous or hysterical condition
After you were released, or any specific mental illness?
No, but I feel my nerves are tense to this day
Interviewer: Is the way you deal with your wife and kids the same as before prison?
I mean your relationship with them, in terms of mindset and behavior?
No, there is none of that
Interviewer: Did they notice any kind of change in you?
Only sometimes I get moments of nervous tension, as soon as I get annoyed by something
Interviewer: Your closest person, your wife—did she tell you that you weren’t like this before?
Yes, I wasn’t like this before, I don’t even have any patience
Now wherever I am, I have no patience, I don’t like to talk much about any topic
Interviewer: Did it happen to you after you were released, that in the morning when you wake up
You wake in the morning and can’t open your eyes?
Afraid that you’re still in prison and you were dreaming you got out?
By God, talking about those things—when I was detained and when I was released
A big problem, and the hardest feeling
When I got home, they hadn’t expected that I would come back