Name: Rayan Riyad Khalil
Born in 1987
My clan is al-Sabaawi
By God, our—my situation
I was a driver on the Turkey route
We took people and brought others
And in the meantime
I started having problems
They started monitoring us, and so on
And because of that our situation got worse
The route was closed, and we had a shop in Ras al-Kour
It was a barbershop belonging to my brothers
Being there meant I didn’t have a job
We started transporting people and taking them to…
We took them from here to Raqqa, and from Raqqa they went to Turkey
And during this time
Once or twice I was caught, and so on
So I was being watched closely
They kept following me a lot, I was under surveillance
I felt I was being watched