The detention happened at our shop
In Ras al-Kour we had a shop, a barbershop
The detention happened there
A car with three men arrived, a car from the Hisba
They got out, and I was standing in the street
They arrested me on the spot, took my phones, searched me, and brought me to this place
Interviewer: Was there an informant against you?
Yes, there was a clue, but no proof
In the end
He said, We just want any proof against you
And as for the rest, we know how to deal with you
Interviewer: When they came to arrest you, did they come asking for you by name?
Or was there more than one person?
No, me personally
Interviewer: So there was an informant against you?
Yes, there was some tip, but I don’t know what it was
Interviewer: Was it someone you knew, or one of your friends?
Or someone you dealt with in your life through work?
Honestly, there was a young man, and he’s gone now
We had some problems between us, and he was killed in the shelling
After some time, after the liberation, they said that so-and-so, son of so-and-so, was the one
Who informed, and he had a car, and that kind of thing
And he worked transporting people
Interviewer: When did they bring you to this prison? Was it at maghreb [sunset], isha [evening], or at noon?
No, no, at maghreb
Between asr [afternoon] and maghreb, and it was raining
Interviewer: The three people you mentioned. Were they from Mosul or from outside Mosul?
No, their driver was from Mosul
A young man named Mahmoud, and we
And the other two, one was thin and dark-skinned, tall
He was from the countryside or something like that
He wasn’t from Mosul, but the driver was from Mosul
From his accent and the way he spoke