When they first brought us in through the door, there was a prefab room
He leaves you standing in the prefab room
He takes whatever personal items you have, he takes your belongings
After you are handed to him by a Hisba member
The Hisba member who brought you in the car hands you over to the man in the room
Then other men come, take you, and escort you to the holding area
Inside the prefab room he blindfolded me
And he took me some distance
But I knew I was still inside the church
But where inside it he took me, I don’t know
About 15 to 20 meters on foot
And we went up the stairs and entered the room
And when we entered
The total number there was about seven, eight, or nine, around that
When you go in, you’re terrified, you don’t know what your fate will be
You might be released or kept, die, be executed, or be killed, you don’t know
I saw elderly prisoners
And there were young ones too
And some were brought in for smoking
Or because of their pants
Or for not keeping up with prayer
Or for walking in the street, and so on
For many other things
They kept bringing two or three in and taking others out, nonstop like that
There were two who stayed, I was taken out, and they remained there
Interviewer: What were their charges?
Their charges—I don’t know, they had problems and there was a case against them
Related to women or something like that
As I remember, because their case was very serious
According to what I heard from someone
Interviewer: Do you mean their case was about women?
Witness: Yes, because of women
Interviewer: So the case was among themselves? No one had filed a complaint against them?
No, no, I mean they were caught in the act with women
Interviewer: Do you mean an adultery case?
Yes, an adultery case, and those two were with one woman
And for that reason they were kept here
Interviewer: The woman who was with them, did they tell you which court they took her to?
No, no, they took the woman
But they put her in a different place
Interviewer: Was there a women’s prison in this place?
You can expect anything from them
Because there are many rooms, this one and others
And on the other side, that was also a prison
Interviewer: So you didn’t hear women’s voices?
No, I didn’t, but there were sounds of torture
Mostly at night and at dawn, especially at night
Interviewer: How many days did you stay in this room, which is a cell?
About eight days or nine days
Interviewer: Eight days or nine days
When you entered the room, did they take you straight to the judge for interrogation?
Or did you stay for a while, and then they took you to the Investigative Judge?
No, I stayed until the second day, then they referred me to the judge