Interviewer: How did you sleep in the room?
Did you feel comfortable while sleeping?
Honestly, there was no comfort
First, fear, and second, planes all night
And every minute, every moment you say, I’m dead
Why? Because there is a chance we will be bombed
Because of their coming and going
You say, We will be bombed, this place will be bombed
Especially when hearing the sound of airplanes
Terror takes hold in your heart
You sit and recite the shahada, and you brace yourself that you will die
Interviewer: How did you spend the time during the day?
We spent it sitting and reading a verse, and so on
Interviewer: Were there Qurans inside the room?
Yes, there were pages and so on
But I still can’t read or write, I just held it for appearance
Interviewer: The one who could read, did they force him to read or not?
There were some who could read, with the Quran in hand, and they raised their voice
They told him to read so the others with him would listen
Interviewer: When you were inside the detention room
Was there a camera pointed at you so that everything you did was visible?
Were you visible to them inside the room?
I don’t know, maybe there was a camera
Maybe, but I don’t remember whether it was there or not
But I remember there was a camera
I remember, in the corner
Interviewer: Did you think your rooms were monitored?
Monitored, I remember, I swear to God
But I’m not a hundred percent sure right now
Interviewer: While you were in that room?
Was there a display screen there?
Did ISIS show you its videos on that screen?
Execution videos, execution and amputation videos?
And battles, were they shown?
In that room we didn’t have it
But after we left
A young man who had been inside before asked me
He said, They used to put it on a memory card
And show us those things
To keep fear in the prisoner’s heart
Interviewer: In your room it wasn’t there?
No, in our room it wasn’t there
But the same thing was in the halls
It was in other places