In the same room there was a toilet
The toilet door was open twenty-four hours
You could relieve yourself whenever you wanted
But in the morning you had to wake up
For prayer at the right time
After the call to prayer, you prayed
Anyone could be the imam and we would pray
Interviewer: Was the imam one of the prisoners?
Yes, one of the prisoners
Interviewer: Did they come to pray with you? Witness: Who do you mean?
Interviewer: The jailers? Witness: No
The jailers prayed, even those who hadn’t been praying
Interviewer: Not the prisoners? Rather the jailer?
No, we didn’t see him
Only if there was an interrogation with you, or they wanted information from you, he would come to take you
Otherwise you stayed in the prison
But at the dawn prayer he would come to wake you; even if you were asleep he would knock on the door
For prayer… prayer… he calls you to prayer
Interviewer: Regarding the toilet, were you able to take your time when you relieved yourself?
No, we were not comfortable—since we entered we did not feel comfortable
Because you do not know your fate
Someone would tell you they would execute you
Another would say they would kill you, and another would say they would cut off your hand
You do not know what your fate is
Interviewer: The water in the toilet—was it hot, warm, or cold?
No, it was tank water, from the tank
Interviewer: Was it always available, or did it get cut off?
It was from the tank, whenever you opened the tap it was there
Cleaning was required, and what did we even have that needed cleaning in the first place
You didn’t have cigarettes
Only leftover food
And the extra water and food, that was the cleaning they had
You had nothing with you
Interviewer: Was there a garbage container?
There were bags you could tie shut
When they gave you food, you tied the bag and threw it at the door, and he would take it
Interviewer: While you were in this place, did you have cleaning supplies?
Like soap, dishwashing liquid, or disinfectants?
No disinfectants, just soap when leaving the toilet
Interviewer: Was the soap enough for you? Witness: It was enough
There were two bars, one for washing hands
And for whoever wanted, like one time
One prisoner told them, I’m janoub [ritually impure], so they told him, Go shower
It was the same place used as both the shower and the toilet
And there were two towels as well
Interviewer: For showering, was it whenever you wanted?
Not whenever you wanted, maybe every two or three days someone would shower
Interviewer: There was no shower schedule? Witness: No, no
Interviewer: You were inside the cell and the toilet was with you too?
The toilet was the same place for showering
Interviewer: No one had authority over you in this matter, you could do it freely?
Yes, we could do it freely