Sometimes it came in a pot, and sometimes in a bowl, depending on the meal
There was no special food, the food was served to everyone, they did not have specific food for anyone
Interviewer: What kind of food?
Rice, and sometimes in the morning yogurt, and things like that
Interviewer: What was for breakfast?
Yogurt and the like, and bread
Interviewer: What was given to each person or prisoner?
There was no portion for each person, at noon they brought a big platter of rice and meat
Or they brought a pot of food, and everyone ate together
Everyone was the same
Whether you were full, ate, or did not eat
You could not tell him you were hungry, and you could not say, Bring me more food
Interviewer: For example, in the morning did each person have a specific samoon [bread roll]?
No, a bag of samoon would come and everyone sat to eat
Interviewer: How much was your share of samoon, one piece or two?
Some ate three pieces of samoon, some two, and some did not eat out of distress
Interviewer: Was the samoon enough?
Interviewer: Did any samoon remain?
No, none of it was left
Interviewer: In your view, was this food cooked inside this building or did it come from outside?
No, it likely came from outside this building
That is obvious, if it was cooked in this building there would have been a smell of food
It could have been cooked here and we did not know
Because you were in a room and did not know your fate
Because of fear and anxiety, nothing stayed in your head
Interviewer: Was there any change in the food? For example, today rice
Tomorrow bulgur and then chickpeas? Or was it all rice?
No, just rice and beans, and things like that
Interviewer: Was it the same type of food the whole time? Witness: Yes
There was, for example, a time when they had a feast
They would give us whatever was left over from it
They gave their leftovers to the prisoners
Interviewer: Was the rice mixed with the broth, or separate?
No, it was separate
Interviewer: The containers they served in, were they plastic?
Made of plastic, plastic
Interviewer: Did you have tea?
Tea was scarce, it was served only in the morning
Interviewer: Did they serve you tea?
Witness: Only in the morning
Interviewer: A cup for each person?
No, no, it came in a thermos
It was enough if each person drank one cup
Interviewer: Were the cups plastic?
Witness: Yes, plastic
Interviewer: When they brought in the food
Did the jailer open the door and bring in the food?
Or would he open the door and call one of you that the food was outside, come take it?
As soon as he brought the food, he would hand it through the door and anyone would take it from him
And he would leave and close the door
Before he served the food, you had finished the previous meal and collected it in a bag
He would take the bag and give you the second meal
Interviewer: Did you have water available, drinking water?
Water was available, drinking water, and if it was cut off there was water from the tank
Interviewer: Did each person have a specific share, or could you ask at any time?
No, there was no specific share
They brought water for drinking, and there would be some left