Interviewer: While you were in the detention room, did any of you develop a chronic illness
Or did someone get scabies or a skin disease
Such that he needed special medical care, or to be moved to another place?
No, that did not happen, but one day
As I heard, someone became very ill and they transferred him to the hospital
Interviewer: Did they take him to the hospital, or did a doctor come to you?
No, to the hospital, no doctor came to us
Interviewer: No doctor came to you?
The one whose condition was critical from the start would be transferred to the hospital, as I heard
Interviewer: Was the one taken to the hospital under guard?
We didn’t know if they took him to the hospital or to the clinic
We only knew they moved him to another place
Interviewer: If you or one of the prisoners had a headache or his blood pressure rose
Or got the flu or similar illnesses
Would a doctor or a nurse come to provide you with treatment and health care?
No, no, that didn’t happen with us, and no one asked us
Interviewer: Didn’t you ever ask a jailer for treatment?
No, no, but one day someone was talking and he said
And he had been in the prison before me
He said—There was a person with us, his condition was critical, he got very sick, and he had a chronic illness
He had epilepsy—a nerve disorder—I think, or something like that
He fell ill suddenly, and they came, took him, and transferred him to the hospital
Interviewer: Did they bring him back? Witness: Yes, they brought him back
They brought him the next day—they took him to the hospital or somewhere else, I don’t know
To the hospital or somewhere else, I don’t know