There were people they brought in
They kept them blindfolded inside
One day they brought a man
They brought him maybe at night, he stayed blindfolded until the next day
Sitting in a corner, what his story was or his fate, we didn’t know
And you couldn’t ask him
And he couldn’t ask you
And you couldn’t approach him
They sat him there, and the next day they took him
Interviewer: This person they brought blindfolded and you didn’t talk to him
Did you receive an order from the jailer or guard not to approach him?
From the moment they brought him in, they told him—Stay like this
Stay in this position
I don’t want to hear anything from you
Interviewer: Did he order you not to talk to him?
Who? When he was talking to him like this, we, out of fear, didn’t talk to him
And we couldn’t ask him, we didn’t know why they’d brought him here
The next day they came and took him away
There was the sound of screaming, but we didn’t see him after that
Interviewer: While this person was isolated and forbidden to talk to
It was as if he had some kind of special immunity or special guard
After a full night, how did this person relieve himself?
He did not relieve himself, he even left without relieving himself
They did not even give him water
How would he relieve himself?
There was a spy
We knew this, and there was a person who would come and sit
He said these people were bad, and of course he was with them
You were afraid to say a single word
Then he would talk to you about other things, and he would press you with questions
He kept pressing with questions a lot
Interviewer: What did he ask about?
He asked us how they had brought us, what this place was, and how they had humiliated us over a cigarette
And whether it was worth it, and so on
He wanted you to say those people were not good, but he was working with them
He wanted to get new information from you, to entrap you