They were annoyed with us
But that happens
Because you’re not one of their members
Considering you’re in that place with them
He tells you—We’re fighting for you, doing this and that, and we have martyrs
We’re fighting in battles and you’re sitting here, you’re supposed to be with your brothers
And so on, and he keeps talking, trying to convince you
He wants to get that idea into your head and thinking
Interviewer: How many guards were in the room with you?
For us, there were two
The guys called one Abu... I don’t remember his name
And the other, Abu Shalaan
Interviewer: Did they take shifts or were they together?
No, each one separately, and sometimes both came
And sometimes one would come, knock on the door, and say—We’re not hearing you anymore
You’re not reading the Quran anymore, and so on
Interviewer: During your time there, over twenty-four hours a day
Were they the same ones or did they change?
No, they changed, they changed
Interviewer: How often did they change?
Every two days, they didn’t stay in the same place
Interviewer: Did the guards here participate in battles?
Did they go out, return, and take part in fighting and support?
When would they go out and come back?
Sometimes there were alerts
At times we’d say there’s no one here except us
Especially when the airstrikes came
We’d say only the prisoners might be here, we couldn’t hear their voices
Then after three or four hours
They might come, and you’d hear them moving back and forth
Interviewer; Did you see yourselves as targeted?
We were targeted, targeted one hundred percent
Targeted—if not by them, then by the planes overhead
We didn’t know in which minute we’d be struck
Interviewer: While you were there and the planes arrived, they would withdraw from the whole building
Did you expect that?
Honestly, at times I
Interviewer: Did you have a sense of what was happening outside and so on?
Sometimes we heard the heavy sound of planes
Here we didn’t hear any sound, there was no one
We would say they’d left us here and we would be bombed while they were gone
In that situation you don’t know what you will do, you are terrified
Even when sleeping, you wake up suddenly from the planes, something terrifying
Interviewer: Do they disappear from the building before you hear the planes, or while the planes are overhead do they vanish?
As soon as the planes started flying, you didn’t hear any movement from them
Interviewer: Do you think they knew the planes were coming?
Honestly, I don’t know
In my view, they knew about it
I remember it happened to us two or three times
And I said it was likely this building would be bombed, and they left us alone in it and departed
We were desperate about that situation
Interviewer: If this building, as they thought, was targeted
Why didn’t they try to move you to another place if this building was targeted?
Why didn’t they try to move you?
One time we were here, and during the lesson heavy plane activity started
He said—Immediately end the lesson and return every prisoner to his place
Within a minute they dispersed quickly
Meaning they even ended the lesson
Interviewer: So he ordered them to disperse? Witness: Yes, to disperse