Interviewer: In this prison, were there visits from families and relatives?
No, no
Interviewer: Didn’t anyone visit you?
No one visited me, and even if someone came to ask about me here, they would tell him I’m not here
Interviewer: Anyone else?
As for me, my father came and asked about me, and they told him I wasn’t here
Even though I was detained with them, they said, He’s not with us
Interviewer: There were no visits? Witness: No
They send him to the Faisaliya Center and tell him, Ask about him there, he went and asked
Interviewer: Were there any special visits for other people?
I don’t know—as for me, my family came and asked about me, and they told them–Not here