Interviewer: Were you tortured? Did you experience torture?
Only flogging
Interviewer: Before the flogging, any other torture?
No, they didn’t torture me, just flogging at that time
Interviewer: Were there torture rooms?
Yes, they had torture rooms in this place
Interviewer: Were there prisoners with you who were taken for torture and brought back?
Yes, many prisoners
They took them for torture, and they beat them unbelievably
Interviewer: They were with you in the same room? Witness: In the same room
Some were moved to other rooms, and some were taken again
Interviewer: The people you were close to, when they were taken for torture
And brought back again, didn’t they tell you about the torture methods?
The ones used on them, like the falaqa [foot whipping], flogging, electricity, or the mazaref [body piercing]?
Everything, there were people they used everything on
They would walk in on their feet, and return carried in a blanket
Interviewer: Did they have torture marks?
Yes, they showed torture marks, but as I told you before
You couldn’t ask, What’s your story, what happened to you, and so on
Interviewer: I mean, did they bring them back after torture?
Was it obvious they had been tortured by skinning? Or flogging?
Or with electricity, or hanging, and so on?
No, there was electricity, and they hit them with a stick
I mean their body was crushed, they hit them with a metal pipe
Interviewer: Do you have a story about one of the people who was with you
About the torture method used on him?
They would take him for two or three days
But it never happened to me
Interviewer: It didn’t happen in front of you?
Witness: No, by God
That’s according to what I had heard, that’s how it was
Interviewer: At night, when you were in the room
Did you hear screams of people being tortured?
Yes, that happens, killing and screams
But where did it come from? You don’t know
Interviewer: Were the screams close or far?
No, it wasn’t very far, I mean
Interviewer: So do you think it was from the rooms next to you?
I think so, and I’m sure they had a place for killing and torture
Interviewer: Was the screaming clear?
Witness: Yes, clear, and loud screams
Interviewer: All night or at a specific time?
At night and in the early morning, this happens
I heard about many who died under their torture
Many people died during torture
Interviewer: Are you saying, or did you hear, that they died from torture?
What kinds of torture did they use?
They tortured them in many ways
Many, anything you can think of in torture
Interviewer: About how many people?
They tortured many people
Many died from torture, and many collapsed from torture
And many suffered other things because of torture
There are people to this day who suffer illnesses as a result of torture
Some got diabetes, some got high blood pressure, or had a stroke
And some even got cancer