Of course, when they took you to the judge, your eyes were blindfolded and they would lift the blindfold in front of the judge
He said, You're before the judge
He started by asking me about prayer and about religion, and there was a group sitting beside him
Interviewer: What kind of questions did he ask you?
About prayer, Do you pray? I answered, Yes
I told him, Yes. He said, Do you know how to recite the call to prayer? I told him, Yes
He said—Get up and recite the call to prayer. I tried the call to prayer, but I didn't do it well
He said—This one didn't use to pray, he was lying to us
He said—He must learn the call to prayer and the prayer, and so on
He would ask you with a hard stare when he spoke to you
In a way that makes you afraid even of yourself
No, he is the one who asks you about this
Interviewer: During your interrogation, especially the first interrogation
Did you feel he knew information about your life?
Did he mention any details that no one knew except you and your family?
No, he knew this, but he didn't say it directly
Interviewer: How did you know that?
I mean, it was obvious, he would ask you questions like, You meet with so-and-so, or you go to such-and-such a place
He had information, but who supplied him with it, I don't know
But he told me at that time—This is your last warning
But next time, the punishment will be different
He threatened me, and after I got out I was under surveillance
Whenever I went anywhere, there were one or two people watching me
And in the end, I was being watched
But in the end, I left Iraq
Interviewer: About the judge who was interrogating you
And since you were the one who shaved his hair
Can you describe his features for us?
And about how old he was, his appearance, and the clothes he wore?
As for clothes, he wore black and a black turban
And his beard was like this, and his age was between forty and forty-one, or about forty-two years
Interviewer: Was his dialect Standard Arabic or the dialect of Mosul?
No, no, the dialect was different, he wasn't from Mosul
Interviewer: Standard Arabic or rural? Witness: No, rural
Interviewer: Meaning from the outskirts?
Yes, from the outskirts
From the outskirts of the city
Interviewer: The other people, about how old were they?
Some were in their thirties and also in their twenties
They were from their group, and they were sitting
Interviewer: From their appearance, were they leaders or ordinary people?
No, no, they were leaders, carrying pistols and walkie-talkies
Interviewer: During the judge's interrogation with you?
Regarding what was said to you directly
Interviewer: Did any of the people there ask you a question, or was it only the judge who asked?
No, only the judge, but later the one who sat next to the judge
When prayer was mentioned, he told the judge that this man does not pray
He said, It is obvious—if he prayed, made the call to prayer, and was observant
He would not be answering this way, hesitating and making mistakes
Interviewer: During the judge’s interrogation, was there someone next to him writing it down?
Yes, he was writing, he was writing on a sheet of paper
On a sheet of paper, he was writing
For example—Why did you answer incorrectly to such and such a question?
And your details—where you go, when you come, whom you meet, and whom you walk with
And which grade I was in, he had a lot of information about me
He asked me about them, and I had forgotten them, I had forgotten
Interviewer: Like what?
For example, he told me, You used to work
On the road to Turkey, transporting people and bringing people, and things like that
He asked me questions—I can tell you he was someone who knew a lot about me
When I went in and he started talking to me, I was surprised by what he said
Like someone who knows you personally
Interviewer: Did he ask questions about your presence in your neighborhood?
He asked me about my home, and about my children, how many children I have
Married or single, and so on
And what I have, where I go, and whom I walk with
Even that I used to sit at my friend’s place and he had an electric generator
He said—So you were mostly at the generator at night
Interviewer: Did he ask about specific people to get information about them, and who were they?
Who? No, he did not ask me that
But I felt inside
That I was under surveillance, and he said this
He said, This time we pardoned you, but the second time
We will execute you immediately when we find anything against you