In the first session, I was sentenced because of prayer
And there was an education center, and they made me go there to learn, and so on
Interviewer: You mean to attend a school and classes?
School and classes, meaning they want to brainwash you
Meaning they say this and that, they want to bring you onto their path
They teach you and tell you that they came here for such and such
And that some of them became martyrs, and that you must do such and such, and that your country is a Muslim country, and things like that
Interviewer: Were the school and the classes in this same building?
Yes, in this building
Interviewer: Were there certain days and specific times and hours for the classes?
The classes were every Sunday and Wednesday
About an hour and a half or two hours, an hour and a half for lessons
So twice a week?
Yes, twice a week
There were people who finished—there was nothing against them
But because of prayer, he was obliged to come back—he would be released but had to keep attending
The first teacher, as usual, was one of them
He wore the same clothes they wore
Yes, he was from Mosul
He was from Mosul—he was the one teaching us
Interviewer: Tell us about how the teaching was done. How was it carried out?
There are seats, people sit, and he teaches you
About religious matters, and we’re like this
We came to fight for you, and you should be with us, your brothers are fighting
He teaches you these things, he wants to convince you
Interviewer: Did he focus on certain topics?
Yes, they had certain things, he says you must apply them and be with the brothers
You must defend your honor and other matters to pull you into many things
Interviewer: Like what? Did they call on you to be among the fighters and the mujahideen as they call them?
While talking to you, if it were up to him, he would say—Come and sign to join us
But he wants to bring you to this path gradually
Interviewer: Did he invite you or someone else directly?
He would say—Go out and come, commit
Be with your brothers, go and fight, and so on
He tells you this
Interviewer: So this was the style of the lesson he taught?
As you said, they sentenced you to be taught prayer, fasting, purification, and the call to prayer
And now you’re telling us about other topics related to what they call jihad or to details of fighting
He was the one who taught us, and the first thing he teaches
First he teaches you prayer, how many units of prayer, and about the call to prayer, and so on
That was the lesson
Then in the second lesson, at the same time, he teaches you these matters
Interviewer: What exactly did he teach you?
He tells you, Go out and fight like the brothers, be with them, and don’t give the enemy a chance to win
And so on, he teaches you these matters
Interviewer: So you didn’t know exactly who the enemy he wanted you to fight was?
I want to ask, did you consider yourselves enemies to them inside the prison?
Yes, that’s right
Interviewer: Were you considered an enemy on the same level as the one they fought?
For him, since you are not with him, he considers you his enemy