Interviewer: After you served your time in prison, how did your life change?
Is your life the same as before prison?
No, but I’ve started to feel that I’m being watched, and so on
Interviewer: Didn’t you develop a nervous or hysterical condition
After you were released, or any specific mental illness?
No, but I feel my nerves are tense to this day
Interviewer: Is the way you deal with your wife and kids the same as before prison?
I mean your relationship with them, in terms of mindset and behavior?
No, there is none of that
Interviewer: Did they notice any kind of change in you?
Only sometimes I get moments of nervous tension, as soon as I get annoyed by something
Interviewer: Your closest person, your wife—did she tell you that you weren’t like this before?
Yes, I wasn’t like this before, I don’t even have any patience
Now wherever I am, I have no patience, I don’t like to talk much about any topic
Interviewer: Did it happen to you after you were released, that in the morning when you wake up
You wake in the morning and can’t open your eyes?
Afraid that you’re still in prison and you were dreaming you got out?
By God, talking about those things—when I was detained and when I was released
A big problem, and the hardest feeling
When I got home, they hadn’t expected that I would come back