Interviewer: Tell us how you got out, the method and the form of your release
I signed a pledge
Interviewer: What did the pledge stipulate, what did you commit to?
A pledge that if I was caught committing violations
Like skipping prayer and the like, then my punishment would be tripled
For now that’s what they decided for me—later we don’t know what they’ll decide
Your situation becomes frightening later if they catch you a second time
And anyone who goes in to them becomes monitored afterward, and they know everything about him
Interviewer: When you left, were your deposited belongings complete, or did they take anything?
No, no
I had only a ring, a watch, and a phone, and I took them
Nothing was missing?
No, no, my belongings were in an envelope and my name was written on it
Interviewer: Did they take you home, or did they leave you here?
No, no, they took me to the street and left me
They didn’t use this method with you?
No, no, they left me at 11 p.m.
Interviewer: Did you know that you would be released that day? Witness: No
Interviewer: Did you find out directly and suddenly?
Suddenly, before you know it, he’s calling
I told you, sometimes two come and call someone to take him; they might not bring him back, or they might bring him back
Or they transfer him somewhere else
Interviewer: From the moment they took you out of the room until they took you out of the prison
Were your hands tied, or were you free when they took you out?
When they release you, they only blindfold you until you reach the start of the street
They remove the blindfold and tell you–Go
Interviewer: Tell me about the moment when you met your mother and your wife
And they met you after you had been missing for a long time, and they didn’t know what had happened to you
How did you handle this situation, and how did they receive you?
By God, it was an indescribable feeling
Something indescribable
Is your mother alive? Witness: Yes, thank God
Interviewer: How did they receive you?
The situation at home was like hell
They didn’t know my fate—one person would tell them one thing, and another would tell them I was detained
And another says they killed him, and another says they threw him into Khafsa
And another says they will execute them
So whenever someone is executed, they start thinking about me
So my family’s minds are all scattered