They took me to the Investigation Section and up to the second floor
They brought me into a room on the second floor, where the Investigation Section was located
It was headed by Abu Hamza al-Tunisi, the senior sharia official and overall emir
Under him were the Emir of Investigation, Abu Seif Maqs, and Abu Hudhayfa
And Abu Zaid, from the Sakhani clan
His brother, Fayez, was the Emir of the Islamic Police
They took me upstairs
My hands were tied behind my back
And I was blindfolded, and they began beating me
They hit me with sticks and metal rods , the beating was extremely painful
I was beaten for 3 days straight
They poured water on me and kept beating me again and again
When I woke up, I found myself hanging on the wall on the second floor
That area was at the start of Sajiyah Street, at the intersection with Hittin School Street
That place was known as the Investigation Zone
I found myself hanging
I remained hanging on the wall for 18 days
It was the middle of the hot summer season
But our Lord, praise be to Him, is merciful in His mercy
And in His glory and majesty
The heat actually helped me endure the beatings and pain
When my body was hot and sweating, the blows hurt less than when it was cold in winter
I suffered terribly from thirst
My toes barely touched the ground
And I could hardly reach a bottle of drink
I would bring it close when they gave me a break to drink, from the intensity of thirst
Because of the severe torture
Abu Seif wrapped his hand around my beard
He grabbed my beard,it was long,and dragged me by it while my hands were shackled
I was out of breath, but God Almighty gives a person strength
Great and powerful strength
He kept dragging me by my beard, saying, I’ll teach the whole town a lesson through you
He said to me, plainly, “The time of the Prophet is gone”
I told him, Are we now living in Pharaoh’s time?
For you to say the Prophet’s era has passed?
He dragged me by my beard until he brought me to the feet of Ibrahim al-Fakkash
Who was nicknamed al-Bariwi
He was sentenced along with me too
They told us we’d been sentenced to execution, but the ruling hadn’t been carried out yet
He dragged me by my beard, pulling me along the ground
Until we reached the feet of Ibrahim al-Fakkash, nicknamed al-Bariwi
He asked him, Do you know this man?
He replied, Yes, I know him
Abu Seif said to al-Bariwi, This is the clever player, al-Shuweimi
They called me the clever player because they never caught me with cigarettes
I’d been in so many prisons and detentions,arrested 27 times before by the Hisba (religious police)
Once they detained me for security reasons, and another time I spent a month and a half in Point 11
That’s why they gave me that nickname
He dragged me by my beard all that distance, pulled me out of the room again, still dragging me
I stayed with them in the investigation section for about 53 or 54 days
They came
And shackled my hands behind my back again
They took me out after 53 days
And said to me
We’ll spare your neck if you pay a sum of money
In exchange for paying a financial amount
The ruling would be treated like theft but under a religious ruling
In the past, people would say things like, I’ll rob you right before your eyes
My strength and my dignity
They wanted to rob me, but in the name of what the Prophet said,meaning freeing a slave
They asked me, What property do you have? At that time, I owned 6 or 7 cars
Because I worked hard in the cigarette trade
Whether that work was forbidden or not
Some people said it was forbidden, others said it wasn’t
Maybe we were ignorant about it, but we didn’t really know whether it was forbidden or not
The important thing is, I worked hard, forbidden or not
I struggled and earned that money
They took everything I had,gold, silver, and cars
They took everything, even my farmland
I had a deed of ownership from 50 years ago
In my name, inherited from my father
Back then, the Syrian regime used to seize land from people who owned a lot of it
Out of fear, my father registered the land in his sons’ names
He divided the land equally among his sons
So my share was the same as my brothers’
Even the land that was originally my father’s
They made me fingerprint it as sold and bought
I also had a motorbike with two frames at times
I used it around the neighborhood and inside the city during traffic jams and hot weather
They made me fingerprint that as sold and bought too