I was detained many times, and regarding the interrogation sessions
They sometimes lasted long, sometimes they interrogated me, sometimes they didn’t
Just to put psychological pressure on me
My first interrogation was at Point 11
I talked too much during the interrogation because of how unjustly they treated me
I was innocent,I was just trying to earn a living, working as a taxi driver
Because I talked so much, they interrogated me and took me to the judge
Their system was that every week they brought us a blank sheet
We’d write our names, like Talal Mustafa al-Shuweimi
Was he interrogated? If yes, he should write “yes”
If not interrogated, he should write “no”
And was he presented to the judge? “Yes” or “no”
And every time, I wrote “no,” blaming them for my case
Since I had children, no means, and my house was rented in the beginning
Sometimes they’d take me to the prison corridor
At Point 11
They’d leave me for two or three hours, blindfolded
Standing on my feet
Or sitting on the ground
They wouldn’t speak to me or beat me
But I could hear the sounds of torture and beatings in the corridor
They’d shout at the prisoners, Stand up, you dog! Turn around! Lift your foot! They had their own methods of torture
But they didn’t beat me, they just kept me in the corridor blindfolded
Leaving me that way for two or three hours
In the end, he’d say to me, Sheikh
Go back to your group cell. I’d remove the blindfold inside and hand it to him through the window
That happened about 10 times
And the last time
I told them I wanted to be interrogated because I was honestly afraid they’d put me in the corridor again
And one time
I lost my patience
I started crying and said, It’s only one death
A person only dies once
I started crying and shouting, so they blindfolded me and took me away
They took me to the interrogation room
And the interrogator
He died, may God have mercy on him
His name was Abu Abdul Rahman
He was from the Jaif area in Raqqa, from the Ghanem al-Zahir clan
He said to me, Talal al-Shuweimi
You
Are you still doing amulet sorcery?
Since I’m from the Marandiyya clan, and our ancestors were known for religion and for using drums
He said, Do you still make amulet spells and play the drums?
And I knew him. I knew him well
I told him, I swear, Sheikh
I told him these words when you stop playing the rababa [string instrument]
He said to me, Are you the brother of Abdul Rahim Shuweimi?
I said, Yes, I’m his brother
I said, But, Sheikh
At that time, my family was trying to use mediations for me
My mother, an old woman, wherever she saw a clan sheikh or a member of ISIS
Any man with a long beard, she would go to him and say, My son has children, and so on
She would follow them around for her son, hoping they’d release me, and I had children
My children became my parents’ responsibility, and they had no power to help
We argued about this topic
Then he said to me, You’re a filthy person
I said, So now for you the Muslim is filthy, and Muslims deserve execution
It’s the rule of the strong over the weak, and there’s no power or strength
He said to me, God willing, you won’t leave this place
He brought in a man, and that man
Had a medium-sized passenger van
His house was in the Kalta area in Raqqa’s countryside, and he used to transport female teachers
The group forced teachers to attend repentance courses. The point is, he used to drive those teachers
The group accused him of smuggling people out of Raqqa
They brought the man and blindfolded him
That act was meant as punishment for me
I felt it was a punishment for me, and while he was talking to me
He made me sit on a chair
While I was blindfolded
I was only blindfolded and tied with plastic ties
The kind used for bundling electric cables
Then he brought the man and started beating him with a water hose called “Lakhdar Brahimi”
He disfigured the man’s body with the beating
The man cried intensely
I could hear the hose striking near me, and he kept beating him until he killed him
Finally, I was so upset that I said, He’ll kill this man if he continues
I told him, I don’t want the interrogation anymore, just stop hitting him, because I realized he was doing it for my sake
He couldn’t hit me, not out of fear
But because there was no proof against me, so he had no right to beat me
And because Abu Yousuf the interrogator and Abu Suhaib the Tunisian were above him in rank
Although Abu Suhaib the Tunisian was very strict religiously, he never allowed anyone to be beaten