I was tortured and kept being tortured for 3 more days
After 3 days, they took me to the court
There was an air fan in the room where they put us
It was installed in the wall for air and odor ventilation, called the sharaq [door vent]
I told the guys, “Listen, guys
If they take us down to the same room
The sharaq switch is below, and we’re placed upstairs in the solitary cells
When you turn on the metal sharaq, it will make noise
Whoever among you goes down to our old room, turn it on so we know who was sent there”
The first one they summoned was al-Bariwi
We waited 5 minutes, 15 minutes, half an hour, and the sharaq still didn’t turn on
Then they summoned another person too
And the sharaq still didn’t turn on
Fear and terror spread among us
Then they called my name, Talal al-Shuweimi
They shackled me and blindfolded me. Abu Seif lifted me by my shoulder and led me
And Abu Hudhayfa held me by the other shoulder
They carried me forcefully as if they were about to carry out the sentence against me and took me out
They said, “Stand,” so I stood
He asked me, “Are you so-and-so?” I said, “Yes, I am”
He said, “You did this and that.” I said, “Yes, Sheikh, I was the biggest cigarette trader
Under the caliphate, but God guided me, and I quit over a year or a year and a half ago”
“And now, after I quit the trade, you summon me and treat me like this?”
We argued, and the sheikh started insulting me
He said, “You’re talkative and loud. You think religion is a game,” and so on
He said, “You and that woman,I won’t mention her name,
You both smoke hookah and walk around with that other woman”
They were all women suffering from poverty and hunger
They traded cigarettes to earn a living and support their children
Some were widows, others had children, and one had a disabled child
They relied on God and borrowed cigarettes from me
To sell them, cover their expenses, and provide for their families
So I said to him, “Sheikh
You’re accusing me of false charges
Keep the cigarette charge, it’s better than accusing me of adultery
Imagine, I entered prison for cigarette trading and ended up with 10 other charges I had nothing to do with
And sadly, I didn’t even know about them until the very end
In the end, I learned that the cases I was sentenced for had nothing to do with cigarettes
My arrest and interrogation were indeed for cigarette trading
But eventually, none of the charges were related to that
Even in the same court, they accused me of adultery
With one of the women who sold cigarettes
Now tell me, does it make sense? I have 3 wives, my daughters are unmarried, and I have 13 children
And now I’m going to commit adultery?
After 3 wives and after reaching 40 or 45 years old?
I told him, “Sheikh, that’s not logical
Leave me with the cigarette trading charge, may God guide you
Judge me for that,it’s better than judging me for adultery”
I told him, “If you don’t fear God, then you should be feared.” He said, “Do you think we don’t fear God?”
Then he stood up and hit me. I don’t know with what, because I was blindfolded
I felt something running down my head, like heat
And that’s when he pronounced the sentence
He didn’t give me anything, didn’t even let me sit. He just asked me a few harsh questions
Then said, “We sentence you to qisas [retribution]
You did such and such”
He asked, “What do you think of my sentence?”
At that moment, I mocked the judgment
I didn’t take it seriously. I was just a cigarette trader,what does qisas have to do with that?
Why should I be sentenced to retribution for cigarette trading?
They judged me as a corrupter on earth
But “corruption on earth” means armed robbery and banditry
Armed assault,not cigarette trading
And today, the whole world smokes cigarettes
Everyone smokes cigarettes
Even alcohol existed in the time of the Companions
But now, in the time of these “new Companions,”
They want to cut off heads and hands
But there’s no power or strength left,today, they’re strong and we’re weak
He asked me, “What do you say about the judgment?”
I said, “Me?”,I wasn’t afraid, I was relaxed
I wasn’t scared at all, I was at ease
I told him, “I’m satisfied with your judgment.” When I said that, they were surprised
He said, “Why are you satisfied?” I said, “Isn’t this God’s decree, the Almighty?”
“You’re ruling by God’s sharia, and I’m content with God’s law”
Then he said to me
“What will you say to the seven-member committee?”
I said, “Who are the seven-member committee?” He said, “They’re the sheikhs, because your file will be sent to them”
I said, “What difference will my words make?”
“You already sentenced me to qisas,what can those sheikhs do now?”
He said, “Say whatever you want to tell them”
I said, “Send them my regards and tell them the Sheikh’s judgment is false upon falsehood”
Your entire verdict is invalid upon invalid
My case is about cigarettes, and you accused me of adultery and other charges
Just to sentence me to execution
How can you sentence me to execution while I’m blindfolded, shackled, and standing on my feet?
Then one of them stood up
And hit me
He punched me in the stomach and I fell to the ground. They held me as another came from behind and hit me
Of course, I was blindfolded and didn’t know where the blows were coming from
When he hit me, I said, I accept the judgment and law of God Almighty