When they shackled my left hand, I lifted the cloth blindfold from my eyes
I looked and saw that everyone was masked, and at the investigation door
There was a black vehicle for transporting prisoners, marked “Judicial Police”
When they issued execution sentences
They handed the sentenced prisoners to the Judicial Police, which handled executions and amputations
At that moment
Terror, death, and pain fell upon me
It was a situation no one would envy, terrible to the point that
It truly defies description, no matter how I try to explain it
When I saw the Judicial Police and their black vehicle parked there
I saw my friend, Ibrahim al-Fakkash
And another man, both shackled
They hit me immediately
Blindfolded me again, put a black bag over my head, shackled me, and made me sit down
I felt that Ibrahim al-Fakkash, out of fear, was repeating, “There is no god but God”
I crawled toward him
And it was sunset time
I asked him, Are you al-Breiwi?
He said, Yes. I asked, What did they do?
He said, They sentenced me to execution
Then we cried,not because we wanted to, but out of sheer terror
Our fear wasn’t only of death or being shot
But from imagining them holding our heads and slitting our throats with a knife,that’s what truly terrified us
Every second we were dying millions of times inside
Or a billion times,each time imagining the knife descending on our necks
We had already seen ISIS videos showing people being slaughtered with knives
Those scenes stuck in my mind, and I imagined the blade cutting through my neck
We cried from fear
We knew well who ISIS were,they had no mercy, no compassion
The third, the fourth, and others came, but one person remained
It was during Ramadan, and we were fasting
As you know, at sunset, when the call to prayer begins for those fasting
Ibrahim al-Alkan said, I want water
Before you cut off our heads, we ask you to bring us water,we are fasting
So they brought us water
We couldn’t see, because we were blindfolded
They gave the water to Ibrahim
When he drank, the water got stuck in his throat from fear
It lodged in his throat, and he began choking
I was so terrified, I thought they were strangling us one by one
At first, when we heard the sunset call to prayer, we relaxed, thinking no execution would happen then
Because they usually wanted crowds to film their productions
So when the call to prayer came, we felt some relief, knowing that executions never happened at sunset or night
They never carried out executions at that time
When Ibrahim started choking, fear overtook me
I crawled backward and ended up in the arms of my friend al-Breiwi
When I stretched out my right hand, I touched the shoe of one of the ISIS members
Each of us had an ISIS member standing right beside him
I jumped into al-Breiwi’s arms and told him, They’re going to strangle us one by one
Then they brought the last person,I think it was Baraa al-Ano,and shackled him
They put us inside the vehicle
We could see a little from under the blindfold. Inside the vehicle were sharp metal pieces and swords
It felt like we were in a scene from the “Khalid ibn al-Walid” series from the sword era