They put us in a small isolated room with only a toilet
A small room with a toilet recently prepared and designated for us
There was a small window in the wall like this
It had thick iron bars
They brought us new iron chains,thick ones, not thin
As if they were meant to restrain some giant beast
Like in American or foreign movies
There was a huge gorilla in one movie that they enlarged with cameras and computers
It felt like they were chaining a giant gorilla with those massive chains
The chains were so thick that the prisoner couldn’t even move his hand
They shackled us with those chains, and between each person there were 26 links
The chains were white and new
Abu Seif told me he had bought them especially for me, of the expensive kind
He said he bought them exclusively from Qoutli Street
They also brought 7 locks
They placed the chain on my hand and locked it with a padlock
Then left 26 links’ space, chained my friend’s hand, and locked it too
And so on
The first prisoner was Ibrahim al-Fakkash, known as al-Bariwi
And I was second
Ibrahim al-Alkan fell ill
Then they fasten the chain to the wall
Ibrahim al-Fakkash was at the front,
and the other end of the chain was fastened to the wall
The group cell was reserved for just the seven of us
They used to bring us a plate of oil and thyme
They would come in wearing masks and bring us food
I used to tell Al-Bariwi, our charge isn’t about the cigarette trade
They chained us and sentenced us to execution
And today this man comes in bringing us food while masked, and we’re bound with iron chains
They even spoke to us through cameras and loudspeakers, telling us to move back
So we’d retreat and hide in a corner of the room while they brought in a plate of oil and thyme
We’d eat like that, and during the first 7 days, we didn’t eat anything until an emir came in
He was from the Al-Dabba family, his name was Abu Saqr
May God grant him wellness, guide him, and forgive him
May God forgive him in this life and the next
He came to us and started sitting with us every day for half an hour
He would tell us prophetic hadiths
May God bless him and guide him
And protect him for his children, God willing
He began forcing us to eat, like how one feeds a patient in intensive care
He’d put a bite of bread in our mouths, forcing us to eat
He started easing our suffering a little
We stayed like this under Abu Saqr’s care
For about three and a half months
Around three and a half months, or about three months and 20 days
When Abu Saqr’s shift ended, another would take over at night
No one dealt with us except Abu Saqr and the plate of thyme
I fell ill
And the weather turned cold
It’s honestly painful to talk about
It wasn’t a human act
Nor an Islamic one, not even something the Jews of Khaybar would do
Because 7 of us sentenced to execution were chained with iron shackles
And there were 27 links between each man
When I needed to go to the toilets
God is witness to what I say
And I wanted to sit to relieve myself
When I sat, my friend next to me had to bend toward me
The third had to bend his body, and the fourth had to stand over me
Meaning four of us stood in the toilet so one could relieve himself, may God honor you
What kind of Islam is that? What sharia allows it?
Seven Muslim men chained together, entering the toilets three or four at a time
It was disgusting behavior
And when one of us got sick
Many of the young men got diarrhea, or someone needed to urinate, it was obvious
We all had to wake up, because between me and the next man were 26 links, so all 7 of us had to get up
Especially when one of us was sick with diarrhea
We stayed like that for about three and a half months, or three months and 20 days