Sometimes the hallucinations and fear cause sicknesses like diarrhea, chills, and psychological illness
There was a man with us named Qadri al-Dabba
Qadri al-Dabba started screaming in his sleep
His eyes bulged, foam came out of his mouth,he became seriously ill, not normal at all
Interviewer: Did the organization help him, or did they leave him to suffer?
They didn’t give him anything, his fits would come every 4 or 5 hours
One time, I fell sick myself
I got chills and severe diarrhea inside the prison
It knocked me to the ground, and I was near death
By God’s power, I recovered
My friends spoke to the ISIS members, but they didn’t give me injections or any help
That happened during the days I was sentenced to death
I don’t know if my illness came from fear or was a real sickness
When I fell ill, there was a jailer under Abu Seif named Abu Abdul Malik
He was from Tabqa, originally from Aleppo Province
He watched us through the cameras, even Ibrahim al-Fakkash started crying over me
And Ibrahim al-Alkan recited Quran over me, rubbing my body and weeping, thinking I was dying
And Ibrahim al-Ayyoub, nicknamed Shantar, was a simple, impatient man
He stood up, started smashing the door, shouting, “Talal al-Shuweimi is dead!”
Abu Abdul Malik answered him
And said, when he dies
When he dies, let us know so we can take him out,that’s what Abu Abdul Malik said
Praise be to God, Talal al-Shuweimi is still alive by God’s grace
Abu Abdul Malik was later struck by an airstrike on his way to Tabqa
May God have mercy on him,I recited Al-Fatiha for him