But once, we had a jailer who wasn’t just a jailer,he was also an emir in ISIS
In the Mafarq al-Jazra area
They said he was one of the “Kanas” family. I remember only his nickname, I forgot his name, but he was a good man too
In the morning, the emir Abu Saqr from the al-Dabba family came
He was on morning duty as the emir
At night, the shift changed. That man left around sunset, and another took over
He was from Mafarq al-Jazra and was well known
He told me he was married to two women
Sometimes he came and sat with us, but ISIS put him under surveillance because he was kind and sympathetic to prisoners
We paid him 7 million to bring us just a piece of a saw
So we could escape, we told him
We’re 7 prisoners. If you can just bring us a small metal saw blade
Just so we could cut the big lock hanging on the wall
To escape
We told him each of us would give you one million. He said, “ISIS will kill me.” We said, “You’ll escape with us”
Praise God, he was supposed to bring us the saw blade
But the next day, they arrested him
They transferred him. We didn’t know whether he was detained or relocated, but we never saw him again after that