The last time I was imprisoned,as I said earlier,they transferred me from one prison to another
To a prison hidden in a corner
Sadly, that prison was across from my mother’s house
My mother’s name is Zahia
And one of the emirs, named Muhammad al-Abadi
Used to tell me, “Zahia’s son, I saw Zahia walking in the garden”
We were on the second floor, and he said, “I saw your mother”
The man was joking with me
We escaped from the prison during the days of the Euphrates Dam collapse in Raqqa
There were several of us, and that same man was with us
His name was Abu Muhammad al-Abadi
May God bless and reward him
We made a hole in the prison wall
He escaped with us, helped us, and watched the road. There were seven of us, and a car was waiting
We escaped by car, the seven of us