They brought us breakfast in the morning, like cheese and rice
Within reasonable limits
Many people would come in the morning and leave at noon
They were transferred elsewhere or released, we didn’t know about these things
Interviewer: As for medical supplies
Were they available in this place?
It never happened that I experienced this matter
Interviewer: What didn’t you experience? Witness: Treatment
It never happened to me
But I think whoever was suffering was taken to the hospital
If their condition was serious
This is just a holding prison, no need for supplies
Whoever had a serious case was transferred to another prison
There is a prison in Meydan they would transfer them to
And in the church there were also prisoners
It became a prison
We didn’t know what was happening
And sometimes we heard screams from torture and flogging
We didn’t know what was going on because we were behind closed doors
We didn’t know what was happening outside, or see it
Interviewer: When you were here
In this group cell
Did you hear any sounds?
At night we used to hear the sounds of beating and torture
But we didn’t know what they were
One time they took someone from us and he never came back
Whether they released him or killed him, we didn’t know
Interviewer: How did you feel when you heard those sounds?
We felt fear, we didn’t know what our fate would be
Whether we would die, be flogged, or thrown away
Three quarters of those they took were killed
Even our thinking became confused because we didn’t know our fate
Whether they would release us or kill us
We didn’t know
Interviewer: When you were here
Was the prison ever bombed?
No, we just heard the sound of planes
And we were terrified they might bomb the prison at any moment
At night the planes were intense, we could hear them
And it went on like that
Interviewer: Tell us about the prisoners who were with you
How was the relationship between you inside the prison?
As I told you from the start, when they brought us in
We greeted each other, and at prayer time one of us would lead
Each person would tell what he was charged with, smoking or something else
We didn’t know everyone, and one of them could be an informant for them
Pretending to complain to make you speak against them
And you’d be held accountable for what you said
So you’d see each of us by himself
They’d give us a paper to read
Our fate and life were exhausting
Interviewer: Let’s talk about the washrooms
Were cleaning supplies available in the washrooms?
There was only laundry soap
The washrooms were here inside
Interviewer: You mean they were available? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And what about showering?
Did you use to shower?
No, there were only washrooms for laundry
This was a shower and toilet
Interviewer: Were there towels?
No, just two small towels
And there was Zahi soap
Showering and using the toilet were done inside
We didn’t know our fate, whether with the air force or inside
Interviewer: While you were here
Did the washrooms ever break down and overflow?
No, that didn’t happen
Interviewer: What didn’t happen? Witness: The washrooms didn’t get clogged
Interviewer: Let’s go back to the topic of food
Was the food enough?
And did you ask the guards
To increase the amount of food?
We couldn’t ask for anything, whether they fed us or not
And whether we ate or not, we couldn’t ask for anything
And you couldn’t ask any question
We couldn’t ask for anything
Only if the guard came and asked us, then we could speak
And that depended on his mood
Interviewer: You mean you didn’t ask for more food? Witness: No
They brought food in the morning and at noon
And most of the time the food was ready
Interviewer: Was the place clean or did it smell?
It was okay
There were mattresses
And a place for prayer and sitting
They came to us in the morning
We had to pray the prayers on time
The prayers were on time, an imam led us and we stood behind him
The imam stood, and the rest stood behind him to pray
People were here, and there weren’t many
Two would come in, for example, and three would leave, like that