Name: Rayan Riyad Khalil
Born in 1987
I was detained in Ras al-Kour
Three people came in a Hisba vehicle
And they brought us to this place
Interviewer: What was the reason for the detention?
The first detention was because of prayer
And the second detention was because of people and belongings we were taking out of the town
So they focused on me and started monitoring me
The second time they brought me to this place
Interviewer: What is your job?
I worked as a cargo truck driver on the Turkey route
Interviewer: Do you mean a medicine truck?
A passenger car, we would take people and bring them
They used to say this area has Rafida [Shia]
And they brought us in under this pretext
Interviewer: Were you married?
Yes, I was married
Interviewer: How many children do you have? Witness: Three
Interviewer: When did they arrest you, and what were you doing?
And how many people were there when they brought you to this place?
They were three people
They brought us into this place
There was an information desk inside
There was an information desk, and then we went in
Interviewer: While they were bringing you here
Interviewer: Did they insult you or beat you? Witness: No
But I did not know what my fate would be or why they had brought me here