They brought us from the prefabricated room
In the prefabricated room they took the personal belongings
Then they blindfolded us and made us go up
these stairs until we reached this room
There were prisoners in it
Because of smoking, the izar [waist wrap], and other matters
We couldn’t ask them about that because we didn’t know them
If you don’t know someone well, you can’t ask him
This is the room we stayed in
And we slept in it, here were the sinks and toilets
And there were prisoners
Many of them were accused of smoking
Or of another matter, or they were policemen
Or we didn’t know what their charge was
They would bring people in and take others out
We feared one of them might be an informant for them
And that he would lure us into talking, these people were not good
We didn’t know our fate so we were afraid of each other
They would take people and bring them down to the basement
We didn’t dare ask what they were questioned about, or what they’d said to the judge
Here is where people slept, and here were the mattresses
And these are the toilets
These toilets were separate
They were outside the room, but they made this opening in them