This is the judge’s place and this is his room
We were transferred to him from the upper floor at noon
Here there was a group of chairs
On both sides, and here was the table. They made me sit here
He asked me—How is your level in religion?
I told him, I know, but I wasn’t praying. He said—Stand up and call the adhan
I didn’t know it well and didn’t answer him well
So he wrote that I had to learn how to pray
They had a special room where they taught people every Wednesday and Saturday
And also those whose identity papers they had would come too
Interviewer: When they brought you into this room
You must have seen them
Was the judge Arab?
And was his dialect from Mosul or did he speak standard Arabic?
And about how old was the judge? Did you know him before?
And the people who were in this room
Did you know any of them? And about how old were they?
And were their appearances from Mosul or from the villages or from outside Iraq?
The judge was Arab, but not from Mosul
And he had a young son
He wore a gold watch, and it was known that this boy was the judge’s son
When he came, people feared him
Interviewer: How was his son wearing a gold watch when they forbid it?
I don’t know, he would come and everyone knew him
His son was young, thirteen or fourteen
Interviewer: Who was the judge and how old was he?
He was about forty-five years old
Those who sat there were young and old
Here sat four or five
And here too, from their group
Interviewer: Did anything change in this place or did it stay the same?
No, it’s the same place. This opening wasn’t here
And over there was a cupboard with shelves and items
For the people, and this
Interviewer: What was he wearing? Witness: Black clothes and a turban
He had a beard, but it wasn’t long
Interviewer: How was his manner with you?
You know their manner and how they treat people
Interviewer: Did he treat you harshly? Witness: Yes, somewhat
Interviewer: You mean he ordered them to give you lessons?
They gave me mandatory lessons
Interviewer: How many days a week? Witness: Two days
Saturday and Wednesday
There was a room and a teaching board
Interviewer: Was it like a school style?
It was a classroom, and you had to learn and realize that they were fighting
And their goal was to win you over to their side
Interviewer: How many times did you appear before the judge?
Three times