When we entered, there was a prefabricated room
And there was someone at reception
The one who brought us called him and said—We’ve brought this person
The other completed the procedures
Inside, they took our belongings and personal items
There was one person inside
One or two people would come and put a blindfold over my eyes
And they took me away, and I did not know what my fate would be
Interviewer: Were the people who brought you the same ones who had arrested you?
And were they from Mosul, or from outside Iraq?
There was a person named Mahmoud who worked with them
He was from the Makawi family—his cousin, also named Mahmoud, worked as a tailor
He was the driver
And two others were with him—he brought us and handed us over to this person
Interviewer: Do you mean Mahmoud is from the area?
His cousins are from the area, and he is from the Great Mosque area
And he used to visit his cousins
After that he became a driver for the Hisba
Interviewer: How old was he?
Around twenty
Light-skinned
Interviewer: What was his fate? Witness: I don't know
Interviewer: They led you to the room
Interviewer: You did not know where the room was?
I don't know because my eyes were blindfolded—they took me in
Through this corridor, but to where? I don't know