My name is Faraj Salamah from
the town of Tabqa in Raqqa Province
I am 27 years old
Married and have one daughter
At the beginning of 2016
I was working in agriculture in rural Tabqa
Things were relatively stable in the area
On February 19 2016, a Friday
The situation was normal
I was getting ready for Friday prayer
When I was about to leave the bathroom
Preparing to go to the mosque
I heard movement outside the bathroom
Then someone knocked on the door
He told me not to come out
I waited for about half an hour
I noticed armed men
From ISIS inside the house
I heard weapons and wireless devices
It became clear it was a raid
Things were not normal
After half an hour someone ordered me to leave the bathroom
Everyone outside was armed
They ordered me to stand in front of the house
And I found my brothers outside too
Sitting on chairs while ISIS members searched the house
I realized the village was surrounded and being searched
Every now and then an ISIS vehicle arrived
Bringing two or three of my cousins
Then leaving again
We stayed until the afternoon prayer
For nearly three hours or more
Then ISIS members put us in vehicles
The first building we entered was the Islamic Police base
Inside I saw relatives from a nearby village
Some of my brothers had gone to Friday prayers before us
So they followed them to the mosque
And while they were praying, they were all arrested
They put us all together
Every 10 minutes cars arrived
Taking several people away to unknown destinations
The cars kept coming
We were about 30 people or more
All brothers and cousins
Finally, it was our turn
We got in blindfolded, not knowing where we were going
We drove a short distance
I believe still within Tabqa
When we entered, we realized it was the Bourj (Tower) Prison of ISIS
We got out of the vehicle and lined up facing the wall
Beside other blindfolded prisoners I could sense nearby
It was completely silent
They began opening doors and distributing the prisoners
They placed two or three in each
solitary cell because of the overcrowding
I was put in a solitary cell too
With two of my cousins
Next to us were other solitary cells, and opposite were group cells
They started taking prisoners for interrogation
To collect personal information about us
Then returning us
During the first day, no one was taken for interrogation
After 2:30 a.m.
We heard noise as they brought in a large number of prisoners
We could see through the cell door
Watching through the small window, we saw the corridor
We saw they had arrested many young men
Blindfolded in the same way as us
Lined up against the wall in the corridor
Then they started distributing them
They put them with us
It turned out they were our relatives from Jarnieh, rural Tabqa
We recognized each other
It was the first time I had seen them
After two days
They transferred me to another cell
It was not solitary
There were around 10 or 11 people
All of them my relatives
We started asking each other about our family members
I asked about my brothers and father
because I didn’t know where they were
But I could hear their voices from inside the solitary cells
Even though our group cell was far from theirs
Located in a different section outside the solitary area
To reach it, you had to pass through the kitchen
Then another room
Before arriving at the large group cell
One of my relatives told me he had been with my father
And reassured me that he was fine
But we still didn’t know why we had been arrested or for what reason
Every week
They would select two or three people and release them
We were in contact with the group cell next to us
The cell door was confusing in layout
It didn’t open to the hallway but faced a wall
We spoke with them through the electrical outlet
Where one of my brothers and cousins were
I kept in touch with them constantly
I stayed for 27 days
In that group cell
Until only my two cousins and I remained
The rest were released
Without knowing which of my relatives and
brothers were still in the remaining group cells
I was called in for interrogation
To be asked about my brother Ibrahim
Whom I thought had been detained with us
But I hadn’t heard his voice
So I realized they hadn’t arrested him
I answered that I didn’t know and that he was in Tabqa
And that we usually went together to Friday prayers
But I didn’t see him because you arrived before the prayer
And took us away before it started
He took me to the disciplinary cell (solitary cell)
And began asking what weapons I owned
I told him I had no weapons at all
I said the only weapon was the hunting rifle
That you found in the house
He repeated his question, claiming we had buried weapons
Accusing me of belonging to the Free Syrian Army
Because my brother was with the Free Syrian Army
I told him my brother
Is responsible for himself, and we have nothing to do with him
He said, No problem then
And took me to a room
Not a normal room
It was smaller than a solitary cell
They called it the disciplinary cell
About 60 centimeters wide
And about one and a half meters long
I stayed there for four days
They gave us food through the door
And at prayer times, they allowed us out only for ablution
After four days, he brought me back for interrogation
And asked what new information I had this time
I told him I knew nothing
When I entered the disciplinary cell
There was someone next to me
From Safira
He told me, When I arrived here, your father...
Was inside this room
They took him out and put me in his place
Then I began to hear my father’s voice
Because the disciplinary cells were in the same corridor
That contained the solitary and group cells
So I could hear my father’s voice
And two of my brothers
And a cousin of mine, I could hear them clearly
That’s how I knew who remained
in prison and who had been released
Late at night
We would talk to each other
Without ISIS members noticing
Or maybe they noticed and pretended not to
After another four days
He brought me back for interrogation again
The interrogator asked if I had any new statements
I told him I’d already said everything I knew
And I had nothing new
He put me in a solitary cell
I entered the solitary cell
And found a young man from Daraa
He told me
Your brother was with me
Then they moved him to the group cell
After midnight
I would talk with my father. He heard me and I heard him
One of my brothers was with him
And they also had no charges brought against them
Another brother was far away in a solitary cell
I couldn’t communicate with him well
But we could hear each other’s voices
And knew we were in the same prison
My cousins were on my right and left
On the right and on the left
After three or four days
They took one of my cousins out of the solitary cells
That were beside me
And moved him to another solitary cell
Then they brought in two women
About 25 to 26 years old
In the prison, we communicated
Through the water taps
We spoke and heard each other, though not clearly
ISIS had arrested them
For walking repeatedly near the base
Accusing them of filming
And sending footage to the Global Coalition Against ISIS
They were taken for interrogation
After midnight
We could hear the voices of the women and the torture
We endured and prayed, saying, God is sufficient
for us, and He is the best disposer of affairs
Then they would be brought back
So exhausted they couldn’t even talk to us
We couldn’t communicate with them properly
After a while
They took out my cousin who was on the left side
And moved him to another solitary cell
Then they brought women again
And placed them in the solitary cell next to mine
So I ended up between two solitary cells holding women
With the women detained the last time
There were young children with them
They took a child from one of the women
For about a week
We couldn’t sleep or eat
Because of the woman’s cries over her baby’s separation
Who I think was an infant
Less than one year old
I used to see, in the solitary cell or the group cell
The names of prisoners, their arrest dates, and reasons
I found the name of a young man I knew from the town of Tabqa
He had written his name and his case on the wall
His name was Muhannad Raja al-Harmoush
They placed him in front of the solitary cell door
Around one o’clock after midnight
I saw them through the window asking his name
He answered, Muhannad Raja al-Harmoush,
so I recognized him immediately
They asked him, What’s your case about?
He said, Mocking ISIS
The interrogator asked, Why do you mock?
He replied, explaining that what he
said was only a joke, nothing more
The interrogator said, No problem with that
Muhannad stayed standing for five minutes
They shackled his hands and blindfolded him
Then took him elsewhere
Through the ventilation opening of the solitary cells
Overlooking the car garage
We could hear clearly
They put him in the van
Carrying with them tools for digging graves
I concluded they were going to kill and bury him
After about two hours
The members came back with their tools but without Muhannad
They were laughing as if returning from an amusing trip
We came to see that as normal
Because it happened regularly from time to time
There were prisoners from the town of Mansoura
They were taken daily for interrogation and torture
Then returned, and that continued for a while
I saw their names on the wall
And learned about their cases
But I didn’t meet any of them because they were far from me
I would hear the sounds of torture when they were taken
But I didn’t know who they were
Once, they took them out before the evening prayer
They took them out one by one
Asking what belongings they had
And if they wanted to send any message to their families
Because the next day
Was the day their sentences would be carried out
Which was execution
And crucifixion in the town of Mansoura
They were sentenced on charges of highway robbery
They were to face the had al-hiraba [punishment for banditry]
Which is execution and crucifixion
They didn’t sleep all night, praying to God
They were taken the next morning
At evening prayer time
ISIS members brought us a newspaper they had issued
It said they had carried out executions
Of eight people
We stayed in shock for several days over what had happened
There was a young man named
Ahmad al-Lajji from Raqqa
And another named Faisal al-Zaher
And another named Ahmad al-Hamoud
He was actually a child, not a young man
They were in solitary cells and we hadn’t spoken before
I didn’t even know they were in prison
They took them and lined them up in front of the group cell
In orange uniforms, with shaved heads and beards
It happened on a Friday morning
They were asked about their charges
All of them were accused of collaborating with the Global Coalition
One of them asked to write a will
So his debts could be paid, but they refused
Then they took them away
I never saw them, only heard their voices
During torture sessions
I didn’t even know their names
Until they were called by name and I saw them then
I used to see their writings on the walls
But I thought they had already been released
Two days later
A young man told me he had seen them killed in Tabqa
Stabbed to death
Then shot afterward
I told him I had seen them only once
Then they brought their magazine
It said they had executed agents of the Coalition
Ahmad al-Lajji, Faisal al-Zaher, and Ahmad al-Hamoud
Our spirits would sink again every
time they took prisoners for execution
There was no taste for sleep or food
When we thought of those killed, their families, and their children
It became normal every two or three days
They would take women from the solitary cells
At night, carrying with them grave-digging tools
The vehicles would leave and come back
We saw the members smiling
As if they hadn’t just killed someone
And it kept happening
Every few days they would take one of the women
There were five or six of them, maybe more
After exactly 16 days
My brother was released
Along with the young man who was with me
Who was from Daraa Province
And who used to say that he was with ISIS
He claimed he was one of ISIS’s security members in Daraa
And was detained after being suspected upon arriving in Raqqa
I had nothing personal to talk with him about
The conversations we had were routine and ordinary
They brought in his place a young man from Tabqa
Who stayed with me for three days
I asked him about the situation outside
He had heard about my detention with my family
I asked him who among my relatives
was still imprisoned or had been released
He told me who had been released from prison
According to him, it was me and two of my brothers
My father, and two of my cousins who remained
I could hear the voices of the others in prison
But those whose voices disappeared
I was very worried about what had happened to them
He assured me that all those who had been released were fine
They placed my brother in the prison corridor before sunset
During the time when we usually received dinner
My brother started talking to me and asking how I was
Taking advantage of the absence of anyone in the corridor
He told me he was going to be released
Since it was customary to release prisoners
Every Monday and Thursday
But my brother’s release was on a Wednesday
I asked him what he had told them, and he reassured me
Telling me not to worry, that everything
was fine and he would be out soon
My brother was four years older than me
Less than a week later, the interrogator came back to me
He asked, What’s new? Do you need anything?
I said, Nothing new, but I want to see my father, just once
He said, You’ll see him today
So I went to see my father, and through the door
I spoke to him and asked how he was
I reassured him that I was fine
And lifted his spirits a bit so he wouldn’t worry too much about me
Then I returned to my cell after five minutes
About a week later
It seemed to me that a senior ISIS official came to the prison
Because they started cleaning and tidying the facilities
The official made a tour around us
Asking, What’s your name? What’s your case?
He asked me, Do you need anything?
I explained my situation and asked about my fate
He said, Don’t worry, everything’s fine
Then he repeated, Do you want anything else?
I said, I want to see my father
He asked, When was the last time you saw him?
I answered, Once, and for five minutes
He said, Alright
Then placed me with my father in the
same group cell, where I found him alone
The official continued his tour
And we could hear the voices of my brother and cousins
As he asked them about their needs
When I saw my father, he hugged
me and started crying. He was fasting
It was Thursday, and we broke our fast together
We didn’t sleep all night
Because of our long conversation
and how much we missed each other
We tried to lift our spirits and comfort each other
We talked about the charges brought against us
My father’s charge was that he once said
That if a military operation began against ISIS in the area
He would be ready to arm 500 fighters
Which was, of course, a fabricated and false accusation
They demanded he bring 500 rifles
My father, in turn, demanded
That they bring witnesses to these accusations
They told him, Your witness is here
He said, Bring him, I have no problem
After the interrogation ended
One of the prisoners told him the name of the witness
And informed my father about it
My father told his fellow prisoners
About the accusation against him
And that there was a witness
He repeatedly asked for the witness
to be brought, but they never did
When one of my father’s cellmates was released
He told the story to the supposed witness
Who later came to the prison
And confirmed that he had not witnessed what my father said
That the entire accusation had no basis in truth
But ISIS members expelled him
Telling him that it was none of his concern
It became clear that the accusation was fabricated
And my father’s imprisonment was purely arbitrary
They took me for interrogation
And asked, Do you need anything?
I felt then that they wanted to release me
I said, No, nothing
He said, The method of interrogation will completely change
If you have something to say
Now is the time before they use another method
I told him I had nothing to add
He was expecting me to talk about weapons and such
But I assured him I had no weapons
And that I wasn’t the person they were looking for
He was the one responsible for what you accuse me of
And he had been imprisoned by you before
And it was you who released him
So you are responsible for this mistake, not me
He said, Alright, and sent me back
After 10 minutes, I heard the sound of torture
It was one of my cousins, I recognized his voice well
They kept torturing him for two hours
Then they summoned me for interrogation
I realized that my turn for torture had come
He repeated his question, Anything
new? I repeated my answer, Nothing
They started torturing me immediately, for half an hour or an hour
They kept torturing me until I lost consciousness
Then they splashed me with water to wake me up
I could hear them, but I couldn’t walk
So they sent me back to the solitary cell
I heard them call for Abdullah Salamah
Both my brother and my cousin shared
The same name
He asked him, Are you Abu Islam? He answered, No
So I knew they wanted my cousin
They took him and repeated the torture on him
He couldn’t bear it because he had asthma
He fainted after half an hour or less
They splashed him with water. I
heard his voice and felt reassured
Because I had been so worried about him
Then they took my brother for interrogation
I started waiting to hear the sounds of torture
Thinking they would do to him what they had done to us
But they didn’t torture him
Even though he stayed there for three or four hours
They sent him back without torturing him
Torture became a daily routine for us
We got used to it
Whenever we heard someone being tortured
We knew our turn was coming
Once, I was asleep one afternoon
I woke up to the sound of one of my cousins being tortured
I knew things had become serious
He was tortured for three hours
Until he lost consciousness and they brought him back
I heard the interrogator say to him
Bring me Faraj Salamah
He interrogated me for a short while
I was waiting for the torture to start
Expecting any blow
Because I was blindfolded and handcuffed
Then the interrogator ordered that I be
tortured by suspension [shabeh]
So I remained suspended
I realized that my cousin hadn’t been tortured again
Because of his illness and the interrogator’s fear of the consequences
Since my cousin’s condition was severe
He postponed his torture session
As for me, I remained suspended for nine hours
Then they sent me back
I was reassured about my cousin after midnight
When I called out to him
He answered that he was fine, praise God
Since then, they slightly changed their approach
They would take us for interrogation from time to time
But they stopped torturing us, or postponed it
At exactly 12 midnight
We heard a sound in the wall near the window
It seemed like an escape attempt was happening
We stayed anxious because we
didn’t know what was happening outside
When I was in the far group cell
I knew there was a place easy to escape from
The prison was basically a basement
With a small breathing window above
Completely reinforced with iron protection
But that group cell
Had an external staircase
Which they had recently sealed off
Using concrete blocks
It was sealed tightly
But if someone thought and worked carefully
It was possible to escape from there
I noticed a solid iron object outside
When my cousin and I were preparing to escape
During a time when my relatives were being released regularly
We thought our turn for release was coming soon
But we decided to escape
Unfortunately, they transferred us to a different cell
When I was with my father, I told him
That we had planned to escape from that group cell
My father was with a young man named Ahmad Seno
And another young man named Hamad
I had spoken to them about my plan to escape through that cell
It seems they remembered my words exactly
Saying, This is the cell he talked about
And that this was where the
external door had recently been sealed
They also saw the same iron piece
I had told them about, so they decided to escape
I realized that they were escaping
The next morning after the escape
There was great chaos inside the prison
They distributed special prison uniforms to us
They took all our civilian clothes
They also gave us numbers
And searched for any iron objects
They installed surveillance cameras in the prison
Then one of them came and asked me, What’s your name?
I answered, Faraj Salamah
He asked, Is your father’s name Khalaf?
I said yes, and he told me that
my father had escaped from prison
I had suspected that all that noise was because of an escape
And that the escape had happened from our same group cell
But I didn’t know who they were at the time
Yet when my father’s voice grew distant, I thought
He must have been in that faraway cell
I pretended to the one asking that I
was upset about my father’s escape
Because no charges had been
proven against us for three months
My father had endured prison and
nothing had been proven against him
So it didn’t make sense for him to escape and leave us behind
Inside, I prayed to God to help him succeed
He told me they would catch him wherever he was
Whether in Turkey or in Germany
I told him I wasn’t responsible for his escape
I was in one group cell and he was in another
He said, You’re not to blame
What we want is for you to call your uncles
And tell them you’ll be killed if your father doesn’t return
I told him I didn’t know their numbers
But he kept insisting
So I said, As you wish, but bring me one of their numbers
A day and then two passed without him coming back
The Tower was made up of 12 floors
Destroyed from the outside by Assad regime airstrikes
They had built a prison in the basement
With multiple solitary cells
And another section they called the disciplinary cells
Which was itself an inseparable part of the solitary area
There was another section for group cells
A corridor separated the group cells from the solitary ones
And there was a section designated for the disciplinary cells
In addition to faraway, unknown cells
There were many people inside
I’ll now list the ones I remember
Among my relatives were my brothers
Abdullah, Abdul Hakim, and Muhammad al-Salamah
And my father, Khalaf al-Salamah
And my cousin Abdullah Hassan al-Salamah
And my other cousins
Abdul Musleh Hassan al-Ibrahim
And Hammouda and Ahmad Hassan al-Ibrahim
And Abdul Hakim Hassan al-Ibrahim
Aziz Hassan al-Ibrahim
Ahmad Hassan—I think I already mentioned him
And Faraj Hassan al-Ibrahim
And their sons, Hassan Ibrahim al-Hassan
Faraj Ibrahim al-Hassan
And Muhammad Faraj al-Hassan
And Muhammad Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi, my cousin
And Kamal Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi
From Jarniya, there was Walid al-Haji
And Muasstam and Hamada al-Haji
There was also a young man named
Anis, a relative of ours from the area
As well as others who had been imprisoned before us
Including Muhannad al-Raji
Ahmad al-Laji and Faisal al-Zahir
Ahmad al-Hamoud
And people from Raqqa Prison, among them Ahmad Sinu
And a young man named Hamad
And young men from the al-Hutayl clan in Mansoura
I don’t remember their names
Because their names were similar to ours
And I started getting confused from so many names
There were also friends of mine in prison
Harith Haj Abdul Sheikh
And Faisal Saad Rajoub from Homs
And Khaled al-Harbi, a young man from Tabqa
And a young man from Rural Aleppo named Alaa
But he was killed in prison
There were also foreign prisoners
Affiliated with ISIS, but they never told me their names
They all went by noms de guerre like Abu so-and-so
Among them were Saudis
And a Lebanese-born man with German citizenship
He had been wounded by a gunshot from one of his comrades
And had metal rods in his body
There were six foreign prisoners in total
Because they were against the idea of establishing the Islamic State
They had criticized it, so they were imprisoned
The general official was called Abu Luqman
His name was Ibrahim al-Shawakh
From the town of al-Sahl in Raqqa Province
The internal official
Was Mahmoud al-Ibrahim al-Dakhil
His mother’s name was Shamsa
From the town of Mansoura in the Tabqa countryside
He was originally from the al-Bou Masra clan
He was responsible for interrogations
in Tabqa and its countryside
The official in charge of the jailers was a Saudi man
Named Abu Nayef
He was responsible for the jailers and the prison’s cleanliness
The jailers were from the same area, from Tabqa
One was called Abu Abdullah
Another was called Abu Zaid
And Abdul Muin
And a young man nicknamed Abu Abdu
Two of them were present, and two were absent
They took shifts for irregular periods, from days up to a week
At first, the approach was calm and smooth
The interrogator found nothing he was looking for
Then he began torturing by beating
All over the body with a hose or a stick
Even if our bodies broke under torture
Because more than one prisoner suffered fractures as a result
He kept beating continuously
As long as the person did not lose consciousness
If he found no result, he tried
the suspension [shabeh] method
He lifted the person using the balingo
[hoist] by his hands
So that his feet did not touch the ground
Which forced the prisoner
To confess to whatever the interrogator wanted
Even if the person had done nothing against them at all
We said there was beating and suspension
As for the women, we heard their screams
Without knowing their method of torture
Without hearing the sounds of beating
Or knowing their style of interrogation with women
But interrogations always took place after midnight
And lasted for around three hours
Torture included everyone without exception
And it was done according to the charges brought against them
And based on confessions
Anyone with serious charges
Was tortured by all means until he spoke
They continued even if it led to death
Once, they tortured a man
Before I was detained
His name was Ammar, from al-Baasi village
They kept torturing him until he died
Without extracting any confession
So I realized they had no problem with a prisoner dying
Depending on his case
No problem
Psychological torture was exhausting and constant
We were kept in the disciplinary cell
They told us, You will not live long. Repent to your Lord
And said things like, Your days are
numbered. Don’t think of getting out at all
There were also people
Among the prisoners whom they dressed in yellow clothes
Their execution outfit
They shaved their hair and beards
Reenacting the steps of execution preparation
Assuming he was not Muslim and they had the right to kill him
Which was sometimes more terrifying
and painful than physical torture
They gave us books
Religious books and the Quran
And newspapers issued by them
We looked for outside news
Though we knew it was not reliable
The news was scarce and limited to their achievements
So we had to read the books
Willingly, not by force
We also communicated with other group cells
Through the electricity and water pipes
To ask newly arrived prisoners about outside news
Relations were good because we were ignorant of our fate
If death came, we were all in the same boat
We had a small glimmer of hope
That we might see each other outside prison
Our relationship was good, even more than brotherly
We refused when they offered to show us their ISIS videos
Because all their productions showed the killing of prisoners
As well as battles
All scenes of killing and violence
We had absolutely no need to see anything like that
There was a routine every Monday and Thursday
Fasting was obligatory
They prepared a meal
Of suhur [pre-dawn meal] on Wednesday night
So we could fast on Thursday
On regular days, there were two
meals, one in the morning and another
At or just before sunset prayer
They sometimes left some food
So if we got hungry at night, we could eat
Every Friday morning
We personally cleaned the group cell
And the corridor between the group cells and the solitary cells
It was mandatory for the prisoners
That two or three of them go out to clean the group cell
They offered to cancel half of my sentence
In exchange for me handing over my
brother who had not been detained
He would come in, and I would be released instead
I claimed that our relationship was normal
And I did not expect him to come for me
If he was outside the area
And that it was their mistake
Because they had already detained
him earlier on multiple charges
And still could not get anything from him
So I was not obliged to do that
When I was released, they tried to bargain with me to join them
At the same time a Syrian regime convoy arrived
Along with the Russians
On their way to Tabqa city
They tried to convince me to take a weapon from them
And fight alongside them if we shared the same cause
As proof of my loyalty to them
Interviewer: And how did they react to your refusal?
Of course, I refused in an indirect way
By saying that I was the youngest in my family
And that my mother would never abandon me after prison
And I had no idea how her health was
So how could I get out and take up arms immediately
After I completed four months in prison
The interrogator came to me and opened the shutter
He said, Come here! What’s your name? I answered him
He asked, How long have you been here? I said, Four months
He said, Fine, you’ve been here too long, we’ll release you
And you must tell your father to come back
Because by escaping, he proved the charge against himself
I said, Since you’re sure he’s innocent
Why did he stay three months until he had to escape
Why didn’t you release him then?
He said, The point is to tell him to
come back, there’s nothing against him
Better than traveling to Azaz, Qamishli, or Turkey
I said, God willing
So I could get out of prison afterward
Before leaving, I asked about my brother, and he said
He must pay 10,000 dollars to be released
Plus another 10,000 dollars for my cousin
The interrogator told me that once they had received the money
They would release them immediately
So I secured the amount for my brother that night
And I went to them after Maghrib prayer
Right after I had secured the money
But they didn’t receive me and told me to come back the next day
Because there were no visits at night
So I came back the next day
I handed over the money, and my brother was released
Some time after my release
ISIS members returned to search for my father
Every day or two, they came back
They knew my brother had fled to Qamishli
But my father hadn’t left the area
And ISIS members knew that
So they came regularly asking about him
And about my brother too
They also used to summon my other brother
To ask him about my father and my brother
When they would come, and
which relatives we were in touch with
They pressured us heavily
Trying to make us leave the area
They clearly didn’t want us there at all
They repeated the same interrogations with my nephew too
They also took our ID cards
From me, my brothers, and my cousins, and never returned them
But they did give us back our mobile phones
They said it was forbidden to return IDs
We followed up with them about the IDs
Until they started threatening to imprison us if we asked again
They told us to forget about them
Then I realized they might use the IDs to escape someday
So we stopped asking about them altogether
They issued us identification cards instead
After we had attended a sharia course
To receive the ID card that became mandatory
We started showing them at checkpoints
Unable to move without them
All the prisoners’ stories were sad
Especially those whose children had been killed
Or who had left orphans behind
There was a young man named Abu Madian
From the town of Mansoura
We used to notice his written memories of his son
In every solitary or group cell we passed through
He would express his feelings and longing
Madian, my dear, I never got enough of you, mourning his son
As if he knew he would never see him again
He was the one who made us feel the saddest
Even though I never met him
I’m still affected by him to this day
Another young man was named Faisal Saad Rajoub
From Homs
He stayed under the siege of Homs even after his family left
Resisting there for about four years
He left through the United Nations
He tried every way to reach his mother but failed
So he was forced to join ISIS
He tried to go to Turkey to see her but couldn’t
During his torture
He kept screaming for his mother
Begging her forgiveness because he couldn’t see her
Or reach her
While she was suffering from heart disease
He was deeply affected by his mother’s condition
His mind was preoccupied
Thinking how his mother would
take the news of his death later
Since my release, I’ve been trying
To escape the area completely
I was in a very difficult mental state
I remained affected until ISIS left the area
Of course, I didn’t wait for them
I was the one who fled
To the town of al-Bab in Rural Aleppo
Because I couldn’t bear staying
Even though I stayed away from the
city and avoided any contact with them
Because of my terrible psychological state
Once, I went down to my city
And saw a man killed and crucified
He was wearing an orange jumpsuit and was an elderly man
Not younger than 50 years old
That sight completely destroyed me
And pushed me to leave the area for good
I left by God’s grace
And I didn’t return until after they had left
When the Syrian Democratic Forces took control of the area