My name is Faraj Salamah from
the town of Tabqa in Raqqa Province
I am 27 years old
Married and have one daughter
At the beginning of 2016
I was working in agriculture in rural Tabqa
Things were relatively stable in the area
On February 19 2016, a Friday
The situation was normal
I was getting ready for Friday prayer
When I was about to leave the bathroom
Preparing to go to the mosque
I heard movement outside the bathroom
Then someone knocked on the door
He told me not to come out
I waited for about half an hour
I noticed armed men
From ISIS inside the house
I heard weapons and wireless devices
It became clear it was a raid
Things were not normal
After half an hour someone ordered me to leave the bathroom
Everyone outside was armed
They ordered me to stand in front of the house
And I found my brothers outside too
Sitting on chairs while ISIS members searched the house
I realized the village was surrounded and being searched
Every now and then an ISIS vehicle arrived
Bringing two or three of my cousins
Then leaving again
We stayed until the afternoon prayer
For nearly three hours or more
Then ISIS members put us in vehicles
The first building we entered was the Islamic Police base
Inside I saw relatives from a nearby village
Some of my brothers had gone to Friday prayers before us
So they followed them to the mosque
And while they were praying, they were all arrested
They put us all together
Every 10 minutes cars arrived
Taking several people away to unknown destinations
The cars kept coming
We were about 30 people or more
All brothers and cousins
Finally, it was our turn
We got in blindfolded, not knowing where we were going
We drove a short distance
I believe still within Tabqa
When we entered, we realized it was the Bourj (Tower) Prison of ISIS
We got out of the vehicle and lined up facing the wall
Beside other blindfolded prisoners I could sense nearby
It was completely silent
They began opening doors and distributing the prisoners
They placed two or three in each
solitary cell because of the overcrowding
I was put in a solitary cell too
With two of my cousins
Next to us were other solitary cells, and opposite were group cells
They started taking prisoners for interrogation
To collect personal information about us
Then returning us
During the first day, no one was taken for interrogation
After 2:30 a.m.
We heard noise as they brought in a large number of prisoners
We could see through the cell door
Watching through the small window, we saw the corridor
We saw they had arrested many young men
Blindfolded in the same way as us
Lined up against the wall in the corridor
Then they started distributing them
They put them with us
It turned out they were our relatives from Jarnieh, rural Tabqa
We recognized each other
It was the first time I had seen them
After two days
They transferred me to another cell
It was not solitary
There were around 10 or 11 people
All of them my relatives
We started asking each other about our family members
I asked about my brothers and father
because I didn’t know where they were
But I could hear their voices from inside the solitary cells
Even though our group cell was far from theirs
Located in a different section outside the solitary area
To reach it, you had to pass through the kitchen
Then another room
Before arriving at the large group cell
One of my relatives told me he had been with my father
And reassured me that he was fine
But we still didn’t know why we had been arrested or for what reason
Every week
They would select two or three people and release them
We were in contact with the group cell next to us
The cell door was confusing in layout
It didn’t open to the hallway but faced a wall
We spoke with them through the electrical outlet
Where one of my brothers and cousins were
I kept in touch with them constantly
I stayed for 27 days
In that group cell
Until only my two cousins and I remained
The rest were released
Without knowing which of my relatives and
brothers were still in the remaining group cells
I was called in for interrogation
To be asked about my brother Ibrahim
Whom I thought had been detained with us
But I hadn’t heard his voice
So I realized they hadn’t arrested him
I answered that I didn’t know and that he was in Tabqa
And that we usually went together to Friday prayers
But I didn’t see him because you arrived before the prayer
And took us away before it started
He took me to the disciplinary cell (solitary cell)
And began asking what weapons I owned
I told him I had no weapons at all
I said the only weapon was the hunting rifle
That you found in the house
He repeated his question, claiming we had buried weapons
Accusing me of belonging to the Free Syrian Army
Because my brother was with the Free Syrian Army
I told him my brother
Is responsible for himself, and we have nothing to do with him
He said, No problem then
And took me to a room
Not a normal room
It was smaller than a solitary cell
They called it the disciplinary cell
About 60 centimeters wide
And about one and a half meters long
I stayed there for four days
They gave us food through the door
And at prayer times, they allowed us out only for ablution
After four days, he brought me back for interrogation
And asked what new information I had this time
I told him I knew nothing
When I entered the disciplinary cell
There was someone next to me
From Safira
He told me, When I arrived here, your father...
Was inside this room
They took him out and put me in his place
Then I began to hear my father’s voice
Because the disciplinary cells were in the same corridor
That contained the solitary and group cells
So I could hear my father’s voice
And two of my brothers
And a cousin of mine, I could hear them clearly
That’s how I knew who remained
in prison and who had been released
Late at night
We would talk to each other
Without ISIS members noticing
Or maybe they noticed and pretended not to
After another four days
He brought me back for interrogation again
The interrogator asked if I had any new statements
I told him I’d already said everything I knew
And I had nothing new
He put me in a solitary cell
I entered the solitary cell
And found a young man from Daraa
He told me
Your brother was with me
Then they moved him to the group cell
After midnight
I would talk with my father. He heard me and I heard him
One of my brothers was with him
And they also had no charges brought against them
Another brother was far away in a solitary cell
I couldn’t communicate with him well
But we could hear each other’s voices
And knew we were in the same prison
My cousins were on my right and left
On the right and on the left
After three or four days
They took one of my cousins out of the solitary cells
That were beside me
And moved him to another solitary cell
Then they brought in two women
About 25 to 26 years old
In the prison, we communicated
Through the water taps
We spoke and heard each other, though not clearly
ISIS had arrested them
For walking repeatedly near the base
Accusing them of filming
And sending footage to the Global Coalition Against ISIS
They were taken for interrogation
After midnight
We could hear the voices of the women and the torture
We endured and prayed, saying, God is sufficient
for us, and He is the best disposer of affairs
Then they would be brought back
So exhausted they couldn’t even talk to us
We couldn’t communicate with them properly
After a while
They took out my cousin who was on the left side
And moved him to another solitary cell
Then they brought women again
And placed them in the solitary cell next to mine
So I ended up between two solitary cells holding women
With the women detained the last time
There were young children with them
They took a child from one of the women
For about a week
We couldn’t sleep or eat
Because of the woman’s cries over her baby’s separation
Who I think was an infant
Less than one year old