They gave us books
Religious books and the Quran
And newspapers issued by them
We looked for outside news
Though we knew it was not reliable
The news was scarce and limited to their achievements
So we had to read the books
Willingly, not by force
We also communicated with other group cells
Through the electricity and water pipes
To ask newly arrived prisoners about outside news
Relations were good because we were ignorant of our fate
If death came, we were all in the same boat
We had a small glimmer of hope
That we might see each other outside prison
Our relationship was good, even more than brotherly
We refused when they offered to show us their ISIS videos
Because all their productions showed the killing of prisoners
As well as battles
All scenes of killing and violence
We had absolutely no need to see anything like that
There was a routine every Monday and Thursday
Fasting was obligatory
They prepared a meal
Of suhur [pre-dawn meal] on Wednesday night
So we could fast on Thursday
On regular days, there were two
meals, one in the morning and another
At or just before sunset prayer
They sometimes left some food
So if we got hungry at night, we could eat
Every Friday morning
We personally cleaned the group cell
And the corridor between the group cells and the solitary cells
It was mandatory for the prisoners
That two or three of them go out to clean the group cell