All the prisoners’ stories were sad
Especially those whose children had been killed
Or who had left orphans behind
There was a young man named Abu Madian
From the town of Mansoura
We used to notice his written memories of his son
In every solitary or group cell we passed through
He would express his feelings and longing
Madian, my dear, I never got enough of you, mourning his son
As if he knew he would never see him again
He was the one who made us feel the saddest
Even though I never met him
I’m still affected by him to this day
Another young man was named Faisal Saad Rajoub
From Homs
He stayed under the siege of Homs even after his family left
Resisting there for about four years
He left through the United Nations
He tried every way to reach his mother but failed
So he was forced to join ISIS
He tried to go to Turkey to see her but couldn’t
During his torture
He kept screaming for his mother
Begging her forgiveness because he couldn’t see her
Or reach her
While she was suffering from heart disease
He was deeply affected by his mother’s condition
His mind was preoccupied
Thinking how his mother would
take the news of his death later