They took me for interrogation
And asked, Do you need anything?
I felt then that they wanted to release me
I said, No, nothing
He said, The method of interrogation will completely change
If you have something to say
Now is the time before they use another method
I told him I had nothing to add
He was expecting me to talk about weapons and such
But I assured him I had no weapons
And that I wasn’t the person they were looking for
He was the one responsible for what you accuse me of
And he had been imprisoned by you before
And it was you who released him
So you are responsible for this mistake, not me
He said, Alright, and sent me back
After 10 minutes, I heard the sound of torture
It was one of my cousins, I recognized his voice well
They kept torturing him for two hours
Then they summoned me for interrogation
I realized that my turn for torture had come
He repeated his question, Anything
new? I repeated my answer, Nothing
They started torturing me immediately, for half an hour or an hour
They kept torturing me until I lost consciousness
Then they splashed me with water to wake me up
I could hear them, but I couldn’t walk
So they sent me back to the solitary cell
I heard them call for Abdullah Salamah
Both my brother and my cousin shared
The same name
He asked him, Are you Abu Islam? He answered, No
So I knew they wanted my cousin
They took him and repeated the torture on him
He couldn’t bear it because he had asthma
He fainted after half an hour or less
They splashed him with water. I
heard his voice and felt reassured
Because I had been so worried about him
Then they took my brother for interrogation
I started waiting to hear the sounds of torture
Thinking they would do to him what they had done to us
But they didn’t torture him
Even though he stayed there for three or four hours
They sent him back without torturing him
Torture became a daily routine for us
We got used to it
Whenever we heard someone being tortured
We knew our turn was coming
Once, I was asleep one afternoon
I woke up to the sound of one of my cousins being tortured
I knew things had become serious
He was tortured for three hours
Until he lost consciousness and they brought him back
I heard the interrogator say to him
Bring me Faraj Salamah
He interrogated me for a short while
I was waiting for the torture to start
Expecting any blow
Because I was blindfolded and handcuffed
Then the interrogator ordered that I be
tortured by shabeh [suspension from the limbs]
So I remained suspended
I realized that my cousin hadn’t been tortured again
Because of his illness and the interrogator’s fear of the consequences
Since my cousin’s condition was severe
He postponed his torture session
As for me, I remained suspended for nine hours
Then they sent me back
I was reassured about my cousin after midnight
When I called out to him
He answered that he was fine, praise God
Since then, they slightly changed their approach
They would take us for interrogation from time to time
But they stopped torturing us, or postponed it