The general official was called Abu Luqman
His name was Ibrahim al-Shawakh
From the town of al-Sahl in Raqqa Province
The internal official
Was Mahmoud al-Ibrahim al-Dakhil
His mother’s name was Shamsa
From the town of Mansoura in the Tabqa countryside
He was originally from the al-Bou Masra clan
He was responsible for interrogations
in Tabqa and its countryside
The official in charge of the jailers was a Saudi man
Named Abu Nayef
He was responsible for the jailers and the prison’s cleanliness
The jailers were from the same area, from Tabqa
One was called Abu Abdullah
Another was called Abu Zaid
And Abdul Muin
And a young man nicknamed Abu Abdu
Two of them were present, and two were absent
They took shifts for irregular periods, from days up to a week