Some time after my release
ISIS members returned to search for my father
Every day or two, they came back
They knew my brother had fled to Qamishli
But my father hadn’t left the area
And ISIS members knew that
So they came regularly asking about him
And about my brother too
They also used to summon my other brother
To ask him about my father and my brother
When they would come, and
which relatives we were in touch with
They pressured us heavily
Trying to make us leave the area
They clearly didn’t want us there at all
They repeated the same interrogations with my nephew too
They also took our ID cards
From me, my brothers, and my cousins, and never returned them
But they did give us back our mobile phones
They said it was forbidden to return IDs
We followed up with them about the IDs
Until they started threatening to imprison us if we asked again
They told us to forget about them
Then I realized they might use the IDs to escape someday
So we stopped asking about them altogether
They issued us identification cards instead
After we had attended a sharia course
To receive the ID card that became mandatory
We started showing them at checkpoints
Unable to move without them