After I completed four months in prison
The interrogator came to me and opened the shutter
He said, Come here! What’s your name? I answered him
He asked, How long have you been here? I said, Four months
He said, Fine, you’ve been here too long, we’ll release you
And you must tell your father to come back
Because by escaping, he proved the charge against himself
I said, Since you’re sure he’s innocent
Why did he stay three months until he had to escape
Why didn’t you release him then?
He said, The point is to tell him to
come back, there’s nothing against him
Better than traveling to Azaz, Qamishli, or Turkey
I said, God willing
So I could get out of prison afterward
Before leaving, I asked about my brother, and he said
He must pay 10,000 dollars to be released
Plus another 10,000 dollars for my cousin
The interrogator told me that once they had received the money
They would release them immediately
So I secured the amount for my brother that night
And I went to them after Maghrib prayer
Right after I had secured the money
But they didn’t receive me and told me to come back the next day
Because there were no visits at night
So I came back the next day
I handed over the money, and my brother was released