At exactly 12 midnight
We heard a sound in the wall near the window
It seemed like an escape attempt was happening
We stayed anxious because we
didn’t know what was happening outside
When I was in the far group cell
I knew there was a place easy to escape from
The prison was basically a basement
With a small breathing window above
Completely reinforced with iron protection
But that group cell
Had an external staircase
Which they had recently sealed off
Using concrete blocks
It was sealed tightly
But if someone thought and worked carefully
It was possible to escape from there
I noticed a solid iron object outside
When my cousin and I were preparing to escape
During a time when my relatives were being released regularly
We thought our turn for release was coming soon
But we decided to escape
Unfortunately, they transferred us to a different cell
When I was with my father, I told him
That we had planned to escape from that group cell
My father was with a young man named Ahmad Seno
And another young man named Hamad
I had spoken to them about my plan to escape through that cell
It seems they remembered my words exactly
Saying, This is the cell he talked about
And that this was where the
external door had recently been sealed
They also saw the same iron piece
I had told them about, so they decided to escape
I realized that they were escaping
The next morning after the escape
There was great chaos inside the prison
They distributed special prison uniforms to us
They took all our civilian clothes
They also gave us numbers
And searched for any iron objects
They installed surveillance cameras in the prison
Then one of them came and asked me, What’s your name?
I answered, Faraj Salamah
He asked, Is your father’s name Khalaf?
I said yes, and he told me that
my father had escaped from prison
I had suspected that all that noise was because of an escape
And that the escape had happened from our same group cell
But I didn’t know who they were at the time
Yet when my father’s voice grew distant, I thought
He must have been in that faraway cell
I pretended to the one asking that I
was upset about my father’s escape
Because no charges had been
proven against us for three months
My father had endured prison and
nothing had been proven against him
So it didn’t make sense for him to escape and leave us behind
Inside, I prayed to God to help him succeed
He told me they would catch him wherever he was
Whether in Turkey or in Germany
I told him I wasn’t responsible for his escape
I was in one group cell and he was in another
He said, You’re not to blame
What we want is for you to call your uncles
And tell them you’ll be killed if your father doesn’t return
I told him I didn’t know their numbers
But he kept insisting
So I said, As you wish, but bring me one of their numbers
A day and then two passed without him coming back