Since my release, I’ve been trying
To escape the area completely
I was in a very difficult mental state
I remained affected until ISIS left the area
Of course, I didn’t wait for them
I was the one who fled
To the town of al-Bab in Rural Aleppo
Because I couldn’t bear staying
Even though I stayed away from the
city and avoided any contact with them
Because of my terrible psychological state
Once, I went down to my city
And saw a man killed and crucified
He was wearing an orange jumpsuit and was an elderly man
Not younger than 50 years old
That sight completely destroyed me
And pushed me to leave the area for good
I left by God’s grace
And I didn’t return until after they had left
When the Syrian Democratic Forces took control of the area