There were many people inside
I’ll now list the ones I remember
Among my relatives were my brothers
Abdullah, Abdul Hakim, and Muhammad al-Salamah
And my father, Khalaf al-Salamah
And my cousin Abdullah Hassan al-Salamah
And my other cousins
Abdul Musleh Hassan al-Ibrahim
And Hammouda and Ahmad Hassan al-Ibrahim
And Abdul Hakim Hassan al-Ibrahim
Aziz Hassan al-Ibrahim
Ahmad Hassan—I think I already mentioned him
And Faraj Hassan al-Ibrahim
And their sons, Hassan Ibrahim al-Hassan
Faraj Ibrahim al-Hassan
And Muhammad Faraj al-Hassan
And Muhammad Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi, my cousin
And Kamal Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi
From Jarniya, there was Walid al-Haji
And Muasstam and Hamada al-Haji
There was also a young man named
Anis, a relative of ours from the area
As well as others who had been imprisoned before us
Including Muhannad al-Raji
Ahmad al-Laji and Faisal al-Zahir
Ahmad al-Hamoud
And people from Raqqa Prison, among them Ahmad Sinu
And a young man named Hamad
And young men from the al-Hutayl clan in Mansoura
I don’t remember their names
Because their names were similar to ours
And I started getting confused from so many names
There were also friends of mine in prison
Harith Haj Abdul Sheikh
And Faisal Saad Rajoub from Homs
And Khaled al-Harbi, a young man from Tabqa
And a young man from Rural Aleppo named Alaa
But he was killed in prison
There were also foreign prisoners
Affiliated with ISIS, but they never told me their names
They all went by noms de guerre like Abu so-and-so
Among them were Saudis
And a Lebanese-born man with German citizenship
He had been wounded by a gunshot from one of his comrades
And had metal rods in his body
There were six foreign prisoners in total
Because they were against the idea of establishing the Islamic State
They had criticized it, so they were imprisoned