There were prisoners from the town of Mansoura
They were taken daily for interrogation and torture
Then returned, and that continued for a while
I saw their names on the wall
And learned about their cases
But I didn’t meet any of them because they were far from me
I would hear the sounds of torture when they were taken
But I didn’t know who they were
Once, they took them out before the evening prayer
They took them out one by one
Asking what belongings they had
And if they wanted to send any message to their families
Because the next day
Was the day their sentences would be carried out
Which was execution
And crucifixion in the town of Mansoura
They were sentenced on charges of highway robbery
They were to face the had al-hiraba [punishment for banditry]
Which is execution and crucifixion
They didn’t sleep all night, praying to God
They were taken the next morning
At evening prayer time
ISIS members brought us a newspaper they had issued
It said they had carried out executions
Of eight people
We stayed in shock for several days over what had happened