There was a young man named
Ahmad al-Lajji from Raqqa
And another named Faisal al-Zaher
And another named Ahmad al-Hamoud
He was actually a child, not a young man
They were in solitary cells and we hadn’t spoken before
I didn’t even know they were in prison
They took them and lined them up in front of the group cell
In orange uniforms, with shaved heads and beards
It happened on a Friday morning
They were asked about their charges
All of them were accused of collaborating with the Global Coalition
One of them asked to write a will
So his debts could be paid, but they refused
Then they took them away
I never saw them, only heard their voices
During torture sessions
I didn’t even know their names
Until they were called by name and I saw them then
I used to see their writings on the walls
But I thought they had already been released
Two days later
A young man told me he had seen them killed in Tabqa
Stabbed to death
Then shot afterward
I told him I had seen them only once
Then they brought their magazine
It said they had executed agents of the Coalition
Ahmad al-Lajji, Faisal al-Zaher, and Ahmad al-Hamoud
Our spirits would sink again every
time they took prisoners for execution
There was no taste for sleep or food
When we thought of those killed, their families, and their children
It became normal every two or three days
They would take women from the solitary cells
At night, carrying with them grave-digging tools
The vehicles would leave and come back
We saw the members smiling
As if they hadn’t just killed someone
And it kept happening
Every few days they would take one of the women
There were five or six of them, maybe more