After exactly 16 days
My brother was released
Along with the young man who was with me
Who was from Daraa Province
And who used to say that he was with ISIS
He claimed he was one of ISIS’s security members in Daraa
And was detained after being suspected upon arriving in Raqqa
I had nothing personal to talk with him about
The conversations we had were routine and ordinary
They brought in his place a young man from Tabqa
Who stayed with me for three days
I asked him about the situation outside
He had heard about my detention with my family
I asked him who among my relatives
was still imprisoned or had been released
He told me who had been released from prison
According to him, it was me and two of my brothers
My father, and two of my cousins who remained
I could hear the voices of the others in prison
But those whose voices disappeared
I was very worried about what had happened to them
He assured me that all those who had been released were fine
They placed my brother in the prison corridor before sunset
During the time when we usually received dinner
My brother started talking to me and asking how I was
Taking advantage of the absence of anyone in the corridor
He told me he was going to be released
Since it was customary to release prisoners
Every Monday and Thursday
But my brother’s release was on a Wednesday
I asked him what he had told them, and he reassured me
Telling me not to worry, that everything
was fine and he would be out soon
My brother was four years older than me