Less than a week later, the interrogator came back to me
He asked, What’s new? Do you need anything?
I said, Nothing new, but I want to see my father, just once
He said, You’ll see him today
So I went to see my father, and through the door
I spoke to him and asked how he was
I reassured him that I was fine
And lifted his spirits a bit so he wouldn’t worry too much about me
Then I returned to my cell after five minutes
About a week later
It seemed to me that a senior ISIS official came to the prison
Because they started cleaning and tidying the facilities
The official made a tour around us
Asking, What’s your name? What’s your case?
He asked me, Do you need anything?
I explained my situation and asked about my fate
He said, Don’t worry, everything’s fine
Then he repeated, Do you want anything else?
I said, I want to see my father
He asked, When was the last time you saw him?
I answered, Once, and for five minutes
He said, Alright
Then placed me with my father in the
same group cell, where I found him alone
The official continued his tour
And we could hear the voices of my brother and cousins
As he asked them about their needs
When I saw my father, he hugged
me and started crying. He was fasting
It was Thursday, and we broke our fast together
We didn’t sleep all night
Because of our long conversation
and how much we missed each other
We tried to lift our spirits and comfort each other
We talked about the charges brought against us
My father’s charge was that he once said
That if a military operation began against ISIS in the area
He would be ready to arm 500 fighters
Which was, of course, a fabricated and false accusation
They demanded he bring 500 rifles
My father, in turn, demanded
That they bring witnesses to these accusations
They told him, Your witness is here
He said, Bring him, I have no problem
After the interrogation ended
One of the prisoners told him the name of the witness
And informed my father about it
My father told his fellow prisoners
About the accusation against him
And that there was a witness
He repeatedly asked for the witness
to be brought, but they never did
When one of my father’s cellmates was released
He told the story to the supposed witness
Who later came to the prison
And confirmed that he had not witnessed what my father said
That the entire accusation had no basis in truth
But ISIS members expelled him
Telling him that it was none of his concern
It became clear that the accusation was fabricated
And my father’s imprisonment was purely arbitrary