I used to see, in the solitary cell or the group cell
The names of prisoners, their arrest dates, and reasons
I found the name of a young man I knew from the town of Tabqa
He had written his name and his case on the wall
His name was Muhannad Raja al-Harmoush
They placed him in front of the solitary cell door
Around one o’clock after midnight
I saw them through the window asking his name
He answered, Muhannad Raja al-Harmoush,
so I recognized him immediately
They asked him, What’s your case about?
He said, Mocking ISIS
The interrogator asked, Why do you mock?
He replied, explaining that what he
said was only a joke, nothing more
The interrogator said, No problem with that
Muhannad stayed standing for five minutes
They shackled his hands and blindfolded him
Then took him elsewhere
Through the ventilation opening of the solitary cells
Overlooking the car garage
We could hear clearly
They put him in the van
Carrying with them tools for digging graves
I concluded they were going to kill and bury him
After about two hours
The members came back with their tools but without Muhannad
They were laughing as if returning from an amusing trip
We came to see that as normal
Because it happened regularly from time to time