At first, the approach was calm and smooth
The interrogator found nothing he was looking for
Then he began torturing by beating
All over the body with a hose or a stick
Even if our bodies broke under torture
Because more than one prisoner suffered fractures as a result
He kept beating continuously
As long as the person did not lose consciousness
If he found no result, he tried
the shabeh [suspension] method
He lifted the person using the balingo
[hoist] by his hands
So that his feet did not touch the ground
Which forced the prisoner
To confess to whatever the interrogator wanted
Even if the person had done nothing against them at all
We said there was beating and suspension
As for the women, we heard their screams
Without knowing their method of torture
Without hearing the sounds of beating
Or knowing their style of interrogation with women
But interrogations always took place after midnight
And lasted for around three hours
Torture included everyone without exception
And it was done according to the charges brought against them
And based on confessions
Anyone with serious charges
Was tortured by all means until he spoke
They continued even if it led to death
Once, they tortured a man
Before I was detained
His name was Ammar, from al-Baasi village
They kept torturing him until he died
Without extracting any confession
So I realized they had no problem with a prisoner dying
Depending on his case
No problem