They offered to cancel half of my sentence
In exchange for me handing over my
brother who had not been detained
He would come in, and I would be released instead
I claimed that our relationship was normal
And I did not expect him to come for me
If he was outside the area
And that it was their mistake
Because they had already detained
him earlier on multiple charges
And still could not get anything from him
So I was not obliged to do that
When I was released, they tried to bargain with me to join them
At the same time a Syrian regime convoy arrived
Along with the Russians
On their way to Tabqa city
They tried to convince me to take a weapon from them
And fight alongside them if we shared the same cause
As proof of my loyalty to them
Interviewer: And how did they react to your refusal?
Of course, I refused in an indirect way
By saying that I was the youngest in my family
And that my mother would never abandon me after prison
And I had no idea how her health was
So how could I get out and take up arms immediately