My name is Muhammad Nour Shahadah,
I reside in the city of Tabqa
I am 31 years old, born in 1990
I was detained in 2017
I am married and have 4 children
I was detained and taken from my home
at exactly 10:00 in the morning
I do not remember the exact day of the month
A patrol of ISIS members came to me
and detained me from my home, blindfolded
Being from the city of Tabqa, I knew they took me
to Bourj [Tower] Prison
Based on my estimation of the directions
they took
As soon as I arrived here,
I was imprisoned
The car drove us in here,
and then we walked
They brought me down approximately here
Right here
They grabbed me by my hair like this,
pulling my head back, and walked me forward
Then they took me to a room,
I do not know exactly where it was
I took off my shoes, pardon me,
and then went inside
They took my personal information,
then led me to a group cell, a small room
Its dimensions were roughly
Half a meter wide, or slightly more, 60 cm
Two meters long,
the length of a grown man
It was called the disciplinary cell
One of the ISIS members, after taking my
personal information, struck me here on my cheek
Which broke the bone here and left a visible mark,
then he ordered the others to take me to disciplinary
The vehicle was a Hyundai H1,
and they blindfolded me inside it
A small passenger van, a Hyundai
When we entered here, I heard the sound
of the car tires over that metal rail
So I immediately knew they had brought me
to Bourj Prison
We entered from here
I was blindfolded,
so one of them grabbed me by my hair
At the time my hair was longer,
so he grabbed me from behind like this
And walked me forward
We entered like this
And of course, when you enter here,
they start beating you and filling you with fear and terror
As if you are walking to your death