The room, after I entered through the door here,
they brought me in kneeling, of course
My hands were bound behind my back,
blindfolded, of course I could not see
Any of them, except once
when one of them took my information
He told me, you are talking about us
and disrespecting the mujahideen
Of course I said, no sheikh,
and he said, will you not stop running your mouth
So he punched me here,
I think there were two people behind me
He hit me and when they helped me stand up,
he struck me here on my cheekbone and broke it
And when they helped me stand up,
he beat me with the green hose
Known as the Lakhdar Brahimi, which became
a notorious torture weapon, he beat me on my back
He said, take him to disciplinary,
and I did not know what disciplinary was
I expected they might have hoists and
balingo [hoist for suspension], then they took me to disciplinary
The disciplinary cell was a room roughly 70 cm wide,
by two meters long
Just like this, nothing in it
except one blanket to sleep on the floor with
Interviewer: During your imprisonment,
how many times did they interrogate you?
They interrogated me approximately
15 or 16 times
Of course, because I was denying the charges
and denying everything, any claim at all
Because I knew, we were afraid of execution
and things like that
Because we felt an unnatural terror due to
the abnormal methods of torture
Abnormal beatings, humiliation, of course
the disciplinary cell alone equaled all other forms of torture, it was the worst
It was worse than all other methods of torture
Interviewer: Was there any audio
or video recording? Or did you not notice?
I do not know, only once they removed
my tamasha [blindfold], they lifted it
Here I noticed two people, I even looked away
from them and kept my eyes fixed on the ground
Even him, I could not look at his face
and he was masked, I could not look at him
Two people sitting in the corner
using laptops
They did not interfere or approach, and two people,
as I later learned, stand behind you during interrogation
The interrogator was sitting here like this,
and next to him he placed
The stick and the whip, his weapons ready,
his torture tools
Interviewer: Who were the interrogators?
And what was their accent?
Interviewer: What were their questions?
What type of questions did they ask you?
Their accent was local,
meaning the interrogator was not a foreigner
There was one person whose accent was not fully
Arabic, but he was not an interrogator
That was only once,
meaning he came only one time
The types of questions: What do you know?
Do you have connections outside? Who is so-and-so?
And who is so-and-so? On the phone for example,
he reads names, who is this person, and this person
Where does this one live? What does he do?
Do you know anyone in the Free Syrian Army?
Or anyone in the areas controlled
by the Assad regime? Or anyone in the party?
A party called the Syrian Democratic Forces,
the SDF
I told him, I do not know anything,
I am someone who does not mix with anyone
Interviewer: Did they have a lot of information
about you? Did they know things about you that nobody else knew?
Interviewer: Did they have methods or intelligence
officers who brought them information?
Of course, my detention was because of what I said
in front of someone who gave them the information
Information about me, ordinary information,
of course they have information about most of the locals
It was ordinary information, they knew my job
and where I live, nothing more
Interviewer: Did they offer you to work with them
or join them in exchange for releasing you from prison?
No, that matter, they assumed that we,
and people like me
Among the prisoners, especially in this place,
would never cooperate with them
They always viewed us as a dagger in their back,
of course that was their perspective
Except once, they tried changing the interrogation
approach from beating
He brought me once, stood me up like this,
and moved me slightly to the left
Then he removed my blindfold
from my face for the first time
He was sitting there, wearing a Chechen-style tunic,
and a desert-colored mask, not black
Behind me were two guards, dressed in black,
wearing black masks
Next to me was a person I know who lives in Tabqa,
I prefer not to mention his name
He spoke to him and said, did anyone beat you?
He said, no, no sheikh
Did anyone harm you or speak to you?
He said no, so he said take him to his room, give him what he wants, and let him call his mother
After he left, he said to me, do you know
why we did not beat him? I said, no sheikh, I do not know
He said, because he was cooperating with us
and told us everything, so you be like that and we will make it easier for you
I told him, I have told you everything I have,
there is nothing to add
And that is when the beating started,
he beat me that day as if I had provoked him with those words
When I got out, my entire back was blue,
all of it
He said, take him and discipline him,
in his words, until he becomes a human being, then I was taken back to disciplinary
Interviewer: Did they threaten you with anything,
like harming your family outside?
They threatened me with my brother,
one of my brothers, that they would bring him and detain him
I told him, he is a minor,
he was 17 or 18 years old at the time
I told him, he is a minor, he has nothing,
even if you bring him
I said, sheikh, I have nothing,
I have told you everything
Of course, at that point I understood
this was a tactic to provoke me into talking
He was trying to provoke me
so that I would talk to him
I told him, if you want to bring him then bring him,
he is a minor who knows nothing
Interviewer: Did they threaten you with execution?
Or with a longer prison sentence if you did not confess?
No, they did not threaten me with execution,
because he would tell me, confess
And undergo one of our sharia courses
and then you will be released, here they do not threaten
Here the death threats, from what I would hear
of course
While I was in my solitary cell,
I could hear them during interrogations, the screaming and torture
Those who confessed, they would tell them,
I will execute you on such-and-such day
After a few days,
we will throw you at such-and-such roundabout
There were things that happened
that I found deeply shocking
One such thing was a prisoner who cursed God,
meaning he blasphemed, as we say
I could hear him being told,
are you doing this to hasten your execution?
I will extend your time and keep you
under torture for an extra month just for that
This matter, to this very moment I am shocked by it,
to this very moment I cannot believe it
I even asked one of the prisoners who was here
with me after ISIS's reign ended, I asked him, and he said, yes I heard it
I heard that too, I asked him, did you hear
the same thing as me or was I imagining it? He said, I heard it with my own ears