To this day, as I told you at the beginning, I am afraid
when I pass by it, every time I pass by I feel tense and anxious
In the disciplinary cell, my blood sugar started dropping,
to this day, it still drops sometimes
Once I got very tense, I do not want to say I was brave
or a hero, honestly I was not scared, but I was tense
Unsettled, meaning annoyed, suffocated by this place,
tight and suffocating
My blood sugar started dropping,
to this day it still affects me
The scars on my feet,
my knee took six months of treatment
And this cheekbone was broken,
the mark stayed for a long time, it never went away
My hand here, to this day, because of one time
on the balingo [hoist for suspension]
Of course the balingo is a hoist shaped like this,
my hand to this very moment
My hand here is not like my other hand,
sometimes it hurts a lot
Interviewer: What were the other methods
of torture they used?
The other method of torture was the disciplinary cell,
and it was worse than the beatings
Worse than anything,
it was humiliation upon humiliation
Interviewer: I mean the devices, like
the balingo, and shabeh [suspension]
Everything you can imagine, of course there was a torture
method that was both humiliation and torture
When you leave the interrogation, they take you out,
he tells you, walk on your own
You are blindfolded and do not know where you are going,
and if you hit the wall, they beat you immediately
Sometimes, I remember once
I hit the wall and fell
Both of them, there were two, started beating me,
and I immediately got up, I had to get up quickly
The rest of the torture methods, they used everything,
only electricity they did not use, everything else they did
Interviewer: Was torture applied to all prisoners?
Or only to specific people?
No, everyone, everyone was tortured,
everyone I believe, I do not think anyone entered here
Into this place as a prisoner and can say
I was not beaten, impossible
Interviewer: Did you hear about any women
being held in the prison? Or hear women being tortured?
No, I did not hear that, but they said before my time
there was one female prisoner, I heard about her
Once, they took my friend who is a nurse,
and he put an IV drip for her
He even said she extended her hand through
a window, but without him seeing her
And he set up the IV,
that is all, that is what I heard
But while I was in this place,
I never heard women's voices, nothing at all
Interviewer: Who were the people responsible for torture?
Where were they from? What was their accent?
The interrogator was from the area,
and the two guards were mostly from the area as well
Their accent was from this region,
I do not know his name of course
I have no idea what his name was,
they would call him Abu Abdullah, that is all
Interviewer: Did you hear of any prisoner
who died under torture here in the prison?
Before my imprisonment, yes I heard,
I heard about two people who died, they were cousins
Even when their family paid,
there were three of them imprisoned
They released one of them in exchange for the fact
that the other two had died under torture, and they paid blood money
They paid their blood money as compensation for their
death under torture, and pardoned the third cousin, who was the brother of one of the deceased
Interviewer: Can you give us
the names of those people?
Which names?
Interviewer: The people who died under torture
Names of people who died under torture? I do not know their
names, because those three were not from this area
From around the area,
I do not know their exact names
The way they would deliver sentences, for example,
I remember an incident with a person, may God have mercy on him
When they made him read his own execution sentence,
they started laughing while he was crying
And they were laughing,
they did that to provoke him
This is something I did not witness personally,
but someone who was an eyewitness told me about it
To this very moment,
this incident still affects me