As I told you, one time
I was washing my clothes
One of them came in and said, do you think you are
at your family's house? Because I was undressed, pardon me
He said, do you think you are at home?
He was one of the guards who treated us badly
Do you think you are at your family's house,
washing your clothes from the smell of smoke
I could not talk back but I said, as you wish sheikh,
I washed them because they started to smell
Because of the disciplinary cell,
they smelled terrible
After that I started paying close attention
to every word they said outside
With every sound, every sound of a prisoner
being beaten, and every person screaming
The one who cries out, oh God,
and the guard responds, now you know God, now you have returned
Interviewer: Was there any way to talk when you were
in the solitary cells next to each other? Could you communicate?
It is true the solitary cells are adjacent,
but it was impossible to communicate, we only heard the call to prayer
We only heard the call to prayer,
and the muaazin was one of the prisoners
Interviewer: We know that ISIS used specific titles
for positions
Like the Emir, the Governor, and the Sharia judge,
can you tell us about each of their roles?
The Emir, what is his role,
and the Governor and the Sharia judge?
Of course ISIS's titles differ from other organizations,
being ultimately a military organization
They differ from the titles used
by armies and other organizations
We know there are officer ranks and so on,
but they
Had the Emir, the interrogator,
and the Sharia judge
This place functions like a security branch,
let us say an intelligence branch for example
The guards would come, and of course some of them
were decent people and others were not
The person who came to take photographs,
we only saw him once, we can consider him the archive
Those people had no titles
and were considered soldiers of the caliphate
The interrogator who conducted interrogations
was also the Emir of Bourj Prison
He was different from the security Emir,
and the judge reviews the prisoner's file
He summons the prisoner and tells him,
you did such-and-such, and this is your sentence
This is what you have done, and of course
that happens after you have confessed and he tells you everything
He tells you, you did such-and-such,
and this is your sentence, case closed
Some prisoners received their sentences
in their cells, which I learned later
They hand it to them on a paper that says,
so-and-so, come, this is your sentence
Or, so-and-so, come, perform wudu [ablution],
prepare yourself, perform ablution and prepare yourself means your life is over
Interviewer: There were some ISIS members
who were called foreign fighters
Interviewer: Were there foreign fighters here
in the prison? And how did you communicate with them if so?
The members who were of foreign nationalities,
not Syrian
A Saudi one time, I recognized him
by his accent, a Saudi person
He came in here and was talking, and I recognized
his accent, being alone I paid attention to every sound
Another time, a foreigner appeared,
and there were Iraqis who would come in
But most of them were locals from the area,
from Tabqa or its countryside, they were the ones interrogating us
Interviewer: How did you communicate
with people of foreign nationalities?
The foreign members did not communicate
with us directly
Except the judge who was Saudi, but I was not brought
before him, in the end I was brought before an Iraqi Sharia judge
They said, this is the Sharia judge or the sheikh,
and they warned us about speaking in the sheikh's presence
They coached us on how to behave before the sheikh,
saying, do not move, and when we tell you to stand, you stand
We had no contact with foreigners at all,
except in the tunnel there was a foreigner, obvious from his accent, who only beat people
His Arabic was broken,
so we knew he was a foreigner
We do not know his nationality,
because everyone was masked
Possibly Uzbeks, who are recognizable by their facial
features, or Afghans, or people from those countries