One night, a shell fell on the building,
it shook a little from the impact
You probably will not believe this,
will not believe what I am about to say
I said, salvation has come, I felt relieved,
maybe we die, it was a relief for us
Either we die and find rest,
or we get out
There was a small commotion among them,
and movement outside, that night they did not take anyone for interrogation
The next day, around 12:30,
or after the noon prayer
Let us be precise,
right after the noon prayer
They executed someone,
they took someone, I heard them take him
They were even mocking him,
they said, this one is gone, God be with him
And said mocking words
that I do not want to repeat
A person who passed away, may God have mercy on him,
they killed him in the open
When they came back, we had prayed noon prayer,
and the prison was shelled
My room was filled with dust,
and there were sounds and chaos outside, unimaginable
I hear screaming, and nobody moves,
he says we have orders
Any of you who tries to make any unusual movement,
we will kill you immediately
Of course, when did I realize my room was the last one?
Because I was the last person to be taken out
The guard came, rather Abu Abdullah
the interrogator himself, he is the one who came
Abu Abdullah came and took me, stood me at the door,
blindfolded me, and placed a laptop in my hands
He said, carry this, held my hand,
and said, walk with me, I will guide you
When I tell you to step, you step,
we went up, I think from here, and we walked
I do not know, I was blindfolded,
this place, because there was chaos and unimaginable dust, we were suffocating
We walked, kept walking until I felt
we went down a little and there was dirt
Here he removed my blindfold, and in front of me
were about 14 or 15 people, I do not remember the exact number
Because after that moment,
I was in shock for two days
There was a person who had been killed,
they killed him before I came out
A killed person, before I came out
they had already killed him
The ones who were taken out before me
saw how they killed him
We were all like this in this position,
and like this, and nobody made any movement
He said, any unusual movement and we will kill you,
even if you step out of line, they lined us up like a column
At that moment, I remembered Camp Speicher,
how they executed them and lined them up like this, I said it is over, they will execute us
Here I felt relieved, I said,
this is enough, death is more merciful than this
We walked, the number of guards increased here,
there were many of them
They surrounded us from everywhere, and I was the last one,
he kept hitting me with his rifle, saying nobody moves
They shouted at someone named Abdul Sattar
or Abdul Jabbar, I do not remember, he told him, any movement and I will kill you
We walked a little through the tunnel,
until we came out facing this building on the other side
We entered a building, then exited it
to an open area, the vehicles arrived of course
When we reached the building, we exited the tunnel
via stairs into an unfinished building, still on its frame
They grabbed a person, dragged him to the side and shot
him on the spot, he said nobody look, this one had a death sentence, he said do not be afraid
The one who said that was Abu Abdullah,
the interrogator
The one who executed him looked visibly delighted,
and the other one said to him, how lucky you are
As if he envied him for this moment,
I wished this one would not catch us, so he would not gloat over us
So he would not feel this thrill,
I do not know where he got it from
Vehicles arrived, they took us and ordered us
all into one van
The rest of the members
rode in another van
Abu Abdullah rode behind us on a motorcycle,
carrying his pistol
He looked at us, and whenever we looked,
he signaled us not to look, you must not know where we are going
We entered the room,
they took us somewhere, a location in Tabqa
We entered, the car drove inside,
a large gate, and the car went into the yard
We entered a room, and for the first time,
all prisoners sat together
We sat down, and the people I knew from Tabqa
sat beside me
We talked a little,
exchanged greetings and spoke
One of the prisoners was drinking tea,
someone said to him, do you really want to drink tea right now, in this situation?
That person was clearly tense,
he said, my death sentence has been issued
So let me live in the moment, let me enjoy,
we have not even had tea in days
After that, they divided us into two groups,
some were taken like me, along with other people
They took us and placed us in a holding facility
belonging to the Islamic Police
And they went with the others,
those who also had prisoners in the same building, they put them together
The rest were all taken to Raqqa, some had to attend
closed courses, or served out their sentences there
Some were executed, some survived
and returned to Tabqa, and we met them
Interviewer: Can you name the people you remember,
whether those who stayed with you in Tabqa or those who went to Raqqa?
I do not know them, I only know,
I only know three from Tabqa
I know two of them to this day,
and they are still afraid, I prefer not to mention their names
Because I know them, it is not possible,
to this day they live in real terror
There was a person named Abboud al-Shawwakh,
I know him, he was brought in and left with us through the tunnel
He is the only person from Tabqa I remember,
the other two I prefer not to name
Most of the prisoners' charges were apostasy
and collaboration
In their language, apostasy means
anyone who was a collaborator
Or for example anyone they considered an infidel,
collaboration meant anyone who had ties with any faction outside their control
They would charge them, sometimes the charges
were over trivial things, even a photo
For example, if you had a photo of the Free Syrian Army,
that was considered collaboration
Sometimes, even a photo of the Syrian flag
was considered collaboration, they treated it as collaboration