This was my place, the guard opens the door
and says to me, go ahead, sir
Sarcastically, meaning mocking words,
and I would go out to him
At the door, he steps in one step,
ties my hands behind my back, blindfolds me, then takes me
Of course he would always take me,
and he would do this move the most
There was a lot of humiliation in it,
he grabs you from behind like this, or pushes your head down hard
That is what I remember,
moments like these are impossible to forget
Interviewer: How long did you stay in this place?
In this place,
I stayed exactly 12 days
Interviewer: How did you spend
your time in this place?
In this place, if we imagine
this door, we enter here
Here was the food they left for you, which consisted of
jam, halva, olives, they left it here for you
You always had this,
there were exactly two shelves here
There was a Quran, Sahih al-Bukhari,
and Tafsir Ibn Kathir
There was a nail clipper here, the room was carpeted
with a decent carpet, not bad
The blankets were clean,
a person should speak the truth, the cleanliness was excellent
Here, this was built with cinder blocks,
a concrete wall
But it was not part of the original construction,
clearly it was new construction
This here, pardon me,
was the bathroom and toilet
When we go in here,
they would place the cleaning supplies here
Laundry detergent,
if someone wanted to wash their clothes
Shampoo for fungus and lice,
and things like that
Regular shampoo, laurel soap,
and dish soap
Dish soap, in case someone wanted
to wash the dishes after meals and give them back
There were two water taps here,
I remember a hot water tap and a cold water tap
And hot water was available,
because the weather was a bit cold
Here there was an exhaust fan,
and there was an old sponge or loofah here
Here was a sponge, two pillows,
this wall of course
Usually here, the tiles were all exposed,
meaning the place was carpeted here
Up to approximately here,
and the tiles here were all exposed
One of the ways I would pass the time
was counting the tiles
I never mixed with other prisoners,
I saw nobody until the last day when we came out
Except one person, an ISIS member who was placed
here for just one hour, that is all
Later I learned that ISIS had executed him
because his charge was fleeing from battle
Or being a deserter, as they say,
or a runaway as they call it in military terms
He was the only person who was placed here with me,
and the second person I saw was during interrogation, that is all
Those are the only people I saw
during my imprisonment
Until the last day, when I saw all the prisoners,
everyone, but I saw them in the tunnel