In the final period,
when they transferred me to the Islamic Police
I left the prison,
then they placed me in a solitary cell
That same day, after two or three hours,
a guard came and took me to a group cell
I saw people for the first time,
other than the dead, I saw people who were alive
Of course I had seen all the prisoners
who were dead, I saw them dead
When I came out, I felt like I was the only survivor
among them, me and the two people who were taken with me
We stayed in this group cell for three days
at a base in Tabqa, it was a basement
After three days, at night there was a huge commotion
and unimaginable shelling
There was a young man, not very old,
who told me this shelling is from our area, we are the ones being shelled
As if he was joking,
just to lighten the mood
An official came in that I did not recognize,
his face was uncovered, he pardoned all the prisoners
Except two, a Yezidi boy
I remember from Iraq
They took him with them to Raqqa, and another person
they also took to Raqqa, what he did and what his charge was, I do not know
Some people owed ten million lira,
or had to pay gold dinars, those were their sentences
People were waiting for their families to pay for them,
some had not paid but were pardoned anyway
When my turn came, I went in to this person,
he was Iraqi by nationality and accent, that is all I know about him
Interviewer: Do you remember
what this person looked like?
He was between 45 and 50 years old,
he had a calm face
He seemed like a very gentle person
and he gave us a sense of security
When they took me to him, there were two standing
behind me and two standing behind him
They warned me not to get too close,
stand where we tell you, and I knew the ones behind him carried rifles
I expected that any wrong move from me
and they would shoot me
He asked me, what is your name?
What do you do? Why were you brought here?
I told him, I was accused of speaking
about the brothers in the Islamic State
And about a certain figure in the Islamic State,
he said, I give you my word of safety, did you speak or not, my son?
I said no, I did not speak, he said, be honest with me,
I have given you my word of safety, nobody can touch you
I said yes, I spoke, and after all that torture
I confessed to him
He said, you are sentenced,
we will whip you 100 lashes, and then you are free
The person I spoke about,
he told me, you do not know this person the way I do
He was a very high-ranking figure,
I cannot mention his name
Because to this day
I live in fear of them, to this very moment
He told me that this person is a good and simple man
and that he personally sits with him and knows him
At that point I realized this person
was a senior figure in ISIS with wide influence
He told me, we will whip you 100 lashes
and then you go free
When I got out, I was hoping the guard
at the other base would be the one to whip me
But it happened that Abu Abdullah the interrogator
was there, he is the one who whipped me 100 lashes
Of course he whipped me with vicious cruelty,
I even left barefoot
When we left for home,
we all left barefoot, without shoes
I left and went home
and sat there and did not go out again
I spent two days treating my injuries
and wounds from the whipping, the pain was unbearable
Of course the psychological damage was greater
than the physical pain, it still affects me a little to this day