Name: Muhannad Mahmoud Saeed
From the right side of the Old City
Born on April 18, 1998
I’m married, and I have two children
I was detained on a Friday, on Eid al-Adha
During the noon prayer
I was standing guard
My brother and I were working a machine to make fries and sell them
At a place with children's rides
Everyone left, and they told me to stay and guard the machine and the rides
At that time, there was foot traffic
While I was selling, the Hisba Diwan car pulled up
Even though one of those they call the Hisba
Was the one who had made me stand guard
They asked me to get in, but I told them I was standing guard
He said, You are neglecting prayer
and selling at the time of prayer
I refused to get into the car
So he pushed me inside and shut the door on me
Interviewer: According to you, you’d taken permission from one of them?
Interviewer: Did he give you permission to stay and not go to prayer?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Was the person you asked
permission from the same one who arrested you?
Or was it another group who did that?
No, another patrol came
The one I asked permission from was standing in the square
And I was standing by the triangle in the Sarj Khana area
And he was blocking the road
And the other came from the Grand Mosque and saw me
I had taken permission and told him that
but he said, There is no such thing
I told him—We are two working on the machine
One of us goes to pray and comes back, then the other goes to pray
Interviewer: Couldn't the one who gave you permission see you?
No, he was far from me
Even if he could see me
They wanted any pretext to hold someone to account
To grab people
Interviewer: Then they made you get into the car. How did they treat you inside?
Did they swear at you or use obscene language?
Did they beat you? And did they blindfold you or not?
Witness: No, no
Interviewer: From the moment you got into the car until you arrived here
They were two, and I became the third
They only pushed me into the car at the start
Because I refused to get into the car
Because I had permission, so why take me and hold me to account?
He did not accept that
In the car, no one spoke to me
They brought us in, and we were three people
Interviewer: Okay, the two who were with you in the car
Do you remember exactly where they arrested them?
And what were their charges?
One of them was from Bawabat al-Sham
He was at a wedding
They caught him because he had plucked his eyebrows
And he’d shaped his beard
Interviewer: Do you mean he was the groom?
No, he was one of the people in the wedding cars
Interviewer: One of the guests?
Witness: Yes
He was probably the groom’s paternal cousin
Or his maternal cousin, I don’t remember exactly
And the other was a young man
His charge was neglecting prayer as well
Interviewer: Were your eyes open?
Witness: Yes, open
Interviewer: What was the exact time when they took you?
I told you, at the noon prayer, exactly
Meaning when the imam was giving the Friday sermon
Interviewer: Okay, the place is narrow, a car can’t get in
Where did the car come in from?
And where did they drop you off, and how?
And how did they bring you to this place?
They stopped here where there is a yard
They drove the car into it
They brought us here on foot
Interviewer: On foot, in front of everyone, just normally?
Yes, it was normal in front of people
Interviewer: And they brought you here?
They brought us inside here
There were prisoners inside
Interviewer: Didn’t you stay here for a long time?
And was the door open when you entered or closed?
It was open, as it is now
But as soon as we entered, they closed it