Interviewer: When they brought you into the hall
And the time for the afternoon prayer came, and it was your first prayer here
Were you in wudu [ritual purity], or did you tell them you wanted to do your ablutions?
Or did they force you to wash?
No, he said, Who among you is not in wudu?
I told him I was, and we went out—we were four or five people
Those who were before us
Had already performed wudu and prayed the noon prayer
Then we came
We performed wudu and returned to the hall to pray
Here, here
These faucets were here
We performed wudu and went out
Did you perform wudu and relieve yourself?
No, I only performed wudu
Interviewer: Only in this place? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: From when you came from the hall until you performed wudu and returned?
Were guards escorting you, or were you alone?
One of them was standing here
And another was standing there
And another was standing in the corridor
As you know, you cannot
I looked to the right and left, searching for
A place to escape—I looked, but there was none
Interviewer: Did he come to you?
Witness: Yes, of course
And here you do not know your fate, whether they will flog you or imprison you
If they imprison you for fifteen days
And your family knows nothing about you
And God forbid, a plane might bomb you and you would die
No one knows anything about you
I looked to the right and left, and I am from this area
I looked for a way, and through the roof I thought I could reach it
I saw the place was crowded, and the idea of escape was hard
Interviewer: The prefab houses and rooms around us, and the destroyed places?
Do you remember what they were used for?
Or did you not see them or pay attention to them?
I did not pay attention to them in those days
As I told you, they used these rooms for the prison
It was for temporary detention, like two or three days
Or five days
And after that they would transfer them
Interviewer: Were the rooms partitioned?
Witness: Yes, they were partitioned
Interviewer: When you went out for wudu?
The first wudu, at the very start of your time in the place
And it was new to you
While you went for wudu and came back?
Didn't you hear torture, the voices of prisoners present? Screams?
Women's voices? Didn't you hear anything like that?
No, I did not hear them
Interviewer: You did not hear?
Witness: No
As I told you, torture does not happen here, and harsh torture does not happen here
Like falaqa [foot whipping] and other methods of torture
Nothing happens here because it is only temporary
He is presented to the sharia
And whoever did not confess
This is what God has decreed for him
Interviewer: By sharia, do you mean the judge?
Witness: Yes, their sharia judge