I'm talking to you about the dawn prayer
You must wake up before the prayer
And since you're inside, you need to be mindful of those behind you
So they won't be held accountable
Meaning you relieve yourself quickly, just for the prayer
And you go for wudu [ablution]
At normal times, when you enter the toilet
You knock for the jailer, to go to the toilet
He opens the door so you can go into the toilet
Interviewer: Was the jailer cooperative, making it easy to get into the toilet?
Yes, he says, Where to? You say, To the toilet, and he says, Go out
Interviewer: Did he clash with you sometimes?
Witness: No, no
Interviewer: With anyone?
Not with anyone, and we had nothing to do
Interviewer: In this place was there just one jailer?
There was one here in the corridor
But over here I wasn't paying attention to him
As you know, when he lets you out, he stands here
You go straight in
Interviewer: You were more than twenty people with one jailer?
While using the toilet, did
two or three go out to relieve
themselves together, or did each person go alone?
No, no, they go out one by one
And when you go out, he closes the door behind you
Interviewer: Didn’t you think, while you were in the prison, when the door opened
And since he was one person alone, to try to escape?
To overpower him or hit him? Didn't something like that ever happen?
That idea exists, but you can’t do anything
You assume there is just one person here
But inside or on the rooftops you don’t know how many they are
And they are armed
The simplest thing is that he kills you without batting an eye
Interviewer: Did you relieve yourself comfortably with no pressure?
No, no, you go in and come out
Only at prayer times, you have to hurry
So those behind you won’t be held accountable
Interviewer: You hurried out by choice? Witness: Yes, yes
Interviewer: Did the prayer have a set time?
Did you have to pray when the call to prayer started?
A certain number of minutes from the call to prayer, or immediately after it finishes?
When the call to prayer begins
You perform wudu and finish the ablution
He waits ten minutes or five minutes and starts the prayer
Everyone must be in the hall for the prayer