They brought us in through the door
They brought us in, they detained me on the charge of neglecting prayer
I told them, I did not neglect prayer
I did not neglect it, I have a dispensation
They answered, No, you neglected prayer, give us your name
I gave them my full name, and my mother's name
And I took out the phone, and while searching me they found the cigarettes
In the izar, and they went crazy
Interviewer: What do you mean by izar?
These pants were not allowed to be worn like this
Unless they had an izar [wrapper] tight at the bottom
Only a short izar like this—there was no long izar
Interviewer: Did you put the cigarettes inside the waistband of the pants?
There was elastic at the bottom of the pants, I put them in there
And as you know, wide pants do not show anything
And when they searched me, they found them
Here, at the bottom of the pants
Interviewer: Describe how you stashed the cigarettes. Where did you put them?
This is the cigarette pack
Let me toss it here
Interviewer: Were the pants wide?
Yes, the pants were wide and the cigarette pack dropped to the bottom
And here it is wide, and at the bottom it is tight, it does not show
Because it is wide, nothing shows in it?
Yes, because the pants are long and wide, it bunches up
It does not show at all
Interviewer: How many packs of cigarettes were you carrying?
I was carrying two packs, one for me and the other for my brother
My brother went to prayer
And he left his cigarettes with me
Were the two packs full?
No, each one had about seven or eight cigarettes
They went crazy
Interviewer: And after they found the cigarettes?
At first they took my name
Interviewer: Where did they take your name?
Witness: They stopped us here
There was a man sitting, bearded
What is your name?
He wrote it in the notebook
And your mother's name, your birth date, and your charge
He wrote, Neglecting prayer, I told him, I am not negligent
He said, Be quiet, you neglected prayer
And he wrote for those who came with me
He turned his face and then went to that church
The main church, or I do not know what they call it
On the computer he recorded our names
He said, Go inside now
Interviewer: The person who recorded your name and took your address and information about you?
Interviewer: Was there a desk or a table here?
Witness: Yes, there was a table
Interviewer: How many chairs were there?
Witness: A table and chairs
It was a guesthouse, like it belonged to their father
There was a table and sofa sets
Interviewer: By the diwan [administrative hall], do you mean chairs?
Yes, chairs, and they sat on them
Where exactly were they sitting?
Here was a sitting area, and inside it went lengthwise
Because the table was in this direction
And the other was lengthwise, and the other table was here
They were sitting, relaxed
Interviewer: How many people sat here, or was it just one person?
One person was the one who took the information
But as for soldiers, as they say
This room was packed
On the roof, at the door, or somewhere else
They were spread out around this place
Interviewer: After he took your name and information exactly
Was it the same person who took you to the detention room, the cell?
Or did he assign someone else, meaning another ISIS member?
No, he said, Go straight into the hall
Interviewer: Without anyone accompanying you?
Yes, you can't move around here
You can't do anything
Because they are all present, you can't do anything or run away
The place was closed. They shut the door on us right after we went in
Interviewer: During this period, from your entry
through the door until you reached this place
Exactly, did they tie your hands with a piece of cloth, or with cuffs?
Or were your hands free?
No, my hands were free
As I told you, when they heard that I was neglecting prayer
They pushed me, and then they found the cigarettes
They pushed us and took us into the hall
Interviewer: The first time you came to this place
Did you imagine this place was a prison, or were you surprised that it was a prison?
It didn't cross my mind that it was a prison
Interviewer: So it was a surprise for you?
Witness: Yes
I thought it was normal
Ten minutes or a quarter hour, then they would say, Go
Interviewer: Not the duration of prison
time, but when you first came to this place?
No, I didn't know there was a prison here
I absolutely didn't know
I was surprised to find people imprisoned here
Interviewer: In this place, when you first came in here
And as you entered through the main door
And the ISIS member took your information
Until they took you into the hall
That period, about how long did it take?
Minutes, or half an hour, or an hour—more than that or less?
No, no
I told you we were three people, it took about
Half an hour—he took our information and our belongings, then to the hall
Interviewer: In this half hour or less?
From when they brought you in through the main gate
to this person, then you entered the hall
Did you hear people screaming?
Or did you hear people being tortured?
Did you hear loud sounds or strange sounds?
Did you hear women’s voices, for example?
And was this prison for women? Had you heard that? Or do you not know?
No, I didn’t hear, and I don’t know
But I could hear them talking inside
Those outside were shouting, Be quiet, everyone, no one speak
From here
When we came, there was a group before us
They brought them into the hall, and had not yet taken them out to the prison
Interviewer: Didn’t you hear the sounds of people they were torturing?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Before you entered the prison
From when you entered through the main gate up to this room
Until they took you into the prison?
Witness: No
I didn’t hear, but in that church
I have a cousin who went in there
The torture there is not normal, he said