Tab 1
We waited a little until prayer time was over
Before maghreb [sunset] prayer, they brought us out and said
Everyone out
A group of us were taken
There were four or five of us, they took us out
We came to this room
There were other prisoners inside
Each one sitting in a corner
I came in
And as you know, I wasn't familiar with any of this
I was preoccupied thinking about what they would do to us
No one knew what their fate would be
I stood here, stayed for a quarter or half an hour
And you're left powerless, helpless
I stood here and sat down
Interviewer: When they brought you out of the big hall where you prayed asr [afternoon]
Was the placement into rooms optional?
Could you choose any room, or were you placed wherever they wanted?
No, no, it was as they wanted
You go there, and you go there, and you go with those ones to that room
Each person
They started separating us
You go there, and you go here
Each one took a group and went upstairs
Interviewer: Were the prisoners divided based on a list?
Or were there no prisoner lists in the prison?
I think there were lists
Like lists of smokers, or of those who prayed—Come out here
And those with other charges, or who’d tried to escape, or fought
Each prisoner was placed according to his charge
Interviewer: How many prisoners could this room hold?
When I came in, there were about 20 people here
We were in this room
We were almost suffocating from how crowded it was
And God forbid, if any bombing happened, none of us would survive
Interviewer: Describe the state of the prisoners here
How did you spend your first hour here?
How did you spend your first night in this place?
What did the prisoners talk about in this room?
Were you free to speak?
Or were you afraid of each other?
The situation was miserable
When you enter the room, everyone is carrying their own burden
And they spend their time sleeping
As for talking, of course we talked, like asking, What are your charges?
Or where do you live, or are you related to someone, and so on
But beyond that, you couldn't talk
Because as the saying goes, the walls have ears
You fear saying something and then paying the price for it
Just normal talk—how were you detained, or why were you detained
And such things
Interviewer: When they first brought you in and took you into the hall
Did you stay in the hall for three or four hours, until they brought you here?
During that time, did they give you food or drinking water?
During that time in the hall?
In the hall, no
Only at dinner time they would give us that
They gave us rice and lentils
Only that, and water
Interviewer: The rice and lentils were served at dinner?
Was it served in one big bowl for the whole group, or separately for each person?
No, about four or five large bowls, they mixed the rice and lentils, and we ate
Interviewer: So as a group?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Okay, can you tell us about your psychological state?
Your condition, or how you felt when you entered this room?
What did you feel when you came to the same place today for the second time?
Is it the same place?
Did anything bring back memories, anything that happened here?
The state you were in that night you spent in this place?
A particular incident that happened to the prisoners or one of them?
Something you can't forget and still remember?
The situation was tragic, as I told you
I mean, you were living with your family and sleeping
Waking up in the morning and seeing your siblings, your father, and your wife
You started thinking about how this night would pass
You didn’t know how long you’d stay here, a night or two
You didn’t know your fate
There were small children among them, because of prayer, they would sit and cry
They’d say to you, What did we do?
That’s not even counting the fear of bombing
It was a heartbreaking situation
Interviewer: In this room, were there any video or surveillance cameras?
No, I don’t think so
There was only one direction
You couldn’t focus on anything specific
You just sat there in silence, doing nothing
Interviewer: Do you mean a candle for lighting?
Yes, a candle for lighting
In a different prison there were cameras
Interviewer: In this place, did you get to choose your spot to sit?
Or were you not allowed to sit wherever you wanted?
No, you and the prisoners
Someone helps the other to secure a spot
If your space was too small to sleep
And someone else had a larger sleeping space
He would sleep comfortably, then say to you, Go sleep over there
Interviewer: On the first morning, when you first woke up
How did you feel when you woke up and found yourself in the cell?
Honestly, I was crying
I pulled myself together, as you know there were young men sitting
It was the first time something like this had happened to me
I woke up in the morning in a strange place, I wasn’t with my family or my brothers
It’s a feeling you can’t describe
Interviewer: Was the reason for crying, fear or missing your family?
No, missing my family
There’s fear inside you
You’re afraid something might happen while you’re far away from your family
Interviewer: Do you remember an incident that happened to one of the prisoners here?
Don’t you remember?
No, there’s nothing
Interviewer: Was there a clock hanging in that place?
Was there a wall clock?
No, there wasn’t a clock
Interviewer: Wasn’t there anything else hanging on the wall?
No, there was nothing
Interviewer: Did the guards walk between the rooms or not?
One of them stood in the corridor
If you wanted to go to the toilet or ask for something
You’d call him, he’d come and open the door for you
Interviewer: And did you go out?
No, I didn’t go out
Interviewer: Was it for dawn prayer?
Yes, I went out for dawn prayer
At dinner time I’d go out to do wudu [ablution]
Interviewer: How many toilets were there?
Here
And those toilets
At dawn prayer, you have to wake up
An hour before prayer, so you get time
To get into the toilet