Tab 1
I walked in and saw around 25 people sitting here
They were sitting here, spread out here and there
The place was clean and the lights were on
And the floor was covered with carpet
They had prepared it to be a hall and a mosque
When you first enter, at the beginning, at the reception
They record your statements and so on
You sit here until another person comes
Who then distributes us into the prison cells
The hall was organized and clean, and the lights were on
And people were sitting here
Interviewer: Did you enter with your shoes on or without them?
No, when we reached the stairs, they made us take off our shoes
Interviewer: You mean everyone took off their shoes?
Yes, everyone took off their shoes
Interviewer: You said it was covered with carpet
Yes, with striped red carpet
Interviewer: So was this hall open like it is now?
Or did it have partitions and divisions?
No, it had dividers
They had divided the place with a curtain
This part wasn’t visible
Interviewer: Do you remember the exact color of the curtain?
It was indigo, fading into black almost
Interviewer: Was there any sponge mattress to sit on?
No, there was no sponge mattress, we sat on the floor
Interviewer: You said this was a temporary detention center, or a mosque?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: How did you know it was a mosque?
There was a prayer rug
There was a prayer rug here
And people were sitting, and when prayer time came
It was covered with carpets specific to mosques
So it was obvious it was a mosque
Interviewer: Did you pray here in this place?
Yes, I prayed here
Interviewer: During your entire stay here, two days and one night
Were all your prayers here?
No, they took us down to pray here
Interviewer: Was the imam from among you prisoners?
Or was he one of their men?
No, he was one of their men
Interviewer: Can you describe to me how you prayed?
And what direction the qibla was?
The qibla was in this direction
The qibla this way, and the rows were like this
The qibla was like this
Interviewer: So it was tilted at an angle?
Yes, it was tilted at an angle, not straight ahead
Interviewer: Don’t you remember how many prayer rows there were when you prayed?
When we entered, the 25 people
After the call to prayer we prayed
They would bring some of the others but not all of them
The sick and others prayed upstairs
And whoever couldn’t go down because of torture
Stayed upstairs and prayed there
At dawn prayer time
You had to wake up an hour before the prayer
Wait your turn to go to the toilet and then do wudu [ablution]
Finish wudu then come to pray
Interviewer: Do you mean that all the time you were in prison you prayed here?
Yes in this place
Interviewer: I will ask you a question
Interviewer: Did they force you to perform the obligatory prayer? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did they force you to perform the voluntary prayer?
Meaning, did they force you to perform it or was it up to you?
No, it was up to you, but when you first entered you had to show you did the voluntary prayers
Yes, you had to pray the ones before and after
And he would lead us in their special duaa [supplication] that could last up to 15 minutes
Interviewer: What do you mean by duaa? Witness: Their special supplication prayer
“O God, grant us victory over those who are hostile to us”... and so on
Interviewer: Was this during group prayer? Witness: Yes in every prayer
Interviewer: Was it the imam who made the supplication? Witness: Yes him
The reason was that they didn’t want any prisoner to be the imam
They wanted one of their own to lead the prayer and the duaa
Interviewer: So this supplication that you called duaa
Do you remember specific words from it?
Yes, like, “O God grant us victory... O God deal with so-and-so”
Yes, “O God deal with America... O God deal with the apostates”
And all of those words
Interviewer: Was this supplication repeated at every prayer?
Yes, it was repeated at every prayer
Interviewer: And were you required to respond behind him?
Yes we were required to, and you had to raise your hands and say Amen loudly
Interviewer: Describe to me how the prayer was, and the supplication
I stood here and the imam stood there
And he raised his hands and made supplication
And you said, O God Amen
While some of them stood behind the windows
Looking through to see who among us didn’t raise his hands
And whoever didn’t say Amen, they held him accountable
Interviewer: Was this at every prayer?
Yes, at every prayer
Interviewer: Was the duaa at every prayer? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Okay, if someone didn’t raise his hands and say Amen
Was he held accountable, or did everyone raise their hands?
You had to raise your hands, you were forced to
Like I told you, one stood here and another there
Watching us while we prayed
And whether someone wasn’t supplicating sincerely
Interviewer: The imam was the one who made the supplication
And you behind him said Amen
Do you remember if he cried? Or was he pretending to cry? Or was he not crying?
He was pretending to be devout and that he was supplicating from the bottom of his heart
Sometimes his voice went down and sometimes he raised it
Interviewer: Was the imam from Mosul?
Or was he from the clans, or from other nationalities?
No, he was from the clans
Interviewer: Do you mean he was not from Mosul?
No, he didn’t speak with the Moslawi accent
Interviewer: In this prison, were there no people from Mosul?
Witness: Yes, there were
Interviewer: As ISIS guards?
Do you mean ISIS members? No, there were none
None of them spoke in our Moslawi accent
But there were people from Mosul among them
But not here, I did not see them here in this hall
Interviewer: How many prayers did you pray in this hall?
When I came, I did not pray the noon prayer because I was late
I prayed the afternoon, sunset, and night prayers
And the dawn prayer, then we left before the noon prayer
Interviewer: Do you mean four prayers?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did you perform all four prayers in congregation?
Yes, and the duaa [supplication] of qunoot
Interviewer: Was it the same imam?
Witness: No, it changed
There were two or three of them
Each one led us in prayer
Interviewer: Were there Qurans or chairs in this hall?
There were no chairs, but there were Qurans
Interviewer: Were there cameras filming you?
And was there a flag of theirs?
I did not notice if there were cameras
But the flags were outside
And I think there was an ISIS flag here
Interviewer: You mean the banner?
Witness: Yes, their banner
Interviewer: Was there a screen where they showed their videos?
No, I didn’t see one here
Interviewer: You didn’t see one?
Witness: No, I didn’t