Tab 1
They came up to us between 9.30 and 10
They told us to go downstairs
We asked why, and they told us that the sharia judge had come to pass judgment on us
Interviewer: Did everyone in the room go down, or just you?
Yes, all of us, because we were all sentenced, and it was a Friday, and the judge does not come on Friday
The judge came, and we lined up in a queue that reached the end of the corridor
There were five or six people in front of me
He started calling our names and our charges; he had a register listing the reason for detention
He ordered the detainees to be flogged—some 20, some 50, and some 30 lashes
When my turn came, he asked my name, and I answered, Muhannad Mahmoud Saeed
I stepped forward to him, and he ordered that I be flogged 45 lashes
I turned my back to the flogger
He started flogging me from the top of my shoulders to the soles of my feet
45 lashes
Interviewer: Were your eyes open?
Witness: Yes, they were open
Interviewer: Can you describe the flogger—his manner, build, appearance, and age?
He was, at the time, between 22 and 23 years old
He had dark skin and wasn’t from Mosul
Interviewer: Do you mean from Mosul’s outskirts or from another province?
Witness: No, from the outskirts
He was dark, with a black beard, wearing their Kandahari outfit
He tucked the Quran under his armpit to lessen the harm while flogging
And we had to ask for forgiveness with every lash—they would tell us to ask for forgiveness
After the flogging, the judge told me to collect my belongings
They handed me only the money
They kept the cigarettes to smoke them—they didn’t destroy them
As for IDs, at that time I didn’t have my ID on me
They brought it for me in the afternoon, and it stayed with them
The next day I came back to collect it
I didn’t know that my family had brought it to them when they asked for it
The next day I came back to take my ID
Interviewer: When you stood in the line, how many guards were there besides the flogger?
Alongside the sharia judge there were three or four people
And others were positioned all around us
The judge was considered a big figure, and a security detail accompanied him
Interviewer: While you were standing there as the five in front of you were being flogged
At that time, didn’t you look around at the place or the building?
Did you see the shape of the building or the details in it?
We were standing there—all you can think is that you are about to be flogged
The person in front of me moved while he was being flogged, so they restarted the flogging from the beginning
He was wearing a thin, tight garment
They punished him for trimming his beard after catching him at a checkpoint called Bab al-Sham
He was punished again because of his tight garment
They told the judge that he couldn’t get his hands out to do wudu [ablution]
So the judge ordered them to repeat the flogging, causing him very great pain
Interviewer: Do you think the flogger was flogging you just in obedience to orders?
Or did he harbor hatred toward you?
Both at once
Not only as an application of religious orders, as he claimed
But he also flogs you with a kind of malice
Interviewer: Did you know him before?
No, but because you’re not a supporter or one of them, they hold a grudge against you