My name is Ahmad Khaled Ahmad
I was born in the Housh al-Biaa neighborhood
Which they also call Housh al-Kanaes [Courtyard of the Churches]
I work as a porter for wooden items
And I work as a porter for lumber
I am a resident of this neighborhood
I was born in 1975
I am 48 years old
I grew up and was raised in this neighborhood
Interviewer: What year did you first enter this church?
I came to this church when I was about 13 or 14 years old
In 1983 or 1982
I entered this church
I ate and drank here
And I joined our Christian brothers in their occasions
When their Sunday prayers came, we would come with them
We accompanied them and sat in the church
We shook hands and talked with them
They are good people, beyond description
Their essence is of gold, and I salute them from here
I swear they are people I hold above me, the Christians
Interviewer: Ahmad, your first entry into this church, for what occasion was it?
What was it for, and what ritual or event did you come to attend?
Interviewer: What do you remember?
Witness: What I remember was every Sunday
On the occasion of their prayer, as we have
Friday prayers, they had Sunday prayers
This ritual was constant in their faith
I was with them every Sunday
By God, we spent all our time in the church courtyard
We would play and move from one
church to another, we were part of them
We were part of them, to the point I knew all these churches well
There were six churches in this area
They called it Housh al-Biaa
I entered all the churches
And I joined them in religious rituals
Yes
Interviewer: I want to ask you, do you know Old Mosul?
Did you visit it regularly?
And have you visited other churches in this neighborhood?
I would like you to share these details
Witness: Yes, we went to a place
They called it Eid al-Deir
Eid al-Deir was held at a site in the Arabi neighborhood
The church was Mar Gorgis
This ritual lasted for a month in the spring
It was held in the fourth month
We would go, join them, and find a place
From early morning, five a.m.
Just to secure a spot
It was a communal meal as well as a religious ritual
That we shared with our Christian brothers, at Mar Gorgis
We entered the church and prayed with them
And supported them
We brought dolma with us and sat on a hill beside it
And their cemetery was there
We joined them in all of this
Especially in this ritual, and another ritual
Which was held at al-Tahira Church
Located near Bash Tapia
Al-Tahira Church, there are two called al-Tahira
This one and the other
That one’s ritual was held on March 21
The same as Nowruz
Which fell on that day
We joined them in their ritual
With a picnic, along with all the Christians living in Kurdistan
They came for this ritual, we joined and rejoiced
And we sat at an outdoor table
We climbed Bash Tapia with dolma and kibbeh with us
And the Christians brought tabboulleh
A favorite dish for them, as dolma and kibbeh are for us
They had tabboulleh
Tabbouleh is indescribable, even now I crave it, it was delicious
Its taste is still in my mouth
Interviewer: Did you visit the churches near this church?
Witness: Yes, I visited them
Even the people who lived there
They were also Christians and part of the church
We sat with them in the church and in their homes
We shared their food and drink and played with their kids
Church by church, I knew them
Every room in every church, I knew them
I knew all the rituals because I joined them so often
Interviewer: Ahmad, as a Muslim from Mosul
What do these memories with our Christian brothers—our partners—mean to you?
Witness: They truly are our partners, they are sincere people
Good people
No need to explain, let me give an example
They came when Ramadan arrived
Because they were so kind and friendly
There was no difference in religion, we were one, God knows
They worshiped God and we worshiped God
Our religion was one, us and them
Faithful, kind, trustworthy neighbors
True neighbors who respected rights in an indescribable way
Every Ramadan
They showed respect for Muslims
They wore headscarves
During our fasting, throughout Ramadan
When they went out to clean, they wore a scarf
Out of respect for our rituals and our Islamic faith
At iftar, they brought us dates
Whatever food they had, they shared it with us
They came to our homes and knocked on the door
They brought us dates, kibbeh, and tabbouni
That was their food
They never forgot us during Ramadan
I thank them from here, they are always in my heart
They cannot be forgotten, especially for these acts
Anyone who shared that knows their value
Christians are people worthy to keep in my eyes and above my head
Of course, they are my heart and soul