We enter the church through this door
As a sign of respect for my faith and theirs
I must touch this wall of the church, blessed
This wall is blessed
I say, in the name of the Father and the Son
And the Holy Spirit, one God, Amen
And I enter with them to the place of ritual
In this place
There were chairs here, and this was an aisle
This is the aisle we enter from
And we sit on the chairs, arranged chairs
And the priest, abouna [our father] as they call him
The priest is called abouna
Because he represents their faith
He stands on this pulpit
This is the pulpit where the priest stands
And the people sit here
There were many, you know, on feast days they came
And the priest here
Reads the Gospel
And we all stand in respect for the Gospel
We rise and stand and read a verse from the Gospel
And we read with them, then sit down
And the priest speaks to us, may God preserve him
He speaks to us about rituals
And about what is permitted and forbidden
Just like what the preacher tells us
The same, they have forbidden things, don’t approach them
Not allowed, you must respect the neighbor
He used to say beautiful words
Those words truly represented us
Because they are honest, sincere, kind people
So when those words came from their mouths, they came out beautifully
Well-ordered, caring for every good person
They had no enmity and carried no hatred toward anyone
Their advice was beautiful, and advice was important to them
Interviewer: Ahmad, do you know the purpose of these rooms?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And why were they used? Please explain
Witness: Yes, these rooms
Were a library for books, the Gospel, and the Torah
This was the library
It was a library, but sadly they burned it
This library was burned while ISIS was here
And inside it
This was a complete library
And this was the pulpit where he sat
They placed the cross
And the items used for the Mass
And the Gospel, then continued
And they placed the organ here, in this storage room
And here was the statue of Our Lady Mary
In this spot, right before my eyes
Our Lady Mary the Virgin, peace be upon her
So this was the ritual, and this was the priest’s place
Yes, I have memories
And this place was for storage
They placed the offerings here, the offering place
They fed the children and brought things to them
This is the water basin
This water was placed here to baptize children
They wiped the child
So he became a Christian
Just like they purified us when we were children
This was their purification
They baptized the child, and when he came out,
they placed a sour-sweet candy in his mouth
And that is how he was baptized and became a Christian