In the summer there was...
Just as our Muslim neighbors taught us the Quran
They also had in summer
Their children came to learn the Gospel
They taught them the Gospel and we joined them
Interviewer: In what place did this happen?
Witness: It was during the summer vacation
When there were no schools
They came from 10 in the morning
Until 12 noon, for two hours
They had this ritual
They taught them the Gospel in the churches
In the churches themselves, all churches opened on these days
They taught them the Gospel in the summer vacation
Interviewer: Were the ones leading these rituals priests?
The church choir? Relatives? Who were they?
Witness: All the neighborhoods, the same area
Just as they had school study
They had a summer ritual, going to study the Gospel
And there was crowding like at school
There was recess and they went out to the church
And they brought them cake and chocolate
After every half hour they had a 10 minute break
Like recess in school
Also you had a recess after every half hour
They had this thing in the church
They taught the Gospel
To children and schools during the summer vacation
Interviewer: I want you to describe the place
When you used to come to it
You have memories there
What did you remember when you came to this place?
What do you remember was in this place?
Can you describe for us the furniture in each room?
I hope you go back in your memories a little and describe it to us
Witness: This church
We are now talking about the Armenian Church
I enter from this door
The cleanliness was indescribable
And the appearance was indescribable
You entered and they had chairs
Arranged neatly, the chair was like a couch
We called it a couch but it was thinner than a couch
They were in rows
One, two, up to about 20 couches
People sat on them
And this was the entrance passage
And on the opposite side also couches
We entered and sat
It was indescribable with the lights
This proof, these chandeliers
These chandeliers, this chandelier and that
This was their dome
You had the pulpit above
This was where the priest went up
He gave a sermon from it
Sometimes, there was no space here
He went up
To speak to the women
The saint and the priest both went up and spoke from this pulpit when there was crowding
He came out here, they stood there, and he raised his voice so they heard him
Like our sermon pulpit
This was their pulpit
These chandeliers lit in an indescribable way
And always chocolate was their symbol
Chocolate was a symbol for them
And they had candy they called sweet and sour, with a mint flavor
Mint like what we used to call alouja before
This was their type of mint
They offered it as a blessing to the children
They purified them and brought them close
And put the chocolate here
There was no one
Who entered this place
When you entered, before sitting down
You came and took a piece of chocolate and ate it
Then you sat there
They welcomed you with a beautiful spirit
It was a church, I do not know how to describe it to you
Beautiful and painful memories
So many, I cannot remember them all because of their number
As many as they were, I feel sorrow