This building was housing for the church guards
And the administration for the priest and clergy
There were also rooms here by the corner
They were for orphans, given to them by the priests
They made sure the children lacked nothing in these rooms
This was a place for one family, sometimes three or four families
Here is the hall, and these are the rooms
About three families lived in them
The priests would house poor Christian families here
They brought them into the churches
To serve the house of God
And they also had
This church
And these rooms, plus the toilet and showers
One room, two rooms, then a third and a fourth
With an annex on the roof, a storage space upstairs
And here was another hall
For the guard, his name was Abu Janet
He was originally from Lebanon
He lived in this church and served it
They used to call him Abu Janet
This was his place and his home
And this other place was the residence and office of the priests
The most famous resident of this church
Was the priest they called abouna [our father]
This was his main residence, with two rooms and an annex
With a bathroom and toilet, reserved for the priest
The one they called abouna, servant of the church
Interviewer: Ahmad, you pointed to these rooms
Do you know what was inside them?
Witness: Rooms where they slept
A room for sitting
And a dining room
Sometimes used for rituals during holidays
The household would receive
Visitors from other churches
They would welcome them
Guests came and were given gifts for the holiday
Yes, they gave out gifts
They helped one another
This room was for sitting
That one for sleeping
And this larger room was like a guest room
When there was a meeting of priests
A large hall, not for the guard
If you can see it from here, you can film it
It was like a guest room, for meetings of priests
Like the gatherings they held
It was a big hall
These were the houses of guards serving the church
And this was their conference hall
They called it the hall, it had a full set of couches
During meetings, priests came and sat here
This was the corridor
And these windows, this was a big hall
Their council hall for priestly meetings
And this wall
Beyond it were churches, called Housh al-Biaa
Which was made up of five churches
This was the conference hall for priests and the church
Interviewer: What was here exactly?
Witness: There were rows of chairs
Like an office, this was the church’s administration
There were rows of chairs here and there
And another row here
A desk here, like a director’s desk
A desk with a swivel chair
He sat here, this was the church administration office
Chairs placed here and there, priests gathered for meetings
The leader, the priest they called abouna
Was in charge, with a desk where he wrote, with papers and books
Interviewer: Did they perform rituals here?
Witness: No, no rituals, just meetings and rest after prayers
They practiced their faith, asked questions, and learned from each other
Religious teaching, for example one priest teaching a new one
So Father taught him, saying this is the religion
He gave him knowledge in faith