This room
The seating area for the church attendants
This was their quarters; two families lived here
They gave this place to a family
With an annex, a kitchen
This is the wash basin area
This is a wash basin
This used to be a kitchen; they used to call it an iwan [portico]
But the church attendants used it
We call them guards, but they were the church attendants
Unfortunately, this piece used to cover them
And this is another room
This one was for sitting
And this one was for sleeping—they used to sleep in it
It had a wardrobe and a television
Here in this room
And in that room there was a sofa of the kind they call Abbasi style
Abbasi sofas, two of them, one here and another there
They used to sleep on them
They were few in number—there were two children, the father, and the mother
They totaled four people
And here, this other one
These stairs take you to a storeroom
It is a small room
They used to store in it
The items the household did not need
Those who lived here, the church attendants
Up above there is a loft, which we call a beitouna [loft]
We call it a beitouna—they used to put the air cooler there
And in summer, the heaters
Like a small storeroom belonging to the house
And you have this room
This room belonged to the other church attendant
This was their sitting room, and they called it the guest room
They used to put a sofa in this spot
A sofa here and another there, and the television was in this spot
The television was not like plasma screens
There was a table and the old TV set
They placed it there, and inside the table there was a VCR and CDs
This room
They generally did not use sofas
They preferred the Abbasi-style wooden benches they liked
So they placed benches here, three benches
Interviewer: Ahmad, what did the benches look like? Can you explain?
The bench was made of wood
They called it a takht [wooden bench]—now you see it in cafés
This heritage style reappeared, and people use it now
When you sit in a café
In the past, they did not sit on metal
Like these days when they sit on metal
So they prefer wood because it is healthier
Wood was healthy
And it looks nice
So they would set out the benches
He would sit here, place a bench and sit, a bed
In the past, they did not make sofas
Technology was not common at that time
Interviewer: What year was that?
Witness: In the eighties and nineties
Yes, most of what I am telling you was in the eighties
Because in the eighties
From the start of my awareness, I grew up with them in those days
These are the days I told you about
They are the ones I remember, the best days I spent with them
From the eighties until 1993 and 1994
They are days beyond description
Interviewer: How old were you at that time?
Witness: I was born in 1975
I am 49 years old
In 1987 I was about 12 or 13 years old
I was a first- or second-grade student in primary school
Since I was seven years old
I was with them—my awareness formed in this place
I was born here
I was born in Souq al-Sha'ar, here in Housh al-Bayaa
I belong to this area
I was influenced by them, and my school was with them, the Tahdhib School
The school that was once a church
They used it in summer as a church
And on the other side, it was a school
And from the other street, it was a church
It was all aligned, a church and a school
Tahdhib School was mixed
We were Muslims and Christians there, boys and girls
Look at the trust and affection that existed among us
How kind people there were
I swear to you, how it was
This room was for sitting and for guests
And this other room
Was a sleeping room for the guard assigned to this church
This room was their sleeping quarters
Be careful so you do not fall here
So the cameraman is not affected by the obstacles
Because of the stones and traces of the explosion
Sir, they used this room for sleeping
For living and sleeping—they used to eat in it
And that room, I told you, was where the television was
The place for the guests who came to them
Because he was a servant of the church
Each of them had a room
There were two guards, two attendants of the church
That house was for one of them
And this house for the other—that was for the sake of God
They helped the poor and the humble needy
They would bring them to the churches, give them homes, and help them
They feared the Lord of the Worlds and upheld people’s rights in a beautiful way
Interviewer: Ahmad, these details you mention were from the eighties
After the fall in 2003
Did these rooms change and become something else?
Witness: Yes, they changed, but only a slight change
After 2003, they changed slightly
But after these wars and circumstances occurred
A severe change happened, a radical change
A severe change because of the war and its effects
Because of the crimes that happened and the killing
They were erased and forgotten
They had almost ended in those days