During ISIS’s presence
Unfortunately, this holy church
They would turn it into a prison or commit crimes in it
Isn’t this God’s house, where Christians speak the name of God?
And remember their religion there
Why do you do this in the homes of people you have wronged?
This church became a prison, they turned it into a prison
Unfortunately, a prison
When the Christians were here, it was a place of freedom
They were free, they welcomed you warmly
You would sit in their religious rituals
There is a vast difference between those who welcomed you and those who turned the place into a prison
And a place of misery for people
Where people are flogged and killed
I do not know how to describe it to you, it is hard
The Christian community is the opposite of them
And look at how they are
How the Christians used to welcome you, they would treat you like a guest of honor
They give you chocolate, you sit, and they bring you cold water
The priest welcomes you
Those others were committing crimes
You see the ugliest scenes
The prisoner, the one whose eyes are blindfolded, whose hands are shackled
In this church
How that welcomed people, and how this one receives people
Look at the vast difference
Interviewer: Ahmad
After ISIS left Mosul
When was the last time you visited this place?
Meaning after ISIS left the city
Witness: Four months after the liberation
We came to visit this area, to our homes
As soon as I came from this street by Shaareen Market
There was a checkpoint there
Here there was nothing
So I would not go that way
I came in here and went out from this place
This place was open before they built the churches
I went in through the churches, and I was moved by them
Before I went to my house, I had not gone home yet
I swear, I came straight here
Interviewer: I want you to describe how you felt
My feelings, God is my witness, I cried
I cried and first remembered their conduct
And second, I saw the churches destroyed
And I used to take part in their rituals
They do not deserve this to happen to them, they do not deserve it
They are kind, peaceful, and trustworthy people
They respected you and treated you like a guest of honor
And then you, ISIS member, come and treat them like this, and destroy the churches
This is not right, you have wronged them severely
It cannot be described, I swear to you
I was affected by it, I walked while crying
Even though no one could see me
When no one sees a person, he does not feel ashamed, so he cries
So I climbed over the rubble and stones
And after that I did not go to my house
I came to see my house, but I came from here
I entered by the Old Bridge as a shortcut through the churches
And I came to Shaareen Market
I went in through the churches, and I saw them destroyed
My heart burned, and I cried intensely, and I was affected by it
I felt deep anguish, I was deeply affected
Interviewer: Before we conclude
I want you to tell me, do you think the congregation of this church
Or the people who were responsible for it
Will they be able to move beyond this painful period
In the building’s history and create new memories?
Witness: Yes, they can, because they have patience
They have suffered
And their anguish grew intense
They were subjected to severe injustice
So with their morale and their patience
And with their beautiful faith
It will return gradually, it will not return quickly
They are sincere—they will rebuild it with their resolve and their shoulders
With their words and their way
With their sincerity and their honesty
Remember my words, these churches will return
And they will do an even better job, God willing
Just as Shaareen Market came back, and Sarjkhana came back
And Bab al-Saray came back
They will restore it with God’s help, just as those areas returned
Because this is their ritual and their faith
Faith should be held above all
A person must struggle for it