My name is Antranig Artin Kevorg
I was born in 1941
I was a church official
I worked as a financial accountant in the church
I worked here for twenty-five years
This church was built in 1857 in the old style
Over time, its walls collapsed
Which forced us to rebuild it in 1965
In this church we used to gather the Armenians every Friday
Interviewer: Well, Mr. Abu Mari, regarding the differences
Compared to other churches in Mosul, how was this church different?
This church was different from the other churches...
Different in name only, not in religion
Its name was the Armenian Orthodox Church, while the others
Were named Syriac Catholic or Syriac Orthodox
Or Dominican and other names
But this church was for Armenians, specifically for Armenians
This plaque on the church door was completely defaced
It is written in Armenian—The Surb Etchmiadzin [The Holy Descent of the Only-Begotten] Cathedral was built in 1857 and was renovated in 1965
Armenian Orthodox Church
It means the name of the church is Surb Etchmiadzin
What does this name mean?
In Armenia there is the mother church
It means we belong to it
It means the name Echmiadzin was left here