This is the main door of the church
Please come inside to see it
Here was the accountant
He collected money for the poor
The accountant’s place
Here there were forty seats
Twenty seats on this side and twenty on that side
The altar is here in front of you
In this state as you see it
And the changing of clothes was in that room
Interviewer: Can we go there?
Yes, please
Interviewer: Explain the details of this hall, how was it?
Tell us about every room here
This is written in Armenian
Take a picture of it
This is a verse from the Bible
Written in Armenian
It was a model church
At the top was the choir
To sing church hymns
This is how it was before
Anything you want
Interviewer: We want to film the church servant’s room. Witness: This is it
Interviewer: Shall we go there? Witness: Yes
Nothing is visible
Here they used to change clothes
And in the other room over there, the same
Interviewer: Let’s start from this room
This room was for changing clothes
You can’t see anything. It's all charred from the burning
Interviewer: You can go out through the door and talk to us
This room and that one were for the priest and the deacons
They used to change here
This is the altar
Our priest used to sit there, above
And there were twelve pictures here
Of the disciples of Christ
Pictures of Christ’s disciples
There was nothing left
As you see in front of you
It has become a place for pigeon nests
Interviewer: Where were the musical rituals held?
At the top, at the top
The hymns were up there, the religious hymns up at the top
The choir
At the top, there on the balcony
They would go up there from outside, to the top
Interviewer: The religious lessons and mourning gatherings, where were they held?
Here, in the church
Interviewer: In what place exactly?
There
They place the coffin of the deceased
And pray over him
On the third day, and on the fortieth day
The family of the deceased would come to pray
And there is the third room
It was used for baptism
The basin there was for baptism
When they wanted to baptize a child, it was done there
Interviewer: Can you explain the baptism process?
Yes, it was done in the room here
The child would be baptized
His name would be recorded by the clerks in the registers
Interviewer: In this room? Witness: Yes