Here, there are graves
I told you before, here is the grave of Dr. Patrick Jakhmashian
He was the head of the Armenian community in Mosul
And his brother Joseph Jakhmashian, and the priest
Our priest is buried here
And here there are one, two, three, four, five, six graves, all of them
And three or four graves over there, in that direction
They vandalized all of them, and the writing on them was in Armenian
They removed them all, they left nothing
Only here, there are a few words that are unclear
All the graves had Armenian writing and dates on them
Only this is left
Interviewer: Mr. Abu Ari, tell us, when were these graves established?
They are very old, they existed before I was born, I do not remember
Interviewer: You do not remember? Witness: No
Interviewer: Why have the graves become like this now?
Because of the vandals
Interviewer: Whom do you mean by vandals?
The vandals, I do not know what to tell you
Interviewer: Is this whole place graves?
Starting from here, one, two, three, four, five
These are their graves