Starting in 1915
Armenians came as migrants from Turkey
They came from Turkey via Syria, and they were received here
Dr. Patrick Jakhmashian
In this place there was no church, only halls
All the families settled here
And they would eat and drink in this place
After that they built a church in that area
Not this church; the old church was over there
And in 1969
They demolished the old church and built the new church
Our rites were held every Friday
Armenian families would gather here and perform prayers
Interviewer: Tell us more about the rites
that took place here in this spot.
Certainly, on holidays we gathered here
And on January 6 we also celebrated
On the major and minor holidays
And now the Great Fast lasts fifty days after a month
These are our rites, and after this fasting our feast will come
In Mosul, before, there were
Around 450 or 500 families
But now just one family or two
We are waiting for associations and organizations to rebuild the church
Is it reasonable for it to stay like this?
Interviewer: What is the reason for the small number of Armenian families inside Mosul?
They left; they migrated to Erbil and Duhok
So no one remained here except two families
Of course we are waiting for the church to be rebuilt so they can return
So that families come back from Duhok and Erbil to here
On that side there was a library
People would sit and read there
It had full volumes of books, but now it has been destroyed