We are Christians, Armenian Orthodox
We are committed to this legacy
The Armenian community comes to this church
It was thriving
It had pews, 40 seats
And the communion bread was there
Here is the sanctuary, this is what you see in front of you now
Now there is no one
Interviewer: What are the main differences between the Christian denominations?
What do you mean?
Interviewer: Like between Chaldean, Syriac, or Armenian?
We are different from them
The church is like other churches
But in the name and the rite there is a difference
For example, we are Armenian Orthodox
And behind us are Syriac Orthodox
And Syriac Catholics
And the Pope’s group is also present in the square
That is the difference
As for religion and politics, there is no difference
We only pray and worship
That is the difference between us
Between the churches
In 1924 we were displaced
It was Patrick’s grandfather—Dr. Patrick, his grandfather
He received them here
He sheltered them, and gave them clothing, food, and drink
For four years or five years
And we were obliged to build this church here
Interviewer: Who were the prominent figures?
The prominent figures…
Dr. Patrick Jakhmashian
Joseph Jakhmashian
Artin Arzevian
Mukhtar Khachik lived here, opposite the church
Those were the ones
I do not remember the other names
Interviewer: What is the most notable thing
That those figures you mentioned did for this place?
They are the ones who built the church
And they ran the church’s work, they did everything
Administratively or economically