This hall belongs to the church
It was for religious ceremonies
We would sit here on religious occasions
There were seats
There were control panels, lighting, and air conditioners
And the bishop’s chairs
Here was the bishop’s chair, and here was the patriarch’s chair
Now it’s as you see in front of you
Everything was here
The sofas, the carpets, and the air conditioners
And now this is all that remains
Interviewer: Mr. Abu Mari, can we talk about the time when ISIS was here?
Do you know why ISIS used this room?
No, I don’t know anything
Interviewer: No—What?
Witness: I don’t know anything about this
I don’t know what they did with it
We had left then, we were in Duhok
Interviewer: These burn marks on the walls, don’t you know what caused them?
No, no
They’re burned, but I don’t know
Interviewer: So this hall was for celebrations?
For religious celebrations
Or if visitors came from outside
Priests or bishops, we received them here