The restoration happened in 1965
From 1965 to 1969
Interviewer: Since that date
Did the restoration efforts preserve the church’s original architecture, or did they alter it?
No, they did not change anything, it remained as it was
So the church was thriving and exemplary
All the families used to come here regularly
On Fridays, and on Sundays they came
And religious holidays were observed here
That is what there was
The church was vandalized
Due to the military operations
Because of the military operations, it was shelled with rockets and other munitions
Interviewer: We mean before ISIS took control
That is, before that time
Was it subjected to destruction, war crimes, or disasters?
You mean how long before?
Interviewer: Before ISIS entered Mosul, that is, before 2013
No, no
And in particular we Armenians are known
For self-financing, and we do all the work ourselves
Through the Central Committee in Baghdad
According to our means, we managed all the churches that belong to us
In 1914
When did ISIS enter?
Interviewer: In 2014 Witness: Yes, in 2014
They stayed here for three years, in this church
I do not know what they did with it
Until it was liberated
We went in and saw the church completely wrecked
We do not know what they were doing with it
Interviewer: Okay Mr. Abu Ari, you say we do not know what happened to it
Did you not hear from anyone that they made this place
It is obvious, do you not see?
That it was for detention and holding
There must have been a court here or something like that
It is clear from the footage
A detention center belonging to ISIS, they kept prisoners here, I do not know
I do not know about it, so I cannot tell you anything, I did not see it
Interviewer: Mr. Abu Ari, who is now in charge of the restoration efforts related to the church?
And is there a plan to restore it?
We want you to tell us the details
I am responsible for the churches, buildings, and monasteries adjacent to the church
If no organizations come to rebuild, it will remain like this
And we do not have the capacity to do construction and rebuilding
Except through support from an organization
Interviewer: Okay, is there a plan for the future
Or in the coming days to restore this place?
I do not know when they will come
No one has come to us. What can I tell you?
No organization has come to us
Interviewer: What is the reason?
Only people from the Christian Endowment came
They inspected the church and the hall
And they said there was no budget available
We are waiting for the budget to be issued so they can rebuild it