My name is Aladdin Khaled Ahmad
I am from the Nabi Jirjis area
I was born in 1973
ISIS detained me over a medicines case
I stayed in this place 28 days
And 10 days in another place
The medicines were for chronic illnesses
They were not sold in pharmacies
When they exceeded what the recipients needed
They brought them to me, knowing I distributed to those in need
Things like that
I was under surveillance
I felt I was being watched
Because they were sending women to my store
For medicines, and I gave injections to people for free
Interviewer: Were the women they sent from among their members?
Yes, members of ISIS
Interviewer: Did you learn that from them, or later?
I learned later
After they detained me
I only had a feeling that they were the ones sending them
ISIS, and that was why I was detained
Interviewer: What was the source of the medicines that came to you?
It was from people who had more than they needed
Yes, from people who wanted to do good
Interviewer: Were there people who bought medicines
Interviewer: And brought them to you seeking a reward for that?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did that happen with you?
Witness: Yes, it happened
I used to work in a pharmacy
So people in the area knew me
They told anyone who wanted to donate, Take it to Abu Abd al-Rahman
He is a man who does good for people
So this was a trust I passed on seeking reward
I wanted to do good—I did not sell them
I was in the store
Two people came to me
They said, Are you Aladdin? I said, Yes
He said, Please come with us to the Hisba [morality police]
I said, What is the matter?
They said, We want to ask you some questions
They took me and brought me to this place
They interrogated me
When they brought me in, I was terrified, afraid
Because their hands were stained with the blood of innocent people
Now I would become one of those people
Interviewer: The two people who brought you here
Can you describe their appearance?
And how old were they? What was their appearance?
Were they from Mosul, based on the accent they spoke to you with?
Or were they from the outskirts of Mosul, or from other provinces?
Or were they of other Arab nationalities?
They were from different backgrounds
But the two who came to me—one was from Hadar and the other from Mosul.
So their dialect was the Moslawi dialect
They worked in the Hisba
Interviewer: Approximately how old were they?
About 40 or 45 years old
Yes, the two who took me
Interviewer: How did they treat you from the moment they took you...
until they brought you to the prison?
Very normally
They didn’t talk to me in front of people
They brought me and led me in here
And they interrogated me
Interviewer: Did they bring you on foot or by car?
Witness: No, on foot
Because the distance is short, about 10 minutes on foot
Interviewer: Was one of them holding you?
Or were you handcuffed?
No, I walked in front of them and they were behind me, armed
Interviewer: So they escorted you without anyone holding you
No, no, they didn’t do anything to me
They just told me they wanted to ask me questions
Interviewer: When they took you to the prison gate
Did those same men go in with you?
Or did they hand you over to other people?
They brought me here and then handed me over to other people
When I came, I didn’t think this was a prison
I told myself they would ask me questions
And when they’d finished, I would leave
But I was surprised that after they’d asked me questions, they detained me
Interviewer: Since you are from this area
What was this place before?
This place used to be a church
Interviewer: Do you remember having come in here before?
When the Christians were present here?
Yes, I entered this place many times
There was a cemetery there
It had graves
We came in here when we were young
We used to come here in the 80s and 90s
We came as families—us and the Christians
Interviewer: Aside from being neighbors with the Christians in the area
Did you have special relationships, like friendships, with Christians?
Which made you come to this place?
Yes, they know I have many relationships with Christians
For that reason, I imagine they asked me who was a priest, and who was in this church
And in the other church, and who lived in the archbishopric
Interviewer: When they first brought you into this place
Into this entrance—which is the entrance to the church or to the prison itself
What was there at the beginning?
How did they treat you?
And how did they treat your belongings?
Did they deal with you when they took information from you?
How was it?
They took information from me
Interviewer: What information did they take from you?
I told you, they asked me about people
What do you know about the Christians who were in this area?
Interviewer: Was this when you arrived?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: When they took your belongings
Interviewer: Did they enter your name into the computer?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did they fill out a form?
Yes, they took my personal information
My full name, and what do you do? What is your job?
What are your relations with people here in the area?
Who do you know of the Christians?
They asked me about all these things
Interviewer: After they took your belongings
Where did they take you?
They took me and we entered the hall
They interrogated me
And that coincided with prayer time
So I prayed two cycles as sunna
After that I prayed the noon prayer
In the archbishopric, then they took me back
After they took me back they took me to the detention place
To the prison upstairs
I stayed upstairs for 28 days
Interviewer: In the first moments of entering the room
Tell me what was in your mind
I thought they were going to execute me
That is what I felt
It was all terror and fear
Because every little while you hear they took someone
He might be a policeman for example, and they kill him
Another for something else, for many reasons
So I thought I would be one of the victims and be killed
I imagined I would die like them
Interviewer: How many people were with you in this room?
At first I was alone
Then a boy named Edmond came in
A Christian, as if he had converted to Islam
He stayed two days with me
Later on every two or three days they would bring one or two
He would sit two or three hours then they would transfer him
Interviewer: Regarding the person you mentioned
Edmond the Christian
How did they treat him?
Their treatment was good
Interviewer: Didn’t you learn what his charge was?
Since he was asked to surrender
And he did, why arrest him?
I was afraid to ask him
Interviewer: Didn’t you talk about this?
I was afraid because they listened to us through the windows
They walked around the yard, so we were scared to talk
Interviewer: Didn’t he try to ask you or talk with you?
No, he didn’t ask me
Interviewer: Did he show signs of torture?
No, no, he didn’t show any signs of torture
Interviewer: Didn’t they use any means of torture on him?
No, he stayed two days with me
Then they transferred him, and I don’t know where they took him
Interviewer: Where was he from?
I asked him, Are you from Mosul? He said, Yes
I still remember he was from the Aden neighborhood
He told me he lived in the Aden neighborhood
And his family had all fled to Erbil
And he had stayed here alone
Interviewer: Didn’t you ask him why he’d stayed?
I told you I was afraid to ask him
I was afraid to ask him
Because it’s possible he was with them
Interviewer: So you stayed here 28 days
And most of the time you were alone
Interviewer: In this room or cell
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: How did you spend your time here?
My time was harsh, a day felt like a year
Interviewer: Didn’t they leave you something specific to use?
Like prayers, since you were so close to death
Interviewer: Were there Qurans in the prison?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: You mean they allowed them?
Witness: Yes, yes
I had a Quran to read and I prayed normally
I made duaa [supplication] and prayed
I fulfilled my duty of worshipping God Almighty
I prayed to God to free me, to let me out and get rid of them
Interviewer: How did you spend the night?
I spent it terrified
It was all horror and fear
Interviewer: While you were in this room at night
Did you imagine they would come to you?
Yes, I imagined they would come to me
Interviewer: Can you describe this state to us?
I imagined it to myself
I told myself that after 10 minutes
Or after an hour or two or at midnight
They would call me, take me, and execute me
Just like the others they executed
They planted horror and fear in my heart
And this continues even now, as I talk to you
As I speak with you now, I feel they are here
Interviewer: Did you sleep very little?
Witness: Yes, very little
Interviewer: Do you mean because of overthinking and fear?
Yes, it is the thinking that exhausted me
And I still take psychiatric medication to this day
Interviewer: Given that you were alone in this place
Did you find yourself not wanting to sleep out of fear
That they would execute you while you slept?
Yes, I felt afraid
Interviewer: So you tried not to sleep?
Yes, I tried not to sleep for fear they would kill me while I slept
Interviewer: Was that imagination?
Or did it reflect a real feeling inside you?
It was a real feeling
Interviewer: Have you heard of such a thing happening?
Yes, they executed many people
There’s the Khasfa sinkhole
How many innocent people they threw into it
More than 5,000, maybe up to 10,000
Interviewer: You were alone, so surely you stayed silent the whole time
Did you have moments when you reflected during detention?
Did you remember things and then sit and cry?
Yes, I cried, I did not feel relief except after I’d cried
Interviewer: Did this happen often?
Witness: Yes, very often
Very often, about once or twice daily
I remembered my children and my wife
I said to myself, I will not see them anymore
Because they will execute me and my story will end
And all my thoughts were of my children, my wife, and my home
Interviewer: While you were in solitary confinement for 28 days
Except for two nights when the Christian was with you
How did they treat you throughout this period?
It was ordinary treatment
Interviewer: Was their speech harsh?
There was shouting and so on
Like, come here and go there, in a shouting tone
And sometimes not
They would tell me, for example, get up, Abu Abd al-Rahman, it is time for prayer
Interviewer: Did this treatment differ from one jailer to another?
Yes, it did, that is true
Interviewer: So there was a jailer who respected you and called you Abu Abd al-Rahman?
Yes, there were those who called me that
Some of them respected me, and some did not
Interviewer: Which jailers were more respectful to you?
Those who were from Mosul
Interviewer: Do you mean Mosul residents affiliated with them?
Yes, from Mosul, they were respectful
But the Arabs from the districts and subdistricts were not respectful
They had all come out of prisons
Their bodies were tattooed, and so on
Interviewer: So they were hard on you?
Witness: Yes
Yes, their speech was harsh toward people
Because they are criminals
Interviewer: Did you try to deal with them
And ask them to bring you something from outside the prison?
And if so, did they refuse?
Did you try to give them a certain sum of money?
So they would provide you a certain need or a comfort?
Yes, sometimes I needed biscuits or other things from outside
Or drinks and the like, and they would buy them for me
I gave them money through the door slot to go, they would buy for me and return
Interviewer: Wasn’t your money with the deposited belongings they took from you?
The deposited belongings, which were my ID card and watch
Were with them in the trailer
Only the money was in my pocket
Interviewer: Didn’t they take the money from you?
Witness: No, they didn’t take it
I had money in my pocket
When I needed something, I asked their permission
And I said, sir, I want something
Could someone go to the grocery and buy for me
They would go, buy it for me, and bring it to me
Interviewer: Didn’t he get annoyed with you when you asked him?
I didn’t ask just anyone
I asked the one who could tolerate me
Interviewer: Did you feel comfortable with any of the jailers?
In case a conversation happened between you
No, no, because I was afraid of them
Interviewer: Didn’t they try to reassure you, for example, and make you talk?
No, frankly you will not feel reassurance with them
Interviewer: Since you were in solitary, did you have a sense...
Of the people they brought for several hours, meaning for a short time?
Did they send in one of their members as a spy?
Or did they assign people to question you or interrogate you inside?
Sometimes I felt that
I said to myself it is possible they would send one of the prisoners
To lure me with his questions, and I would answer them
I was careful of them
Interviewer: Were there rooms next to you from which you heard voices?
Yes, I heard voices from here
There were some in the back
And in Mar Yousef Church
But we did not hear their voices because they were a bit far
They would bring them here
When they whipped here, I heard the sound
They would bring whoever had prayer beads, or the like
They held them accountable by flogging them here
Whoever they caught because of cigarettes
Or because of a satellite dish
They would punish them here, flogging them
Interviewer: Okay, regardless of the flogging that happened during the day
Did you hear sounds of torture at night?
Interviewer: Like screams from prisoners, for example? Witness:
Yes, a little
Interviewer: What were those sounds like?
When they caught someone who worked in the police
Or in the National Guard, for example, or in the army
They would bring him in, ISIS’s security group
From his screaming, it was clear they were beating him
Because we heard the sound from the window
Interviewer: Do you mean you didn’t see anyone being tortured?
Interviewer: And you, were you not tortured in this prison?
Witness: No
Interviewer: So only the sounds you heard…
No, I didn’t see anything, they didn’t take me anywhere
Rice and broth, they brought it ready in foam plates
In the morning they brought us tahini and sammoun [bread roll]
And sometimes they brought pieces of cheese with it
That was in the morning, and at night they brought dinner
Interviewer: Did they bring rice and broth daily?
They varied it—it wasn’t the same food every day
Interviewer: How many pieces of sammoun did they bring per day? Witness: Two in the morning
At noon, one piece with a plate of rice and a cup of broth
Interviewer: So they didn’t mix them together?
Witness: No
Interviewer: And what about dinner?
At dinner they sometimes brought sammoun and cooked chicken
They gave us the leg of the chicken, or the wing, or something else
Interviewer: Was the food enough?
Witness: Yes, it was enough
When a person is in prison, he won’t crave food because of the worry
Interviewer: Tell me honestly, was it enough? Witness: Yes, it was fine
Interviewer: Was the quality good or bad? Witness: It was bad
Interviewer: Did it come hot or cold?
They brought it sometimes hot and at other times cold
Meaning they brought it from far away
Interviewer: Did it ever happen that they asked you what you like to eat?
No, they didn’t ask me
If a person wanted to buy food
He would tell the jailer he craved food from outside
Like kebab or something else
When the market was open
They would bring us from the guy called Hazem
I twice asked to buy kebab from him
Half a portion for one person
Two skewers were enough for me, two pieces
Interviewer: When you sent someone to buy food or what you needed
Was the ISIS member you sent
Bargaining with you to take an amount of money in return for that?
I would tell him, If you’re hungry, get yourself food with mine
And he would say to me, No, they don’t accept that
Interviewer: Did he take an amount above the price of what he brought?
No, he brought it at the same price
Interviewer: Didn’t it happen sometimes that someone asked you for a bribe?
No, not at all
Interviewer: For example to connect you with your family by a phone call
No, but sometimes I would send him to my house
To bring me medicine
That happened twice—I sent him to bring me medicine
And his name was Abu Taha
Interviewer: Who is this Abu Taha?
He is one of their members
Interviewer: Did you know him before? Witness: No
Interviewer: And when he did that
By going to your house to bring you the medicine
It was a kind act from him
Interviewer: Did he do that on their orders or on his own?
No, on his own. Wasn’t he the jailer responsible for the room?
During his shift I would ask him to go, because he knew the house, it was nearby
Anyone from the street could have gone to bring it for me
I used Angised and Isordil, heart medications
Interviewer: In this case, did your family know you were detained?
But they didn’t know in which place exactly
Interviewer: So he didn’t tell them your location?
Witness: No, he didn’t tell them
Interviewer: During your 28 days
Did you need a doctor, or for a nurse to come to you?
Did a doctor actually visit you?
No, I know what I suffer from
And the treatment I take
Interviewer: Regardless of your knowledge of what you suffer from
Did their schedule include a doctor visiting you from time to time?
Yes, they asked us if we needed a doctor
So they could take us to him
If you felt your blood pressure was high, for example, or something like that
But I didn’t ask them for this
Interviewer: You mean there was understanding of your health condition
And special consideration for you
Yes, they knew that
Interviewer: Regarding the food
Was there any kind that harmed you and they still brought it to you?
Or did they not bring it to you because you told them it harmed you?
No, the food they brought didn’t harm me
If there was fat, I wouldn’t eat it
For example, I would eat the bread and the chicken thigh
And I wouldn’t eat the rest
Because I suffered from high blood lipids, and until now
Interviewer: Didn’t it happen one day that they asked you
About this food, whether it was beneficial or harmful to you?
And did they try to bring you something that would help you and not harm you?
They asked me, and I told them this doesn’t harm me
Interviewer: So they asked you?
Witness: Yes, they asked me
Interviewer: Do you think you had some kind of special care in the prison?
Not like the treatment of others
Interviewer: Considering they placed you in a place by yourself
It was like that somewhat
Interviewer: Was that because of your age?
Or because they expected you would be with them and help them
Yes, it was for that reason
Meaning because they needed me, and they wanted me to join them
This good treatment, they wanted from it in return
To motivate you and urge you to join them
Yes, it was like that
Interviewer: Is that it?
Witness: Yes, I felt that
In the morning when I woke up and wanted to go to the toilets
They allowed me to go there to relieve myself and return
And as for bathing, it was twice a week
On Mondays and Thursdays we had the right to bathe
And they gave us ten minutes or a quarter hour to bathe
Interviewer: When you relieved yourself, did you do so comfortably?
Or did you feel you were being watched?
When I entered the toilets, I felt I was being watched
Interviewer: And were you actually watched, or was it just a feeling?
It was a feeling
Interviewer: So you weren’t watched?
Witness: No, I wasn’t watched
But it was my feeling because the toilets were adjacent to the prison
It was next to the parking area, and the jailer stood outside next to the toilets
Interviewer: Regarding cleanliness in the prison
Did they give you cleaning supplies to clean the room?
Yes, they gave us some
Interviewer: Were they available regularly?
Yes, available—they gave us Dettol and a bucket of water
Every two days we wiped the room
Interviewer: Was the cleaning time mandatory on a certain day?
Every two days we had the task of cleaning the room
We did the cleaning inside the room
Interviewer: Was hot and cold water available in the showers?
Yes, they heated the water for us to bathe with
They gave us a bucket of water with about 50 liters of water
We bathed with it—we had to finish within 10 minutes to a quarter hour
Interviewer: Did they distribute underwear to you?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Didn’t they give you other clothes?
When I sent them to bring me the medicine
My family sent me underwear and pajamas
Interviewer: Was bringing them in normal?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did they not allow visits in the prison?
No, they didn’t allow anyone to do that, and my family knew that
Interviewer: Okay, in these 38 days
28 days in this prison and 10 days in another prison
How many times did you go to interrogation and to the judge?
Witness: Twice
Interviewer: And was the judge the same both times?
No, they were different people in each interrogation
Interviewer: So the first interrogation happened in the hall?
Witness: Here
Interviewer: And where did the other one happen?
It happened at the archdiocese
Interviewer: What did he ask you about specifically at the archdiocese?
He asked me about the matter of the medicines as well
And as I told you, he asked me about the people present here
Whom you know, and who was in this church
And who the priest is, about his family, his children, and his brothers, and what you know
And whom you know among the Christians who left
I told him, All the Christians left—none remained
Some remained who had converted to Islam
Among them this Saadallah, the restaurant owner
He converted to Islam out of fear, and stayed here
Then he went to Baghdad and returned to his religion again
Interviewer: Did they try to get information from you, not only about the Christians?
But about their money, their houses, and their properties in the area
And details about things they couldn’t know, for example
They asked me about the graves of the Christians
About the burial place of the priests
I told them, In Mary Church
The tomb is in the church in the Qasan area
I know that because I participated with them, as they were my neighbors
They have intelligence and information and know everything
They know what the child playing in the street is doing
Interviewer: Were you surprised by these questions?
Witness: Yes, of course I was surprised
Interviewer: These questions they asked you that surprised you
What did they leave you with exactly during the interrogation?
I became fearful, terrified
Because they frighten people
Interviewer: Did they use threats with you during the interrogation?
Yes, to some extent
Interviewer: What did he say to you, for example?
He said, Speak, Hajj, about what you know
Better than us asking you
So I told them what I had
So that they wouldn’t be the ones asking me
Interviewer: What did he ask you specifically?
They asked me, What is your job?
And who comes to you, and who sits with you?
And what do you know about ISIS
Out of fear I told them that ISIS is good
And there’s nothing wrong with it, and you are an Islamic state
Things like that
And I was terrified of them
Interviewer: From the questions they asked you
It appears they knew many details about you
Did they beat you or insult you while questioning you?
Or did any of the members standing behind you
Attempt to deal with you with a weapon or by using a sharp instrument?
Or did anything specific happen during their interrogation of you?
No, from when they took me to Mar Yousef Church
I overstepped a little in speaking with them
So one of them pushed me
And I told you when I fell on the stairs
Because there were stairs
This fall still affects me
I have pain in my back and legs
Interviewer: What caused the problems during the conversation?
Because they brought me in unjustly
I mean, I hadn’t committed a crime to be imprisoned, or anything like that
And I knew I had done nothing and that I was innocent
When my imprisonment dragged on
I asked them, What is the reason for my imprisonment?
They told me, You know everything. But I didn't know anything
I had suspicions that they wanted me to work with them
And I would not work with them, and I stayed that way, thank God
Interviewer: Did they ask you to work with them directly?
No, but through their questions it became clear they wanted me to work with them
Interviewer: What did he say to you, for example?
He said, For example, we have wounded people. Can you insert an IV cannula for them?
Or give them injections
I told them I don't have a license to do that, and I was afraid, and so on
And that I had sworn not to give an injection to anyone
Interviewer: So they asked you to help them according to your medical specialty?
Yes, but I didn't leave them any room for that and I didn't work with them
Interviewer: So they didn’t ask you to join them and pledge allegiance directly?
Yes, not directly
I felt they wanted me to work with them
But I didn't give them any room and I didn't work with them
Interviewer: After they’d completed the interrogation with you in this hall inside this building
Where did they take you after that?
They took me to a holding house, which was the house of Raed Jobbo
Which was basically a house used as a prison
They put us into a religious course for 10 days
After these 10 days
My detention then totaled 38 days, then they released me
I told you I stayed here 28 days
Then they moved me to that house, which was also a prison
I stayed there 10 days
In those 10 days they put me in a course of religious instruction and tawhid
When the 10 days ended they released us
Interviewer: When they transferred you to the other prison and you stayed there 10 days
Were you by yourself, or were you with a group?
No, I was with a large group, more than 30 people, roughly
Interviewer: Had those people been imprisoned for a long time?
Some for 10 days, some stayed a month, others eight days
It depended on each person's case
Interviewer: Can you tell me the charges they were accused of?
One of them because of birds
And another because of cigarettes
And another they caught while he was smuggling cigarettes in a car
His name was Khalil
Various charges, most for smoking
Interviewer: Considering there was a group of people during those 10 days
And you had come out of solitary to a prison with a group
How were your relationships? And how did you spend your days and nights together?
It was normal, we talked freely
And when the time for the lessons came
We went out and sat in the house courtyard. We sat in pairs, and they taught us
Interviewer: In that prison where you stayed 10 days
Interviewer: And you were 30 people?
Witness: Yes, more than 30
Interviewer: What were their ages, roughly the youngest to the oldest?
There were 18-year-olds, and there were 40-year-olds
And there were 50-year-olds—there were various ages
Interviewer: Because of this difference between ages, between young and old
And because of differences in mindsets and backgrounds
Were there quarrels or problems between them, or between one group and another, while you were there?
No, no problems happened between the prisoners at all
On the contrary, we got along and liked each other
Everyone helped each other
If someone was hungry and had no food, another gave him some of his food
We ate together, for example
If someone had a headache we gave him a painkiller tablet
That was how it was
Interviewer: How did they treat you there as a group?
When you were by yourself, you had special care
Was the care the same there?
Yes, there was care
And they had a person there
He was responsible for something like a pharmacy
Meaning he was from ISIS
He had a set of medicines that he gave to anyone suffering from something
They had medications for headaches or heart conditions
It was in the hallway, like a small pharmacy
Interviewer: Were you allowed to move around inside there?
It is a small house
We wandered in its courtyard or in the room—nothing more than that
Interviewer: Was it allowed to go out to the courtyard at any time?
Yes, the room doors were open, and the house was fortified from the outside
Interviewer: How many guards were there?
Witness: Five guards
Interviewer: How did they treat you?
It was fine, not bad
Interviewer: Were their nationalities or accents those of Mosul locals and Bedouins?
Or were they only from Mosul?
They were mixed—two of them were from Diyala, as I recall
And three were from the outskirts of Mosul
Interviewer: Was the food there like it was here?
Yes, they brought us the same food
Interviewer: Was there any discrimination between one prisoner and another, or not?
No, everyone was equal
Interviewer: You said there was a small pharmacy
Yes, it was small, for whoever needed a painkiller tablet
Or, for example, someone with a sore throat, they gave him a capsule
They dispensed the medicine for him normally
Interviewer: This place is indeed a prison
But as a prison, did you feel there was special care?
Or was that, as you mentioned, because they needed
To ask you and others to join them?
It was varied because each person had a different case
Interviewer: Since you were now with a group of prisoners
How did you spend your nights and days with them?
It was normal—it was better than here
Interviewer: Tell me about your life and the times you spent in the prison
We used to talk most of the time
We got to know each other and asked where people lived, for example
And we talked about religion in case they were listening
They would know we were talking about religion
We talked about religious stories and such things
We spent time like that
Interviewer: Do you think there were spies among you from their personnel?
Or did they bring in people who volunteered to act as spies and pass information
I don't know—I don't think so
I don't think any of their members were among the prisoners
Do you remember particular stories that happened during your imprisonment there over the 10 days?
Or a specific person's story you still remember
Or a story that affected you that you still remember
And it hurts when you remember it
Or a case of a particular person that happened in front of you?
Or a particular injustice?
It was all injustice
Because we were all unjustly imprisoned
Can someone be imprisoned because of cigarettes?
It was all injustice, like the one they brought because of cigarettes
And the one they brought and flogged because he’d said a word outside to his friend
Trivial things
Interviewer: Weren't there any charges more serious than cigarettes?
Or did they bring someone unjustly when he didn’t even have cigarettes?
Most of them were family matters
Meaning they would also bring someone who had a problem with his wife, or whose voice was loud
Interviewer: They hear his voice and then bring him?
Someone files a complaint against him
Meaning they had operatives everywhere
For example, they hear that someone blasphemed, so they bring him
Or if someone blasphemes, they would behead him on the spot
Interviewer: How did you spend your time in the prison?
They gave us papers containing religious material to memorize
Quranic verses and suras, and tawhid material to memorize
And instruction, and such things
Interviewer: Did you memorize them as lessons?
Yes, they asked us in the morning when we woke up
Interviewer: So lessons and homework?
Witness: Yes
They gave us three or four pages of paper
We memorized them and in the morning we answered their questions
No one is unaware of these things
Everyone knows the Ibrahimiyya prayers
We all had them memorized
Interviewer: So it was like a school
Witness: Yes, almost
Interviewer: What kind of lessons were they?
And who was the person who taught you?
Was it the same person who came every time?
Yes, it was the same person and his name was Abu Muhammad
Interviewer: Was it the same one who came daily? Didn't someone else come?
No, the same one came
Interviewer: Can you describe to me what he looked like?
Was he actually a teacher by profession, or did he teach in a mosque?
Yes, he was a teacher
He was a teacher and about 40 years old
He had great knowledge of religion
He asked us and encouraged us
To memorize and read the Quran
Interviewer: What was the type of lessons exactly?
Were the lessons related to jurisprudence and matters of purification, prayer, and creed?
Or were there lessons you think they intended to push you to pledge allegiance?
Were they advising you to pledge allegiance?
And did they try to show you they were in the right, and so on?
Was that the case?
Yes, that's right—those things were there
Interviewer: How so? What did they ask you, for example?
And how did they deal with you on this matter?
Honestly I don't know what to say to you
Meaning they wanted us to join them
Interviewer: Through the lessons?
Witness: Yes, through the lessons
Interviewer: Through the lessons, did you receive an explicit call to pledge allegiance?
Yes, they openly asked if anyone wanted to pledge allegiance
Interviewer: Did a pledge of allegiance happen in the prison?
No, during my 10 days there, that did not happen
But young boys would come to Sheikh Shaban Mosque
Which is Abu Dharr al-Ghifari Mosque
They brought young children who didn't know anything
They tricked them into pledging allegiance
And brought them in to make them part of their members
Interviewer: You mentioned the mosque is Sheikh Shaban Mosque
Is its name Sheikh Shaban Mosque?
No, its name is Abu Dharr al-Ghifari Mosque
But at that time there was a man named Sheikh Shaban in this mosque
Interviewer: Do you mean they pledged allegiance with him?
No, he was the one in charge of the mosque
Interviewer: Who is this Sheikh Shaban?
Witness: He is from the local area
Interviewer: Is he still around now?
No, he isn't—he's in the north or in Turkey, I think
Interviewer: Why is he in the north?
Witness: He hasn't come back
He is one of their supporters
Interviewer: Was he a supporter of ISIS?
Yes, more or less a supporter
Interviewer: Do you mean he went out there to escape?
Witness: Yes, he escaped
Interviewer: His house and the money he had here, where did they go?
I think they were confiscated
Interviewer: Given that this man is from your area
Did you know he supported ISIS, or did you find out after they came in?
No, after they came in, he joined them out of fear
Interviewer: And he is a religious man?
Witness: Yes, a religious man
Interviewer: Did he really join them out of fear?
ISIS are criminals
Out of fear, anything can happen
Interviewer: You were more afraid than him in prison, and you are not a religious man
Why didn’t you join them?
I would not join them, because I knew the government would return
And that they would fall and the movie would end
This group is manufactured
Interviewer: Since you were with the group for 10 days
And you said the food was the same and of the same kind
Regarding your use of the bathrooms, since you were a large group
How many toilets and showers were there?
There was only one
Interviewer: And you were more than 30 people?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Was there any kind of schedule for going to the bathroom?
Yes, it had to be quick in the morning
Anyone who wanted to use the toilet had to hurry
So the one behind him could go in
Then the third, the fourth, and so on
Interviewer: So it was up to you
Yes, it was just a house, guarded by ISIS members
But we were at ease, going to the toilet and so on
Interviewer: Were cleaning supplies and soap available?
Yes, they were available
Interviewer: You were more than 30 people, so your number was large
Did you have a cleaning schedule?
Were two or three people cleaning daily?
Yes, every day four people would clean a room
There were two rooms
Interviewer: Were the four from the prisoners or from ISIS members?
They were prisoners
Interviewer: Did they set a schedule for you, or was it among you?
Among ourselves, for example me and my friends
We would be four, for example, and say we will do the cleaning today
The next day, another four would do the cleaning
They cleaned the sleeping area, swept, and wiped it with Dettol and a towel
Interviewer: Were disinfectants also available?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did any prisoner develop a skin disease?
No, that did not happen, because the period was short
Interviewer: Did any prisoner suffer from a chronic illness?
And did he have a special kind of food?
A person who had a chronic illness, a heart condition, or other issues
Had his medication with him
Interviewer: And if his medicine ran out, would they bring him some?
Witness: Yes, they would give it to him
Interviewer: Did it happen that someone asked them for treatment
Interviewer: And did they tell him they didn’t have it?
Witness: No
Interviewer: So if it was not available in the pharmacy, would they bring it from outside?
Yes, they would bring it from outside
Interviewer: You mentioned that the jailers’ treatment of you was normal
Interviewer: Didn’t a judge come to you there?
Witness: They came for visits
Interviewer: Did they come for interrogation?
Witness: No, they came for visits
They would look over the place
They called him al-Hajji, and we did not know who he was
During that visit, was there direct contact and conversation with you as prisoners?
Yes, they would ask us how the brothers treated us
Meaning ISIS members, and we would tell him their treatment was good
That was all, and we could not say more than that
And even if their treatment was not good, we would say it was good
Interviewer: Did torture or flogging happen there?
Witness: No, there was no torture
Interviewer: Was there no flogging?
Witness: No
Interviewer: And no one was punished there?
Interviewer: Absolutely?
Witness: Yes, absolutely
I told you we were comfortable
Interviewer: How did they get you out of the prison?
The course ended, so I left
Interviewer: So they told you that when it ended, within 10 days, they would release you?
Yes, when the course ends, we release you
Interviewer: So they told you you would be out after 10 days?
Yes, they said we had a course, and when it ends, they would release us
So we counted the days
Interviewer: While you were on the course
Did you get a visit from your family?
No, I did not
Interviewer: For you or for other prisoners?
Witness: No, visits were not allowed
They released us at the time of the afternoon prayer
They brought us to Hajj Idris Mosque
Abd al-Rahman ibn Awf Mosque
We went in and prayed the afternoon prayer
And they released us from the mosque
Interviewer: Did they treat you harshly?
No, it was very ordinary treatment
Interviewer: Where did you take your belongings from?
They gave us the belongings there
My watch, my things, and my ID, and we left
Interviewer: After you got out and were released and returned home
Did your family know you’d be released?
No, they did not know
Interviewer: Can you describe how you felt?
And the moment your family met you, your wife and children?
It was an indescribable feeling
Interviewer: I want you to try to describe how it was
I was very happy. I wanted to hug my children and my family
And my friends and my people
And they all celebrated me
But it was a simple celebration
So the noise would not be heard
Because they were not allowed to hear the sounds of ululations and celebration
Interviewer: How was your meeting with your wife?
And with your mother who was still alive at the time?
How did you feel in that meeting and was there crying from joy?
Yes, there was crying from joy
My kids and my wife cried from joy
And they asked me at home—What did you do for them to take you?
I told them, I did nothing, you are my family and you know what I have
They took me unjustly
And thank God, God made it easy for me and I was released
Interviewer: After you stayed 38 days
Of which 28 days were in solitary and alone
And that was the hardest period you went through
Yes, it was
Interviewer: How did you become after this experience?
Was your life after release the same as it was before prison?
Was your personality the same before and after prison?
Or did your life change?
I became cautious in everything
In my movements, in my words, in everything
I even started praying right on time
When the muezzin says Allahu Akbar
I go straight to the mosque, because of fear
Interviewer: Did you have psychological changes?
For example, you were not quick to anger before
Did you become quick to anger?
I had a psychological problem and because of it I still see a psychiatrist
His name is Dr. Ali Neamat
Interviewer: Because of this detention?
Witness: Yes, because of it
And until now I take psychiatric medication
Interviewer: How was your condition at the beginning?
Surely your condition now is not like it was at the beginning
So how was your condition at the beginning?
Did you feel that your interactions were easy with your wife, children, and people?
Or were you withdrawn and afraid of everyone?
Did you become more afraid for your children, that the same thing might happen to them?
I want you to describe that state you were in
Before prison I was normal and had no problem
But after prison I developed this psychological problem
I was irritable with my family, my wife, and my kids
And when ISIS was present my anger was mixed with fear
I feared that if I raised my voice they would hear it, because they walked right by the door
Interviewer: Did you feel you were being watched?
Yes, I felt I was being watched
Interviewer: Were you not comfortable with your actions and movements even in your home?
Yes, because I developed a psychological problem
A severe psychological problem until now
Interviewer: Your relationships with people, trust in them, and new relationships
Were they the same as they used to be?
In making decisions with people or with a specific person
Was it the same thinking and same feeling?
No, I’ve become different now
Interviewer: What do you mean by different?
I’ve become afraid of people
I speak cautiously, and the words I say I must be certain of
Interviewer: And that continued even after ISIS left?
Witness: Yes, until now
Interviewer: And is it the same with your relationships with people?
My relationships are just greetings and I don’t like to get close with anyone
I’ve become quiet
Interviewer: Is this all just a reaction?
Witness: Yes, it is
Interviewer: And can you get rid of it?
I ask God to let me get rid of it
Interviewer: God willing
Interviewer: Do you want to tell us a particular story or incident?
That happened to you while you were in prison or while ISIS was in Mosul
Or an image you recall now before you
Or an incident that affected you or made you cry under ISIS
Something that happened in front of you and made you sad and cry
I was saddened for the people who died
I was saddened for my house that was looted
And I had nothing else
And after the area was liberated
Good people came and helped us
One brought me a fridge to help
Another brought me a freezer, another brought me a sofa set
I’d lost everything I owned
And until now I rent a house, I don’t own one
And the government has not compensated me for anything
We’ve given up on the existing government, we’ve lost hope in them
And thank God, Lord of the worlds
Interviewer: You said you were saddened for your looted house
Was it looted by ISIS?
Or did it happen during the battle?
Or was it looted by certain people?
How was it looted, and who did it?
The looting that happened
Was by ISIS and by gangs during the liberation
And my house was destroyed by shelling
And there was looting
Like the Ali Baba gangs and other thieves
Interviewer: Were those who looted from Mosul?
No, they were strangers
Interviewer: Do you mean strangers from Mosul’s outskirts or from outside?
From gangs that entered Mosul?
The gangs that entered Mosul are the ones who destroyed it
The people of Mosul did not destroy it
Interviewer: You personally, aside from the money stolen from your house
And the things stolen from it, and aside from prison
What do you feel was stolen from you besides these?
My health was stolen
When I lost my health I lost the dearest thing I had
And I could no longer make my family live properly
Because there is no livelihood
And no work like before
Now they give me a small welfare salary, it doesn’t even cover the rent
And our hope is in God
Interviewer: How do you make money besides welfare now?
I can’t work
Interviewer: And your kids?
Witness: They are young
They go to school
I pulled my eldest son out of school so he could work and support me
He is 17 years old