My name is Aladdin Khaled Ahmad
I am from the Nabi Jirjis area
I was born in 1973
ISIS detained me over a medicines case
I stayed in this place 28 days
And 10 days in another place
The medicines were for chronic illnesses
They were not sold in pharmacies
When they exceeded what the recipients needed
They brought them to me, knowing I distributed to those in need
Things like that
I was under surveillance
I felt I was being watched
Because they were sending women to my store
For medicines, and I gave injections to people for free
Interviewer: Were the women they sent from among their members?
Yes, members of ISIS
Interviewer: Did you learn that from them, or later?
I learned later
After they detained me
I only had a feeling that they were the ones sending them
ISIS, and that was why I was detained
Interviewer: What was the source of the medicines that came to you?
It was from people who had more than they needed
Yes, from people who wanted to do good
Interviewer: Were there people who bought medicines
Interviewer: And brought them to you seeking a reward for that?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did that happen with you?
Witness: Yes, it happened
I used to work in a pharmacy
So people in the area knew me
They told anyone who wanted to donate, Take it to Abu Abd al-Rahman
He is a man who does good for people
So this was a trust I passed on seeking reward
I wanted to do good—I did not sell them