I was in the store
Two people came to me
They said, Are you Aladdin? I said, Yes
He said, Please come with us to the Hisba [morality police]
I said, What is the matter?
They said, We want to ask you some questions
They took me and brought me to this place
They interrogated me
When they brought me in, I was terrified, afraid
Because their hands were stained with the blood of innocent people
Now I would become one of those people
Interviewer: The two people who brought you here
Can you describe their appearance?
And how old were they? What was their appearance?
Were they from Mosul, based on the accent they spoke to you with?
Or were they from the outskirts of Mosul, or from other provinces?
Or were they of other Arab nationalities?
They were from different backgrounds
But the two who came to me—one was from Hadar and the other from Mosul.
So their dialect was the Moslawi dialect
They worked in the Hisba
Interviewer: Approximately how old were they?
About 40 or 45 years old
Yes, the two who took me
Interviewer: How did they treat you from the moment they took you...
until they brought you to the prison?
Very normally
They didn’t talk to me in front of people
They brought me and led me in here
And they interrogated me
Interviewer: Did they bring you on foot or by car?
Witness: No, on foot
Because the distance is short, about 10 minutes on foot
Interviewer: Was one of them holding you?
Or were you handcuffed?
No, I walked in front of them and they were behind me, armed
Interviewer: So they escorted you without anyone holding you
No, no, they didn’t do anything to me
They just told me they wanted to ask me questions
Interviewer: When they took you to the prison gate
Did those same men go in with you?
Or did they hand you over to other people?
They brought me here and then handed me over to other people