When I came, I didn’t think this was a prison
I told myself they would ask me questions
And when they’d finished, I would leave
But I was surprised that after they’d asked me questions, they detained me
Interviewer: Since you are from this area
What was this place before?
This place used to be a church
Interviewer: Do you remember having come in here before?
When the Christians were present here?
Yes, I entered this place many times
There was a cemetery there
It had graves
We came in here when we were young
We used to come here in the 80s and 90s
We came as families—us and the Christians
Interviewer: Aside from being neighbors with the Christians in the area
Did you have special relationships, like friendships, with Christians?
Which made you come to this place?
Yes, they know I have many relationships with Christians
For that reason, I imagine they asked me who was a priest, and who was in this church
And in the other church, and who lived in the archbishopric
Interviewer: When they first brought you into this place
Into this entrance—which is the entrance to the church or to the prison itself
What was there at the beginning?
How did they treat you?
And how did they treat your belongings?
Did they deal with you when they took information from you?
How was it?
They took information from me
Interviewer: What information did they take from you?
I told you, they asked me about people
What do you know about the Christians who were in this area?
Interviewer: Was this when you arrived?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: When they took your belongings
Interviewer: Did they enter your name into the computer?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did they fill out a form?
Yes, they took my personal information
My full name, and what do you do? What is your job?
What are your relations with people here in the area?
Who do you know of the Christians?
They asked me about all these things
Interviewer: After they took your belongings
Where did they take you?
They took me and we entered the hall
They interrogated me
And that coincided with prayer time
So I prayed two cycles as sunna
After that I prayed the noon prayer
In the archbishopric, then they took me back
After they took me back they took me to the detention place
To the prison upstairs
I stayed upstairs for 28 days