Interviewer: In the first moments of entering the room
Tell me what was in your mind
I thought they were going to execute me
That is what I felt
It was all terror and fear
Because every little while you hear they took someone
He might be a policeman for example, and they kill him
Another for something else, for many reasons
So I thought I would be one of the victims and be killed
I imagined I would die like them
Interviewer: How many people were with you in this room?
At first I was alone
Then a boy named Edmond came in
A Christian, as if he had converted to Islam
He stayed two days with me
Later on every two or three days they would bring one or two
He would sit two or three hours then they would transfer him
Interviewer: Regarding the person you mentioned
Edmond the Christian
How did they treat him?
Their treatment was good
Interviewer: Didn’t you learn what his charge was?
Since he was asked to surrender
And he did, why arrest him?
I was afraid to ask him
Interviewer: Didn’t you talk about this?
I was afraid because they listened to us through the windows
They walked around the yard, so we were scared to talk
Interviewer: Didn’t he try to ask you or talk with you?
No, he didn’t ask me
Interviewer: Did he show signs of torture?
No, no, he didn’t show any signs of torture
Interviewer: Didn’t they use any means of torture on him?
No, he stayed two days with me
Then they transferred him, and I don’t know where they took him
Interviewer: Where was he from?
I asked him, Are you from Mosul? He said, Yes
I still remember he was from the Aden neighborhood
He told me he lived in the Aden neighborhood
And his family had all fled to Erbil
And he had stayed here alone
Interviewer: Didn’t you ask him why he’d stayed?
I told you I was afraid to ask him
I was afraid to ask him
Because it’s possible he was with them
Interviewer: So you stayed here 28 days
And most of the time you were alone
Interviewer: In this room or cell
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: How did you spend your time here?
My time was harsh, a day felt like a year
Interviewer: Didn’t they leave you something specific to use?
Like prayers, since you were so close to death
Interviewer: Were there Qurans in the prison?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: You mean they allowed them?
Witness: Yes, yes
I had a Quran to read and I prayed normally
I made duaa [supplication] and prayed
I fulfilled my duty of worshipping God Almighty
I prayed to God to free me, to let me out and get rid of them
Interviewer: How did you spend the night?
I spent it terrified
It was all horror and fear
Interviewer: While you were in this room at night
Did you imagine they would come to you?
Yes, I imagined they would come to me
Interviewer: Can you describe this state to us?
I imagined it to myself
I told myself that after 10 minutes
Or after an hour or two or at midnight
They would call me, take me, and execute me
Just like the others they executed
They planted horror and fear in my heart
And this continues even now, as I talk to you
As I speak with you now, I feel they are here
Interviewer: Did you sleep very little?
Witness: Yes, very little
Interviewer: Do you mean because of overthinking and fear?
Yes, it is the thinking that exhausted me
And I still take psychiatric medication to this day
Interviewer: Given that you were alone in this place
Did you find yourself not wanting to sleep out of fear
That they would execute you while you slept?
Yes, I felt afraid
Interviewer: So you tried not to sleep?
Yes, I tried not to sleep for fear they would kill me while I slept
Interviewer: Was that imagination?
Or did it reflect a real feeling inside you?
It was a real feeling
Interviewer: Have you heard of such a thing happening?
Yes, they executed many people
There’s the Khasfa sinkhole
How many innocent people they threw into it
More than 5,000, maybe up to 10,000
Interviewer: You were alone, so surely you stayed silent the whole time
Did you have moments when you reflected during detention?
Did you remember things and then sit and cry?
Yes, I cried, I did not feel relief except after I’d cried
Interviewer: Did this happen often?
Witness: Yes, very often
Very often, about once or twice daily
I remembered my children and my wife
I said to myself, I will not see them anymore
Because they will execute me and my story will end
And all my thoughts were of my children, my wife, and my home
Interviewer: While you were in solitary confinement for 28 days
Except for two nights when the Christian was with you
How did they treat you throughout this period?
It was ordinary treatment
Interviewer: Was their speech harsh?
There was shouting and so on
Like, come here and go there, in a shouting tone
And sometimes not
They would tell me, for example, get up, Abu Abd al-Rahman, it is time for prayer
Interviewer: Did this treatment differ from one jailer to another?
Yes, it did, that is true
Interviewer: So there was a jailer who respected you and called you Abu Abd al-Rahman?
Yes, there were those who called me that
Some of them respected me, and some did not
Interviewer: Which jailers were more respectful to you?
Those who were from Mosul
Interviewer: Do you mean Mosul residents affiliated with them?
Yes, from Mosul, they were respectful
But the Arabs from the districts and subdistricts were not respectful
They had all come out of prisons
Their bodies were tattooed, and so on
Interviewer: So they were hard on you?
Witness: Yes
Yes, their speech was harsh toward people
Because they are criminals
Interviewer: Did you try to deal with them
And ask them to bring you something from outside the prison?
And if so, did they refuse?
Did you try to give them a certain sum of money?
So they would provide you a certain need or a comfort?
Yes, sometimes I needed biscuits or other things from outside
Or drinks and the like, and they would buy them for me
I gave them money through the door slot to go, they would buy for me and return
Interviewer: Wasn’t your money with the deposited belongings they took from you?
The deposited belongings, which were my ID card and watch
Were with them in the trailer
Only the money was in my pocket
Interviewer: Didn’t they take the money from you?
Witness: No, they didn’t take it
I had money in my pocket
When I needed something, I asked their permission
And I said, sir, I want something
Could someone go to the grocery and buy for me
They would go, buy it for me, and bring it to me
Interviewer: Didn’t he get annoyed with you when you asked him?
I didn’t ask just anyone
I asked the one who could tolerate me
Interviewer: Did you feel comfortable with any of the jailers?
In case a conversation happened between you
No, no, because I was afraid of them
Interviewer: Didn’t they try to reassure you, for example, and make you talk?
No, frankly you will not feel reassurance with them
Interviewer: Since you were in solitary, did you have a sense...
Of the people they brought for several hours, meaning for a short time?
Did they send in one of their members as a spy?
Or did they assign people to question you or interrogate you inside?
Sometimes I felt that
I said to myself it is possible they would send one of the prisoners
To lure me with his questions, and I would answer them
I was careful of them
Interviewer: Were there rooms next to you from which you heard voices?
Yes, I heard voices from here
There were some in the back
And in Mar Yousef Church
But we did not hear their voices because they were a bit far
They would bring them here
When they whipped here, I heard the sound
They would bring whoever had prayer beads, or the like
They held them accountable by flogging them here
Whoever they caught because of cigarettes
Or because of a satellite dish
They would punish them here, flogging them
Interviewer: Okay, regardless of the flogging that happened during the day
Did you hear sounds of torture at night?
Interviewer: Like screams from prisoners, for example? Witness:
Yes, a little
Interviewer: What were those sounds like?
When they caught someone who worked in the police
Or in the National Guard, for example, or in the army
They would bring him in, ISIS’s security group
From his screaming, it was clear they were beating him
Because we heard the sound from the window
Interviewer: Do you mean you didn’t see anyone being tortured?
Interviewer: And you, were you not tortured in this prison?
Witness: No
Interviewer: So only the sounds you heard…
No, I didn’t see anything, they didn’t take me anywhere