Interviewer: Okay, in these 38 days
28 days in this prison and 10 days in another prison
How many times did you go to interrogation and to the judge?
Witness: Twice
Interviewer: And was the judge the same both times?
No, they were different people in each interrogation
Interviewer: So the first interrogation happened in the hall?
Witness: Here
Interviewer: And where did the other one happen?
It happened at the archdiocese
Interviewer: What did he ask you about specifically at the archdiocese?
He asked me about the matter of the medicines as well
And as I told you, he asked me about the people present here
Whom you know, and who was in this church
And who the priest is, about his family, his children, and his brothers, and what you know
And whom you know among the Christians who left
I told him, All the Christians left—none remained
Some remained who had converted to Islam
Among them this Saadallah, the restaurant owner
He converted to Islam out of fear, and stayed here
Then he went to Baghdad and returned to his religion again
Interviewer: Did they try to get information from you, not only about the Christians?
But about their money, their houses, and their properties in the area
And details about things they couldn’t know, for example
They asked me about the graves of the Christians
About the burial place of the priests
I told them, In Mary Church
The tomb is in the church in the Qasan area
I know that because I participated with them, as they were my neighbors
They have intelligence and information and know everything
They know what the child playing in the street is doing
Interviewer: Were you surprised by these questions?
Witness: Yes, of course I was surprised
Interviewer: These questions they asked you that surprised you
What did they leave you with exactly during the interrogation?
I became fearful, terrified
Because they frighten people
Interviewer: Did they use threats with you during the interrogation?
Yes, to some extent
Interviewer: What did he say to you, for example?
He said, Speak, Hajj, about what you know
Better than us asking you
So I told them what I had
So that they wouldn’t be the ones asking me
Interviewer: What did he ask you specifically?
They asked me, What is your job?
And who comes to you, and who sits with you?
And what do you know about ISIS
Out of fear I told them that ISIS is good
And there’s nothing wrong with it, and you are an Islamic state
Things like that
And I was terrified of them
Interviewer: From the questions they asked you
It appears they knew many details about you
Did they beat you or insult you while questioning you?
Or did any of the members standing behind you
Attempt to deal with you with a weapon or by using a sharp instrument?
Or did anything specific happen during their interrogation of you?
No, from when they took me to Mar Yousef Church
I overstepped a little in speaking with them
So one of them pushed me
And I told you when I fell on the stairs
Because there were stairs
This fall still affects me
I have pain in my back and legs
Interviewer: What caused the problems during the conversation?
Because they brought me in unjustly
I mean, I hadn’t committed a crime to be imprisoned, or anything like that
And I knew I had done nothing and that I was innocent
When my imprisonment dragged on
I asked them, What is the reason for my imprisonment?
They told me, You know everything. But I didn't know anything