I had suspicions that they wanted me to work with them
And I would not work with them, and I stayed that way, thank God
Interviewer: Did they ask you to work with them directly?
No, but through their questions it became clear they wanted me to work with them
Interviewer: What did he say to you, for example?
He said, For example, we have wounded people. Can you insert an IV cannula for them?
Or give them injections
I told them I don't have a license to do that, and I was afraid, and so on
And that I had sworn not to give an injection to anyone
Interviewer: So they asked you to help them according to your medical specialty?
Yes, but I didn't leave them any room for that and I didn't work with them
Interviewer: So they didn’t ask you to join them and pledge allegiance directly?
Yes, not directly
I felt they wanted me to work with them
But I didn't give them any room and I didn't work with them
Interviewer: After they’d completed the interrogation with you in this hall inside this building
Where did they take you after that?
They took me to a holding house, which was the house of Raed Jobbo
Which was basically a house used as a prison
They put us into a religious course for 10 days
After these 10 days
My detention then totaled 38 days, then they released me