Rice and broth, they brought it ready in foam plates
In the morning they brought us tahini and sammoun [bread roll]
And sometimes they brought pieces of cheese with it
That was in the morning, and at night they brought dinner
Interviewer: Did they bring rice and broth daily?
They varied it—it wasn’t the same food every day
Interviewer: How many pieces of sammoun did they bring per day? Witness: Two in the morning
At noon, one piece with a plate of rice and a cup of broth
Interviewer: So they didn’t mix them together?
Witness: No
Interviewer: And what about dinner?
At dinner they sometimes brought sammoun and cooked chicken
They gave us the leg of the chicken, or the wing, or something else
Interviewer: Was the food enough?
Witness: Yes, it was enough
When a person is in prison, he won’t crave food because of the worry
Interviewer: Tell me honestly, was it enough? Witness: Yes, it was fine
Interviewer: Was the quality good or bad? Witness: It was bad
Interviewer: Did it come hot or cold?
They brought it sometimes hot and at other times cold
Meaning they brought it from far away
Interviewer: Did it ever happen that they asked you what you like to eat?
No, they didn’t ask me
If a person wanted to buy food
He would tell the jailer he craved food from outside
Like kebab or something else
When the market was open
They would bring us from the guy called Hazem
I twice asked to buy kebab from him
Half a portion for one person
Two skewers were enough for me, two pieces
Interviewer: When you sent someone to buy food or what you needed
Was the ISIS member you sent
Bargaining with you to take an amount of money in return for that?
I would tell him, If you’re hungry, get yourself food with mine
And he would say to me, No, they don’t accept that
Interviewer: Did he take an amount above the price of what he brought?
No, he brought it at the same price
Interviewer: Didn’t it happen sometimes that someone asked you for a bribe?
No, not at all
Interviewer: For example to connect you with your family by a phone call
No, but sometimes I would send him to my house
To bring me medicine
That happened twice—I sent him to bring me medicine
And his name was Abu Taha
Interviewer: Who is this Abu Taha?
He is one of their members
Interviewer: Did you know him before? Witness: No
Interviewer: And when he did that
By going to your house to bring you the medicine
It was a kind act from him
Interviewer: Did he do that on their orders or on his own?
No, on his own. Wasn’t he the jailer responsible for the room?
During his shift I would ask him to go, because he knew the house, it was nearby
Anyone from the street could have gone to bring it for me
I used Angised and Isordil, heart medications
Interviewer: In this case, did your family know you were detained?
But they didn’t know in which place exactly
Interviewer: So he didn’t tell them your location?
Witness: No, he didn’t tell them
Interviewer: During your 28 days
Did you need a doctor, or for a nurse to come to you?
Did a doctor actually visit you?
No, I know what I suffer from
And the treatment I take
Interviewer: Regardless of your knowledge of what you suffer from
Did their schedule include a doctor visiting you from time to time?
Yes, they asked us if we needed a doctor
So they could take us to him
If you felt your blood pressure was high, for example, or something like that
But I didn’t ask them for this
Interviewer: You mean there was understanding of your health condition
And special consideration for you
Yes, they knew that
Interviewer: Regarding the food
Was there any kind that harmed you and they still brought it to you?
Or did they not bring it to you because you told them it harmed you?
No, the food they brought didn’t harm me
If there was fat, I wouldn’t eat it
For example, I would eat the bread and the chicken thigh
And I wouldn’t eat the rest
Because I suffered from high blood lipids, and until now
Interviewer: Didn’t it happen one day that they asked you
About this food, whether it was beneficial or harmful to you?
And did they try to bring you something that would help you and not harm you?
They asked me, and I told them this doesn’t harm me
Interviewer: So they asked you?
Witness: Yes, they asked me
Interviewer: Do you think you had some kind of special care in the prison?
Not like the treatment of others
Interviewer: Considering they placed you in a place by yourself
It was like that somewhat
Interviewer: Was that because of your age?
Or because they expected you would be with them and help them
Yes, it was for that reason
Meaning because they needed me, and they wanted me to join them
This good treatment, they wanted from it in return
To motivate you and urge you to join them
Yes, it was like that
Interviewer: Is that it?
Witness: Yes, I felt that