In the morning when I woke up and wanted to go to the toilets
They allowed me to go there to relieve myself and return
And as for bathing, it was twice a week
On Mondays and Thursdays we had the right to bathe
And they gave us ten minutes or a quarter hour to bathe
Interviewer: When you relieved yourself, did you do so comfortably?
Or did you feel you were being watched?
When I entered the toilets, I felt I was being watched
Interviewer: And were you actually watched, or was it just a feeling?
It was a feeling
Interviewer: So you weren’t watched?
Witness: No, I wasn’t watched
But it was my feeling because the toilets were adjacent to the prison
It was next to the parking area, and the jailer stood outside next to the toilets
Interviewer: Regarding cleanliness in the prison
Did they give you cleaning supplies to clean the room?
Yes, they gave us some
Interviewer: Were they available regularly?
Yes, available—they gave us Dettol and a bucket of water
Every two days we wiped the room
Interviewer: Was the cleaning time mandatory on a certain day?
Every two days we had the task of cleaning the room
We did the cleaning inside the room
Interviewer: Was hot and cold water available in the showers?
Yes, they heated the water for us to bathe with
They gave us a bucket of water with about 50 liters of water
We bathed with it—we had to finish within 10 minutes to a quarter hour
Interviewer: Did they distribute underwear to you?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Didn’t they give you other clothes?
When I sent them to bring me the medicine
My family sent me underwear and pajamas
Interviewer: Was bringing them in normal?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did they not allow visits in the prison?
No, they didn’t allow anyone to do that, and my family knew that