I told you I stayed here 28 days
Then they moved me to that house, which was also a prison
I stayed there 10 days
In those 10 days they put me in a course of religious instruction and tawhid
When the 10 days ended they released us
Interviewer: When they transferred you to the other prison and you stayed there 10 days
Were you by yourself, or were you with a group?
No, I was with a large group, more than 30 people, roughly
Interviewer: Had those people been imprisoned for a long time?
Some for 10 days, some stayed a month, others eight days
It depended on each person's case
Interviewer: Can you tell me the charges they were accused of?
One of them because of birds
And another because of cigarettes
And another they caught while he was smuggling cigarettes in a car
His name was Khalil
Various charges, most for smoking
Interviewer: Considering there was a group of people during those 10 days
And you had come out of solitary to a prison with a group
How were your relationships? And how did you spend your days and nights together?
It was normal, we talked freely
And when the time for the lessons came
We went out and sat in the house courtyard. We sat in pairs, and they taught us
Interviewer: In that prison where you stayed 10 days
Interviewer: And you were 30 people?
Witness: Yes, more than 30
Interviewer: What were their ages, roughly the youngest to the oldest?
There were 18-year-olds, and there were 40-year-olds
And there were 50-year-olds—there were various ages
Interviewer: Because of this difference between ages, between young and old
And because of differences in mindsets and backgrounds
Were there quarrels or problems between them, or between one group and another, while you were there?
No, no problems happened between the prisoners at all
On the contrary, we got along and liked each other
Everyone helped each other
If someone was hungry and had no food, another gave him some of his food
We ate together, for example
If someone had a headache we gave him a painkiller tablet
That was how it was
Interviewer: How did they treat you there as a group?
When you were by yourself, you had special care
Was the care the same there?
Yes, there was care
And they had a person there
He was responsible for something like a pharmacy
Meaning he was from ISIS
He had a set of medicines that he gave to anyone suffering from something
They had medications for headaches or heart conditions
It was in the hallway, like a small pharmacy
Interviewer: Were you allowed to move around inside there?
It is a small house
We wandered in its courtyard or in the room—nothing more than that
Interviewer: Was it allowed to go out to the courtyard at any time?
Yes, the room doors were open, and the house was fortified from the outside
Interviewer: How many guards were there?
Witness: Five guards
Interviewer: How did they treat you?
It was fine, not bad
Interviewer: Were their nationalities or accents those of Mosul locals and Bedouins?
Or were they only from Mosul?
They were mixed—two of them were from Diyala, as I recall
And three were from the outskirts of Mosul
Interviewer: Was the food there like it was here?
Yes, they brought us the same food
Interviewer: Was there any discrimination between one prisoner and another, or not?
No, everyone was equal
Interviewer: You said there was a small pharmacy
Yes, it was small, for whoever needed a painkiller tablet
Or, for example, someone with a sore throat, they gave him a capsule
They dispensed the medicine for him normally
Interviewer: This place is indeed a prison
But as a prison, did you feel there was special care?
Or was that, as you mentioned, because they needed
To ask you and others to join them?
It was varied because each person had a different case
Interviewer: Since you were now with a group of prisoners
How did you spend your nights and days with them?
It was normal—it was better than here
Interviewer: Tell me about your life and the times you spent in the prison
We used to talk most of the time
We got to know each other and asked where people lived, for example
And we talked about religion in case they were listening
They would know we were talking about religion
We talked about religious stories and such things
We spent time like that
Interviewer: Do you think there were spies among you from their personnel?
Or did they bring in people who volunteered to act as spies and pass information
I don't know—I don't think so
I don't think any of their members were among the prisoners
Do you remember particular stories that happened during your imprisonment there over the 10 days?
Or a specific person's story you still remember
Or a story that affected you that you still remember
And it hurts when you remember it
Or a case of a particular person that happened in front of you?
Or a particular injustice?
It was all injustice
Because we were all unjustly imprisoned
Can someone be imprisoned because of cigarettes?
It was all injustice, like the one they brought because of cigarettes
And the one they brought and flogged because he’d said a word outside to his friend
Trivial things
Interviewer: Weren't there any charges more serious than cigarettes?
Or did they bring someone unjustly when he didn’t even have cigarettes?
Most of them were family matters
Meaning they would also bring someone who had a problem with his wife, or whose voice was loud
Interviewer: They hear his voice and then bring him?
Someone files a complaint against him
Meaning they had operatives everywhere
For example, they hear that someone blasphemed, so they bring him
Or if someone blasphemes, they would behead him on the spot
Interviewer: How did you spend your time in the prison?
They gave us papers containing religious material to memorize
Quranic verses and suras, and tawhid material to memorize
And instruction, and such things
Interviewer: Did you memorize them as lessons?
Yes, they asked us in the morning when we woke up
Interviewer: So lessons and homework?
Witness: Yes
They gave us three or four pages of paper
We memorized them and in the morning we answered their questions
No one is unaware of these things
Everyone knows the Ibrahimiyya prayers
We all had them memorized
Interviewer: So it was like a school
Witness: Yes, almost
Interviewer: What kind of lessons were they?
And who was the person who taught you?
Was it the same person who came every time?
Yes, it was the same person and his name was Abu Muhammad
Interviewer: Was it the same one who came daily? Didn't someone else come?
No, the same one came
Interviewer: Can you describe to me what he looked like?
Was he actually a teacher by profession, or did he teach in a mosque?
Yes, he was a teacher
He was a teacher and about 40 years old
He had great knowledge of religion
He asked us and encouraged us
To memorize and read the Quran
Interviewer: What was the type of lessons exactly?
Were the lessons related to jurisprudence and matters of purification, prayer, and creed?
Or were there lessons you think they intended to push you to pledge allegiance?
Were they advising you to pledge allegiance?
And did they try to show you they were in the right, and so on?
Was that the case?
Yes, that's right—those things were there
Interviewer: How so? What did they ask you, for example?
And how did they deal with you on this matter?
Honestly I don't know what to say to you
Meaning they wanted us to join them
Interviewer: Through the lessons?
Witness: Yes, through the lessons
Interviewer: Through the lessons, did you receive an explicit call to pledge allegiance?
Yes, they openly asked if anyone wanted to pledge allegiance
Interviewer: Did a pledge of allegiance happen in the prison?
No, during my 10 days there, that did not happen
But young boys would come to Sheikh Shaban Mosque
Which is Abu Dharr al-Ghifari Mosque
They brought young children who didn't know anything
They tricked them into pledging allegiance
And brought them in to make them part of their members
Interviewer: You mentioned the mosque is Sheikh Shaban Mosque
Is its name Sheikh Shaban Mosque?
No, its name is Abu Dharr al-Ghifari Mosque
But at that time there was a man named Sheikh Shaban in this mosque
Interviewer: Do you mean they pledged allegiance with him?
No, he was the one in charge of the mosque
Interviewer: Who is this Sheikh Shaban?
Witness: He is from the local area
Interviewer: Is he still around now?
No, he isn't—he's in the north or in Turkey, I think
Interviewer: Why is he in the north?
Witness: He hasn't come back
He is one of their supporters
Interviewer: Was he a supporter of ISIS?
Yes, more or less a supporter
Interviewer: Do you mean he went out there to escape?
Witness: Yes, he escaped
Interviewer: His house and the money he had here, where did they go?
I think they were confiscated
Interviewer: Given that this man is from your area
Did you know he supported ISIS, or did you find out after they came in?
No, after they came in, he joined them out of fear
Interviewer: And he is a religious man?
Witness: Yes, a religious man
Interviewer: Did he really join them out of fear?
ISIS are criminals
Out of fear, anything can happen
Interviewer: You were more afraid than him in prison, and you are not a religious man
Why didn’t you join them?
I would not join them, because I knew the government would return
And that they would fall and the movie would end
This group is manufactured
Interviewer: Since you were with the group for 10 days
And you said the food was the same and of the same kind
Regarding your use of the bathrooms, since you were a large group
How many toilets and showers were there?
There was only one
Interviewer: And you were more than 30 people?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Was there any kind of schedule for going to the bathroom?
Yes, it had to be quick in the morning
Anyone who wanted to use the toilet had to hurry
So the one behind him could go in
Then the third, the fourth, and so on
Interviewer: So it was up to you
Yes, it was just a house, guarded by ISIS members
But we were at ease, going to the toilet and so on
Interviewer: Were cleaning supplies and soap available?
Yes, they were available
Interviewer: You were more than 30 people, so your number was large
Did you have a cleaning schedule?
Were two or three people cleaning daily?
Yes, every day four people would clean a room
There were two rooms
Interviewer: Were the four from the prisoners or from ISIS members?
They were prisoners
Interviewer: Did they set a schedule for you, or was it among you?
Among ourselves, for example me and my friends
We would be four, for example, and say we will do the cleaning today
The next day, another four would do the cleaning
They cleaned the sleeping area, swept, and wiped it with Dettol and a towel
Interviewer: Were disinfectants also available?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did any prisoner develop a skin disease?
No, that did not happen, because the period was short
Interviewer: Did any prisoner suffer from a chronic illness?
And did he have a special kind of food?
A person who had a chronic illness, a heart condition, or other issues
Had his medication with him
Interviewer: And if his medicine ran out, would they bring him some?
Witness: Yes, they would give it to him
Interviewer: Did it happen that someone asked them for treatment
Interviewer: And did they tell him they didn’t have it?
Witness: No
Interviewer: So if it was not available in the pharmacy, would they bring it from outside?
Yes, they would bring it from outside
Interviewer: You mentioned that the jailers’ treatment of you was normal
Interviewer: Didn’t a judge come to you there?
Witness: They came for visits
Interviewer: Did they come for interrogation?
Witness: No, they came for visits
They would look over the place
They called him al-Hajji, and we did not know who he was
During that visit, was there direct contact and conversation with you as prisoners?
Yes, they would ask us how the brothers treated us
Meaning ISIS members, and we would tell him their treatment was good
That was all, and we could not say more than that
And even if their treatment was not good, we would say it was good
Interviewer: Did torture or flogging happen there?
Witness: No, there was no torture
Interviewer: Was there no flogging?
Witness: No
Interviewer: And no one was punished there?
Interviewer: Absolutely?
Witness: Yes, absolutely
I told you we were comfortable
Interviewer: How did they get you out of the prison?
The course ended, so I left
Interviewer: So they told you that when it ended, within 10 days, they would release you?
Yes, when the course ends, we release you
Interviewer: So they told you you would be out after 10 days?
Yes, they said we had a course, and when it ends, they would release us
So we counted the days
Interviewer: While you were on the course
Did you get a visit from your family?
No, I did not
Interviewer: For you or for other prisoners?
Witness: No, visits were not allowed