Interviewer: After you stayed 38 days
Of which 28 days were in solitary and alone
And that was the hardest period you went through
Yes, it was
Interviewer: How did you become after this experience?
Was your life after release the same as it was before prison?
Was your personality the same before and after prison?
Or did your life change?
I became cautious in everything
In my movements, in my words, in everything
I even started praying right on time
When the muezzin says Allahu Akbar
I go straight to the mosque, because of fear
Interviewer: Did you have psychological changes?
For example, you were not quick to anger before
Did you become quick to anger?
I had a psychological problem and because of it I still see a psychiatrist
His name is Dr. Ali Neamat
Interviewer: Because of this detention?
Witness: Yes, because of it
And until now I take psychiatric medication
Interviewer: How was your condition at the beginning?
Surely your condition now is not like it was at the beginning
So how was your condition at the beginning?
Did you feel that your interactions were easy with your wife, children, and people?
Or were you withdrawn and afraid of everyone?
Did you become more afraid for your children, that the same thing might happen to them?
I want you to describe that state you were in
Before prison I was normal and had no problem
But after prison I developed this psychological problem
I was irritable with my family, my wife, and my kids
And when ISIS was present my anger was mixed with fear
I feared that if I raised my voice they would hear it, because they walked right by the door
Interviewer: Did you feel you were being watched?
Yes, I felt I was being watched
Interviewer: Were you not comfortable with your actions and movements even in your home?
Yes, because I developed a psychological problem
A severe psychological problem until now
Interviewer: Your relationships with people, trust in them, and new relationships
Were they the same as they used to be?
In making decisions with people or with a specific person
Was it the same thinking and same feeling?
No, I’ve become different now
Interviewer: What do you mean by different?
I’ve become afraid of people
I speak cautiously, and the words I say I must be certain of
Interviewer: And that continued even after ISIS left?
Witness: Yes, until now
Interviewer: And is it the same with your relationships with people?
My relationships are just greetings and I don’t like to get close with anyone
I’ve become quiet
Interviewer: Is this all just a reaction?
Witness: Yes, it is
Interviewer: And can you get rid of it?
I ask God to let me get rid of it
Interviewer: God willing
Interviewer: Do you want to tell us a particular story or incident?
That happened to you while you were in prison or while ISIS was in Mosul
Or an image you recall now before you
Or an incident that affected you or made you cry under ISIS
Something that happened in front of you and made you sad and cry
I was saddened for the people who died
I was saddened for my house that was looted
And I had nothing else
And after the area was liberated
Good people came and helped us
One brought me a fridge to help
Another brought me a freezer, another brought me a sofa set
I’d lost everything I owned
And until now I rent a house, I don’t own one
And the government has not compensated me for anything
We’ve given up on the existing government, we’ve lost hope in them
And thank God, Lord of the worlds
Interviewer: You said you were saddened for your looted house
Was it looted by ISIS?
Or did it happen during the battle?
Or was it looted by certain people?
How was it looted, and who did it?
The looting that happened
Was by ISIS and by gangs during the liberation
And my house was destroyed by shelling
And there was looting
Like the Ali Baba gangs and other thieves
Interviewer: Were those who looted from Mosul?
No, they were strangers
Interviewer: Do you mean strangers from Mosul’s outskirts or from outside?
From gangs that entered Mosul?
The gangs that entered Mosul are the ones who destroyed it
The people of Mosul did not destroy it
Interviewer: You personally, aside from the money stolen from your house
And the things stolen from it, and aside from prison
What do you feel was stolen from you besides these?
My health was stolen
When I lost my health I lost the dearest thing I had
And I could no longer make my family live properly
Because there is no livelihood
And no work like before
Now they give me a small welfare salary, it doesn’t even cover the rent
And our hope is in God
Interviewer: How do you make money besides welfare now?
I can’t work
Interviewer: And your kids?
Witness: They are young
They go to school
I pulled my eldest son out of school so he could work and support me
He is 17 years old