They released us at the time of the afternoon prayer
They brought us to Hajj Idris Mosque
Abd al-Rahman ibn Awf Mosque
We went in and prayed the afternoon prayer
And they released us from the mosque
Interviewer: Did they treat you harshly?
No, it was very ordinary treatment
Interviewer: Where did you take your belongings from?
They gave us the belongings there
My watch, my things, and my ID, and we left
Interviewer: After you got out and were released and returned home
Did your family know you’d be released?
No, they did not know
Interviewer: Can you describe how you felt?
And the moment your family met you, your wife and children?
It was an indescribable feeling
Interviewer: I want you to try to describe how it was
I was very happy. I wanted to hug my children and my family
And my friends and my people
And they all celebrated me
But it was a simple celebration
So the noise would not be heard
Because they were not allowed to hear the sounds of ululations and celebration
Interviewer: How was your meeting with your wife?
And with your mother who was still alive at the time?
How did you feel in that meeting and was there crying from joy?
Yes, there was crying from joy
My kids and my wife cried from joy
And they asked me at home—What did you do for them to take you?
I told them, I did nothing, you are my family and you know what I have
They took me unjustly
And thank God, God made it easy for me and I was released