My name is Talal Mustafa al-Shuweimi
I’m from Raqqa Province, living on Sajiyah Street
I’m 45 years old
I have 3 wives and 13 children
During the Assad regime’s control of Raqqa, I worked at the Water Department
After the problems and battles started
I was dismissed from work
The regime accused me of being a terrorist
The Air Force Intelligence raided my house
Because they claimed I was a terrorist
The dismissal order came from Damascus
Of course
It was all a malicious report
Because we were locals and stayed in the city
My dismissal order came in 2012
So I fled Raqqa for a while
And my brother was arrested
By the Assad regime
On behalf of the regime
They put him in Sednaya Prison for about 6 years
After they detained my brother for 6 years in prison
The Free Syrian Army entered Raqqa
I was already dismissed from work as a “terrorist”
About 6 or 7 months after the FSA entered
ISIS entered the city, calling itself the Islamic State
They took control of the area
Within their first 2 or 3 months of settling in
They arrested me, accusing me of being a regime agent,a shabiha [pro-regime thug]
They detained me at Point 11, with the security members
Inside the former Governor’s Palace
I stayed there for about a week
After the Governor’s Palace, they took me
To a new security base near the National Hospital area in Raqqa
It was inside the old Military Judiciary building of the Assad regime
A week later, they moved me from the Governor’s Palace basement
To the old Military Judiciary building near the Traffic Circle
I stayed in that base
Under the same charge, regime agent
I stayed there for 53 days
After 53 days
They released me because there was no evidence against me
The one who interrogated me
Was from Raqqa Province, from Tabqa city
His family name was Khameesi
He was called Abu Yousuf, the interrogator
He was the head of interrogators
Another man was nicknamed Abu Abdurrahman
His name was Mahmoud al-Ali al-Sahou from the Ghanem al-Zahir clan
From an area called al-Jaif
East of the al-Eywij area
Near Rashid Farm in Raqqa
I stayed under interrogation for about 53 days
After they confirmed there was nothing against me
They realized I’d already been dismissed by the Assad regime as a “terrorist”
So they released me
And gave me a clearance card
A certificate proving there were no charges against me
As a Syrian citizen
And a Sunni by faith
I went back to work with the other workers
Trying to earn a living to support my children
Around 50 or 60 days after returning
I was surprised to see someone
Sadly, he was from the same neighborhood, Sunni, and a local of the area
His name was Mahmoud al-Shahada
He was an ISIS emir overseeing the Water Department
Known as Abu Hudhayfa
Abu Hudhayfa had been detained in Assad regime prisons back in 2000
Accused of joining Jund al-Sham
He struck a deal with the regime in Sednaya Prison and was released
Then brought to Raqqa and appointed as an emir in the caliphate
Mahmoud al-Shahada, known as Abu Hudhayfa, and his brother were both active and skilled
His brother’s name was Hassan
He had two brothers, Hassan and Hassaan
His brother was an emir and his right-hand man
When I came back to the Water Department
I was surprised he’d become the department’s emir after being released from Sednaya
When the workers learned I was coming to work again
I had no salary, but people gave us charity for the children
They offered us odd jobs outside
Of course, we had no fixed income since I and others were dismissed from work
Then Abu Hudhayfa came
And arrested me himself,Mahmoud al-Shahada
By then, he’d become “Minister of the Caliphate” because of his influence and knowledge
He had many initiatives, so he arrested me
He tricked me into it
At the time, we were fixing a broken water line
In the Khasra Faraj area, and when we came
He said, “The sheikh wants to see you”
“He wants to ask a few questions, and there’s also a broken pipe at the security point”
He said, “You should fix it.” I said, “As you wish, Abu Hudhayfa”
When I arrived there, I only saw weapons pointed at me
They threw me to the ground, stepped on my neck, and arrested me
For about two months
When I returned to work at the Water Department
Abu Hudhayfa grabbed me by the hair
Dragged me toward the table
Pressed my head onto it
And placed his foot on my left shoulder
He said to me, “You’re a shabih (pro-regime thug). You shouldn’t enter the institution. You’re an agent for the regime”
I told him, Calm down, Sheikh, this is my clearance from Point 11, and I’m clean, there’s nothing against me
I have children, but he said, No, you’re a shabih
And no one will be able to get you back to work
We brought mediations from one sheikh and another, but nothing worked
At that point, I had a small amount of money
And my brother had about 125,000 Syrian pounds
So I bought a taxi
A taxi with no official papers
Back then they used to call it “Arouriya”
Because it was stolen,they’d steal and sell it without papers
So they called it an “Arouriya car”
I worked as a taxi driver
For about 5 to 6 months
One day
The Hisba (religious police) raided me at my home
On 16th Street
They said to me, You’re a man who trades cigarettes
And they detained me for 4 days
They insulted me, but it wasn’t severe or extreme
They kept saying, You’re a cigarette dealer, and so on
I told him, Sheikh, I’m not a cigarette dealer, I don’t even smoke cigarettes, but yes, I smoke hookah
Yes, I smoke hookah
But I don’t smoke cigarettes. If I did, I’d tell you
Anyway, they detained me
One man
And took me to a Hisba base called “Panorama”
It’s in Raqqa, near Maqs Roundabout, called “Panorama”
There was a Hisba base there. The emir in charge was Abu Bishr
Abu Bishr, a Saudi national
After 4 days of detention
I moved my home to another neighborhood, fearing someone was targeting me
I was hungry, and I had 12 or 13 children
There was no strength left in me
I thought, There are people who trade cigarettes and make a living from it
So I started selling cigarettes. Honestly, the accusation already stuck to me anyway
So I decided to trade cigarettes
And I began working in that trade
For about a month or a month and a half
Then a Hisba patrol came and arrested me
They detained me for about 15 days
And the one who arrested me
Was a man from Rumaila named Mustafa al-Hamid al-Muslih
Known as Abu Seif Maqs
He also had another nom de guerre, Abu Seif Doshka
Also known as Abu Seif Maqs
He was originally from the Wahb clan
His maternal uncles were from the Masaar group of the Barij clan
As for Abu Seif Maqs, his past
Was extremely bad
He used to take hashish and pills and was unemployed
And strangely enough
When ISIS entered, I was shocked to see he had become a Doshka gunner
Then, since he was from the area and knew people
They made him emir of the Search and Investigation Unit, this man called Mustafa
Mustafa arrested me
For the second time, for about 15 days. He tortured, beat, and insulted me
Of course, they found no cigarettes with me
The emir of the Search Unit was the same Mustafa al-Muslih
Known as Abu Seif
And another man called Ibrahim al-Ali al-Khayheet
From the Ghanem al-Zahir clan, living near the Jazra Junction in Raqqa
Known as Abu Hudhayfa
Abu Hudhayfa was about 30 years old
The sharia official was Abu Hamza al-Tunsi
There was another man, originally from Sukhna, living on Sajiyah Street in Raqqa
Named Abu Zayd
His brother was the emir of the Islamic Police
In Raqqa Province, overseeing the whole wilaya
Abu Zayd was a sharia official
Second in rank under Abu Hamza al-Tunsi
He worked as a messenger between the court and the Hisba’s sharia office
As for how many times I was imprisoned
If I tried to describe my suffering, I’d need 3 months to finish
The torture and misery we endured
I was imprisoned 28 times
Some people might think I’m lying, but the locals know me well
My bag was always ready, because every 2 or 3 days ISIS would arrest me
The first time I was jailed in a security checkpoint, the charge was suspicion
I was imprisoned there for 56 days
The other 27 times were all for cigarette trading
My detentions ranged between 10 to 15 days, sometimes up to 2 months
Then they’d release me, since they found no evidence, and I was very cautious around them