The last time
They
Launched a campaign against cigarette sellers, and ISIS members specifically targeted me
Me and 2 or 3 other people
7 people, including me, were sentenced to qisas [execution by retribution]
They sentenced them to qisas with me too
They summoned me and took me by deceit
They tricked me and took me away
They called me on the phone and said, Are you Talal al-Shuweimi? I said, Yes, I am Talal al-Shuweimi
They said, Someone confessed against you
He said you sold him 2 cartons of cigarettes
That wasn’t true at all
Because I hadn’t personally sold cigarettes for about a year
Yes, I was a cigarette dealer
But
When I was in the trade, I didn’t distribute or sell cigarettes myself
I didn’t distribute or sell them
When they summoned me, I told them, I’ll come right away
I got in my car and went to the Hisba, which was at the end of Sajiyah Street
On Atiya Bakery Street
And the Hisba emir who was on Sajiyah Street
Was named Issa, from the Jais clan, known as Abu Humam
And Abu Humam, before that
Had been a sergeant in the Political Security branch under the Assad regime
When he was a sergeant under the Assad regime and ISIS was established
Abu Humam came and announced his defection and joined the Islamic State
When Abu Humam summoned me, he had already raided my house about 10 times
Out of 27 raids, he came several times, knowing they’d never find cigarettes with me
One time he knocked on my door and called out, “Hey Shuweimi!”
Your hookah is running, and we know you don’t have cigarettes, but bring the hookah and come
So I carried the hookah with its coals and placed it in his car
When Abu Humam summoned me, I asked him, Where’s the man?
Who testified against me? He told me, Rest for 5 minutes
Now I’ll call the man
When he called me, he said the man is here with me, come see him
When I went, it turned out there was no man there at all
He said, In 5 minutes he’ll come
So I waited 5 minutes
And said, Abu Humam, where’s the man? He told me, You sold cigarettes
I said, Sheikh
I swore to him by God, and honestly, I swear truthfully, I don’t sell cigarettes
And I don’t distribute cigarettes. I have workers who sell and deliver instead of me
What surprised me was his attitude, and I sat down
I told him, Abu Humam, let me tell you something. Even if I sold two boxes of cigarettes
You’re not smarter than Abu Seif. If he were in your place, he would’ve arrested me right away
The news would’ve reached Abu Seif before it reached you
He said, God willing, and started laughing