Those who conducted the interrogations with us
Were from inside the prison
Like Abu Yousuf the interrogator and Abu Abdul Rahman
The second one was from the al-Sahou clan
The group deliberately used people in interrogations who had strong intelligence connections inside the city
That’s one point, and the first and most important
The most important and strongest thing they had
Was that they had security agents inside the prison
They had security agents from our own people, from our towns, sadly
ISIS had security agents from our local people working inside the prison for money
For example, someone would come, and I’d look at him, and one of them
Was from the al-Bou Saraya clan, named Abdullah
He sat beside me, and I had been in prison for 10 days
When he sat and started crying, saying he was wronged and jailed over selling a pistol
I trusted him, as I had nothing to hide
The group’s informants or security men
Would come acting like victims, saying they were innocent, and talk about ISIS in front of me, saying we’ll get out tomorrow
And say, God is generous, and promise that such-and-such faction would enter the city
So the person in front of them would confess and start talking
These were the ones ISIS sent in as informants and internal agents
They were very intelligent people
One of these people was named Abdullah al-Asaad
His house was next to the Nabhan Glass Shop in Raqqa, and he was killed
While fighting in one of the battles
He started crying in front of me, and about 40 days later
He started crying again and told me that his mother had died
When I got out of prison, his goal was to get information from me
When I was released, I went to his house to offer condolences to his father
And I said, Keep your faith strong, Abdullah is crying and mourning his mother
Since I had been released, it was my duty to visit my friend’s family who was still in prison
I was shocked when his mother came out, cursing him and saying, May God never grant him success, and that she had disowned him
She said, He claims I’m dead, but he’s an informant for the group
There were many people who infiltrated others in this same way
Our people are kind-hearted and simple
So they might slip and say something by mistake, and that security informant
Would then
Report it to the security forces, and based on that, the person would be accused. Many people were killed that way
Stories like this were common