As for torture methods
Torture
We witnessed how they tortured people
The problem was that they had two styles
One underground
And another above ground, completely different
Like a person with two faces,and both faces were terrifying
As for the Hisba (religious police)
It had 20 faces
Regarding torture methods
Anything you can imagine existed. Many locals were imprisoned
And subjected to different torture methods,for example, crucifixion
Or they’d shackle your hands like this with cuffs
When your hands were raised with the cuffs, your ribs would tear apart from here
When Abu Seif lifted the prisoner,he was a huge man from eating too much Western food
God gave him the strength to eat 4 or 5 sandwiches
At the expense of the so-called caliphate
He was very strong, while I was weak
He would grab me by the neck and lift me about 20 or 30 centimeters off the ground
My legs would kick violently, just like in American movies
I couldn’t walk or breathe from the pain in my chest
I had tonsillitis, my ribs were broken, and to this day I still suffer chest pain
At that time
The guys, God bless them, took care of me for about 68 days
They would take me to the toilets, bathe me, and cared for me well
Among them were Ibrahim Abu Nashwa and Ibrahim Ayyoub, known as Shantar
All the guys who were with me in prison were kind and helped me in every way
I was never cared for in my life the way those six men cared for me when I was the seventh
When I was broken and my ribs were shattered in prison