Out of fear and terror
My ribs and legs could barely move
In the room above us there were solitary cells, each about one square meter, with a ceiling
Barriwi carried me and we went up
He broke a small iron piece from one of the solitary cells
Then Barriwi started scraping the wall
The wall was coated with smooth cement
We discovered it was made of modern white stone, not black stone
Barriwi said, “Talal al-Shuweimi, let’s escape,” so we tried to run away
It was me and Barriwi
And Ibrahim Ayyoub, known as Shantar, was watching the door with Bara al-Ano
We started digging the wall and dug the length of about two bricks and the width of two more
But we were terrified, because each brick
Had two sides, one of them thick
The thick side was pressed against another thick side, with a cement layer in between that couldn’t be broken easily,it made a loud sound
Across from our room, one of the group’s members was standing guard
We were terrified
I went to the sheikh and told him, Out of fear, no one knows what to do,especially the sentenced ones
So I said to the imprisoned sheikh with us
My brother
Read to us from the Quran, maybe God will save us from them and help us escape
Or make them blind to us,things like that, which are close to sorcery, God forbid
But we were desperate, and a drowning man clings to a straw
As you know, I was sentenced to execution, and a drowning man clings not just to a straw but to the water itself
Trying to hold onto the water
The sheikh actually believed himself
He was a man whose house was on Mansour Street in Raqqa, sentenced to execution
On charges of sorcery
He said he treated people with traditional Arabic medicine
He went to treat a woman who had joint pain in her legs
And they arrested him for that, accusing him of witchcraft
That man started reciting
And it became like some satanic ritual, while we continued pounding on the wall
Hard, but the guard outside didn’t hear us
The guard sitting outside was an ISIS member who had just finished his training course
His name was Abu al-Yaman
Abu al-Yaman was from Aleppo Province
When we made an opening in the wall, one of us, a diabetic man
Named Ibrahim al-Ali al-Alkan, known as Abu Nashwa
Got so scared that his blood sugar spiked
He almost died
And he actually did die
They had brought us wool blankets
Because winter was approaching
We tore up those wool blankets, and also some other covers
When we broke through the wall of the Hisba prison, behind it was an investigation building on Sajiyah Street
There was a depth of about 7 meters
After 7 meters, there was the yard of a ground-floor house
Because of the pounding noise, the homeowner came out
He shouted, Who are you? I said, Uncle, I’m Talal al-Shuweimi, your relative
And Ibrahim al-Fakkash said, I’m from the Fakkash family, from the Shibli Salamah clan
We started crying and begged him not to report us,we were sentenced to execution
The man cried along with us
He started crying and said, My nephews, jump down quickly
So they wouldn’t cut off my neck with yours
And the man was holding a laser lighter for us
He looked at us and said, “My brothers’ sons, hurry up, the daylight has broken,” and when we finished
Ibrahim al-Alkan fell ill
And the last time we went out
The house of Emir Abu Seif was on Sajiyah Street
The Hisba (religious police) base was on Sajiyah Street, and the road was like this
Sajiyah Street is on the southern side
The Hisba is on the northern side, and Abu Seif’s house is on Sajiyah Street
The organization had taken that house from a Kurdish family
The owner was called Abu Sateef, a well-known bicycle repairman in Raqqa and on Sajiyah Street
So Abu Seif took his house
Abu Seif, the Emir of the Investigation, took the house of Abu Sateef, the Kurdish bicycle repairman
The Hisba base was across from his house, and when he went out
He saw that the wall had been destroyed across the width of about two and a half rooms
Suddenly, the security men surrounded the area and came up to us
They started shooting at my feet and separated me from the other young men
Then they brought us back again
For the case of crucifixion and suspension, and of course the beatings and insults