Our daily routine among ourselves
We had no real routine, only reading the Quran, crying, and supplicating
Asking God to free us and the nation of Muhammad
At night, we’d sit
Reciting the Quran and praying Fajr until sunrise
We’d fall asleep drowsy, still in our chains
We barely slept half an hour or less before waking up in fear,some crying, some deep in thought
Some would sit alone in the corner, imagining death
When they were about to execute one or a group, the organization would film an ISIS video
On a disc or flash drive
Abu Seif brought us a flash drive back then, and we watched it
It was like horror movies, we were sentenced to death, and he made us watch people being beheaded
May God not grant him success in this world or the next
He showed us footage of an execution slaughterhouse in Deir ez-Zor Province
Where they executed 35 people hanging from sharp iron hooks
One emir was carrying two men like this, wearing a short white robe,he was from Deir ez-Zor
He carried two men like that
He killed them and hung them on iron hooks
Then Mustafa, known as Abu Seif
Said to me, “Look, Talal al-Shuweimi, do you see the execution prep, Talal al-Shuweimi?”