There were mediations everywhere
But not before God Almighty,there’s no mediation, and no bribery works
When I was sentenced to death, neither my mother, my father, nor anyone could help me
Only God Almighty can help you
And your deeds help you in their eyes
But they still had mediations
One of my neighbors was detained
His name was Qusai Ahmad al-Omara,he paid them 5,000 dollars and was released
In the final days, for example
I was under the death sentence when the judicial committee arrived
They started bringing me my wife
Then they started bringing me my second wife
Of course, in exchange for money, whoever wanted the price of a motorcycle, I gave it to him
And whoever wanted diesel for his house, I gave it to him
There were many things I benefited from after my family found out that I was in prison
We started playing openly
When my family found out that I was in prison
My wives started
And even
Almost every day they came to visit me, one day they came, one day they didn’t
Of course secretly, so no one would see us outside
The prison was in a narrow corner facing my family’s house, and I saw them secretly
They brought silver and gold coins, and their food was now paid for by us personally
We were 7 people sentenced to execution
Every day one of us paid for the food, the seven of us, and this prison
It seemed that the jailers, the emir, and the rest of the group bringing food were all from poor families
When they brought food, they gave it to the other prisoners
Because the prison had two sections: one for the rest of the prisoners and one just for us seven
We seven took turns. For example, if it was my turn, my wife knew that today was my turn
She brought food for me and for the guards, like fried chicken one day and grilled kebab another
She brought us ready meals from the market, and there was plenty. My turn came once a week since we were 7 people
Every day food was paid for by one of us, so my turn came once a week to bring the food
The food bill was about 75 to 100 thousand per month, all ready food from the market for us
And the ISIS members started sitting and spending evenings with us
They chatted with us, and we bought nuts and soft drinks, though we were shackled
They trusted us and learned our story
They told us, “Your charge is collaboration with the Global Coalition, and you’re sentenced to execution”
That actually helped us a lot in planning our escape