When they tried to bargain with me
They bargained with me a lot, even the well-known emirs
There were prominent figures among them
Specifically, one from the al-Amer family and one from the al-Mukhtar family bargained with me
They told me, “Bring us fertilizer”
Fertilizer 33, the one they use to make explosives
They bargained with me to bring cigarettes and hide the fertilizer inside them for them
Many people bargained with me, not just them
Even Abu Seif himself bargained with me to work with him
And to pass on reports and information to him
He told me, “Whatever you want in return, you’ll get it”
I told him, “I’m not that kind of man”