One day, the organization took me
Abu Seif came to me. The first time, he came with Abu Khaled al-Idlibi and other men
They took me away
They said, “Come with us to carry out your sentence”
Of course
They took me along with six other men
Among them was a man named Abdul Karim al-Ghaffaf
He was from the al-Marandi clan
He was one of my uncles, and his charge was adopting Shia beliefs
An old man, about 80 years old
There was also another man from the al-Bu Assaf clan named Yasin al-Yasin
Anyway
There were six men, and I was the seventh
They took me in a car, and I felt that we had left the city
They made us get out, and there was a cool breeze in the air
They made us kneel on our knees
And when they made us kneel
One of the emirs said, “Remove the cloth blindfold from Talal al-Shuweimi’s eyes”
They removed the blindfold from my eyes
Then I looked to my right and left and saw that everyone was lined up on both sides
They told them, “You did this and that, say the two testimonies”
So they recited the testimonies, and each one was shot in the head
I looked around and the place was full of trees,it used to be a Baath Pioneers camp
When we were kids, we used to go there in summer for school camps during the Assad regime
One of them said to me, “Talal al-Shuweimi”
What do you want?
I said, I don’t want anything. You brought me here and sentenced me to execution
He said to me
They removed the cloth blindfold from my eyes so I could see around me
Among them were well-known people,some of the senior figures in the ISIS state
High-ranking figures who are still alive today
He said to me
Now we’ll carry out the sentence and get rid of you
Then another masked man came
And said to me
What is your last wish?
At that moment
I told him, to speak with my children
He placed the pistol on my head
He said, “Say the two testimonies,” so I did
Then he struck me
As if he hit me in the head, but he fired the shot beside my ear
When he fired beside my ear, out of terror and horror
My hands were tied behind my back, and I fell to the ground
From the terror of it,it was like an American movie
I mean, something
Something indescribable, something even the Jews wouldn’t envy you for
Nor the Christians, nor Israel, nor even black devils would wish to see you in such a position
They wouldn’t even gloat over you