As for me, there’s a saying: they asked the nail, “Why did you go into the wall?”
He answered, “From how much they hit my head”
I didn’t sell cigarettes by choice, but I was an employee
My salary was 12,000 Syrian Lira, working in the Water Authority
After I started working, Air Force Intelligence raided my house and detained my brother, taking him to Sednaya Prison
When they raided my place and I fled, I had 10 children
They needed food and bread
I bought a taxi without papers and drove it, but the income wasn’t enough
And cigarette trade wasn’t punishable by execution or anything like that
But the organization imposed execution on us, even though it wasn’t for cigarette trade
Their judgments became vindictive
They invented charges,collaboration, cigarettes, ammunition,just to sentence us to execution
I was forced into cigarette trade. I have children and pay rent for two houses
Every day I’d buy bread for 2,000 or 3,000 Syrian Lira, and there was no other work
With the organization, either you join them or remain jobless
So how could I feed my children?
Should I trade cigarettes to earn a living and feed them, or let them starve to death?
Just like many others, there were about 2,000 people
And I was under a death sentence