Prison had a huge impact on me
When I first escaped from prison
I started crying
Tears of joy, not sadness
I began kissing the ground
I looked up to God Almighty, crying and shouting, breathing in the air
So many things happened to me
Prison affected me deeply,like forgetfulness, for example
It left me with memory loss
Tragic events that scarred me
In my life, I never held hatred toward anyone
But they made my heart hard
They killed the mercy inside me as a human being belonging to humanity
They ignored so many rights,human rights, and my rights as a Muslim
As a father and provider for a family, for example
They stripped the mercy from within me
There are still many things inside me
ISIS affected me deeply, and I still suffer from what’s called forgetfulness
On top of that, the greatest hardship remains,that only God provides and sustains us
God Almighty is the Provider
For me, ISIS destroyed my life
Why am I still struggling today to buy bread?
Why am I looking for a job as a taxi driver for daily pay?
What’s the reason?
Because of an ignorant man
Because of an infidel
Who should be in prison for two or three years
God willing, may the Almighty take from my life
And give it to his
Just so I live long enough until he gets out of prison, to see him even for one hour
To settle my score with him
An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth, and the aggressor is the unjust one
Everyone dies once
Better that than dying every hour before your children