This is the room where they used to hide me
Where they used to hide me, and I was shackled
with a chain. There was a door here
Before, there was a door here, and here
was a door. They had locked me in
Because of how strict they were, there were three doors,
one door, this second one, and this third door
We were here, shackled with chains,
and there were iron bars here that they had placed
Here were iron bars that they had placed
We were chained up. The chain was here
The seven of us would sleep in this area
Here, there used to be iron bars shaped like this
At this same height, there were
iron bars. I would take off my clothes
And rub my body with ludaelin [dish soap], and climb up
There were pipes here. I would sit on them and squeeze myself through
There was a hole over there, with
green pipes, pipes for the water heater
I would talk to my wife and son. My wife and son came
After I sent for her, my wife and son came
I started talking to her. There was a metal ladder under the neighbors
This area, they used it as a bathroom,
this thing here, they used it as a bathroom
We never bathed because we were shackled in chains
This bathroom was only a bathroom in name because we were shackled in chains
From here I would look at the street
and at my wife. Sometimes they would sit here
From here, we pierced the wall. I would climb up using a plastic container
I would stand on a plastic container, look through like this, and I could see
Now if you point the camera from here,
I can see my aunt Najah's house
And how I could see my house from the east side
Here you can see my aunt Najah's kitchen on the right, and the rooms on the left
Whoever enters between the kitchen and the rooms is visible to us. We were from here
We would signal to them from here, communicating by gestures. We had no other way
This was their bathroom, and this was the chain
The problem was not here. The chain was tied here
We were seven people. Seven of us slept here, and I slept here
Ibrahim al-Bariwi slept next to me here, and Ibrahim al-Alkan slept here
Bara al-Hano was here, and Ibrahim al-Ayyoub here,
and Ramadan al-Jassim slept here
Sometimes Ibrahim al-Ayyoub would sleep in Ibrahim al-Jassim's spot
Then Shantar would come, that was Ibrahim al-Ayyoub's nickname. He slept
These are the marks from the iron bars. Look at
the ceiling, the bars were placed here
On the ledge from this side. Those are their traces
Everything you have seen here is factual evidence
Look here at the traces of the iron bars
above, on the wall and on the ceiling here
I would undress because my body was
so thin that my hands would slip out of the cuffs
And rub my body with dish soap
just to be able to see my family
And talk to them, and let them know I was still alive
I stayed here for about two months, two months or a little more