This was the office, which was fortified and used for the archive
This was a room, and here was a table
Here was a hall, and there was a hall for the solitary cells here
Now I will take you inside, come in
and see. Here there was a solitary cell
There was a wall here with two solitary cells, and more solitary cells here
Before entering here, there was a bathroom
Here was the kitchen and here was a room for the prisoners
This is the bathroom entrance, and this room was for the prisoners
This was a room for the prisoners and this was the kitchen. It was also fortified here
Come and see how it was fortified here
This area was fortified for the prisoners with iron bars
This is the kitchen for the prisoners in the second section
Not our section, but the second section