This is the prison entrance. This was
an office, and they would enter from here. There is an office here
It is currently closed. We will enter from another door so you can see
So you can see how you enter from another
door. Come closer to me, over here
Here was the office. You enter through this door. Here was the office
There was a room door here. Its traces are still visible now
The homeowners have made repairs to their house
This room door, there was an internal office for their sharia official
Here was the office, and here was
the emir, and here also was their sharia official
We will now take you to the second
floor. All these rooms were
This was a prison, and this room was for their members. The second room
The second room behind the bathroom
was also a room for their members
Now we will go up to the second floor. This was the office
This room was open like this, and it was an office for the sharia official
This was their internal office