This place was a kitchen
A small kitchen to prepare tea and other things for
the priest’s guests because this was the priest’s room
There was also a table
A desk table was here
He used to sit here and the others sat in front of him
This was Father’s room, here was the room
We talked about this kitchen
This was the guards’ room
The guards used to sleep in it
This room, come and see
This was the guards’ room
And this room we call in Armenian “Taganiya”
The Taganiya room, the committee room
In Arabic they called it the committee room
There was also a desk and chairs here, they used to sit on them
Interviewer: Committee of what?
Witness: Let’s say a subcommittee
Responsible for the church
Responsible for the Armenians in Mosul, in this room
And the other room was the accounts room
This room, careful
It was the same thing
It was the same thing, there was a table here
A desk like a table
I remember a safe here, the accounts room
They used to pay salaries and other things, this was the accounts room
This room was the reception room
Our bishop’s chair was here
This whole place was full of chairs, the entire room
Guests and others used to come
And the reception on feast days
After Mass we went upstairs
We drank coffee and ate chocolate
Anyone who wanted to congratulate another did so here
And inside was the priest’s room, Father’s room was here
Inside, here
This was his room
This room
I remember this room
This was the priest’s room
Interviewer: Do you remember the furniture that was inside?
Witness: There was a closet in this place, I still remember it now
There was a bed here
The cooler was here, and the TV was here, that’s what I remember
I remember it 100%, as if it were before my eyes
This kitchen
I have beautiful memories in this kitchen
It was on Thursday
We called it Good Friday
Father, may he rest in peace, every Thursday
Karikin died in Erbil
And Janet’s mother used to prepare the Last Supper here
We deacons and the priest ate dinner here
Before we did the consecration
These were the bathrooms, well known
This was their daughter Janet’s room
Of course it was a bedroom
Interviewer: The person you mentioned, what did he do in the church?
Witness: The priest, Father, he was the church priest
He was the one who performed the Mass, he was the priest
Interviewer: Did he live here?
Witness: Yes, he lived here
This was his house and his church
But he died before ISIS arrived
His name was Der Karikin
I called him Abu Janet, he was known as Abu Janet