This was the choir place
Girls used to come here and sing
And perform church hymns
There was an organ here
It was played by Janet, the priest’s daughter, here
The choir girls, all here
They were many, about 20
Over time
In the 1990s, the number grew to around 60 people
People emigrated and left because of the miserable conditions
In the end only 10 people remained
ISIS came and no one was left
This was their place
Interviewer: This choir you told us about
At what time did you practice it exactly, and in which rites?
Witness: During Mass, on Friday
We deacons would sing from below
Like question and answer
And they would chant from here
We performed the hymns here on Friday
And on all feast days, here