This room is the same room I told you about upstairs
They built it recently
In 2008 or 2010, we built this room
Rooms became scarce because of the families
We would come here if there was an occasion or a holiday
Whether it was over or not, we would come here to celebrate
Holidays and other occasions among us, this hall was enough for us
There were also chairs
There were only chairs, small events
Like New Year’s and other events
We would go out on the holiday and sit here
Coffee and things like that, there was nothing else here
Interviewer: Did you say there were chairs?
Witness: Yes, there were chairs around the hall
There was also a chair for the bishop
like the one I told you about upstairs
The same chair was here
Because it was larger than the one upstairs
Up there there was more crowding, and it was up the stairs
That was its purpose, we held small and lovely occasions
Interviewer: What year are you talking about for this hall?
Witness: 2010 and 2011, until ISIS arrived
Interviewer: If we talk about the
80s and 90s , what was this place then?
If you remember
Witness: In the 80s and 90s, I was a student here
I was a student here
This place
That room which I told you is the deacons’ room
Opens from here
I was a student here, I remember this place as mine
I was a student, and my teacher’s name was Digin [Madam] Mari, may she rest in peace
May she rest in peace, she is the one who taught me Armenian
We sat here like in a classroom, and we were little
We were eight or 10 years old, learning Armenian
We would come on Fridays
Cars would come, and they taught us
This was a classroom
And that is also a classroom, we will see it when we go out—there is another classroom
It was a small classroom
This was a classroom
In the 80s