Here there used to be a desk
You wanted a baptism certificate for example
You came here and asked the priest for a baptism certificate
Or a death certificate and so on
It was from here
An office room where he wrote whatever information you needed
For marriage for example
Marriage or divorce certificates, all of that was here
Here, the desk was here
In this place
Interviewer: And the rest of the room?
Witness: A place to sit
For example you came to get a baptism certificate
So you sat instead of staying standing, everyone sat
And there was the chair of the archbishop
The head of the Armenian community in Iraq
There opposite him
But here it was all chairs
Interviewer: The chair you told us about, where was it?
Witness: Here, in the middle
Interviewer: What is this?
Witness: This was the place of the archbishop, the head of the Armenians
The head of the Armenians, he sat here
Also two small chairs, to the right and left
Priests sat with him
Because he was of higher rank
It was a council, everyone who came sat there
Interviewer: What did the chair look like, was it ordinary?
Witness: A presidential chair here
In the middle a presidential chair
Interviewer: Was the chair built in?
Witness: No, it was wooden but first class
It was beautiful and had a cross sign on it
It was something beautiful
It was not something ordinary