This used to be a small garden
On days like these and at this time
Especially when we came for Mass on Friday
We sat here and the weather was nice, you know spring weather is beautiful
Those were beautiful days in this place
God willing they will return
And we will restore the church to what it was
And their families will come back, how I wish they would return
I am the only one who came back here. May they return
Mosul is good now, God willing
Interviewer: Ari, what message do you give to the families who left?
Witness: Those who left Iraq, it is hard for them to return
But those still inside Iraq, let them come back to Mosul
Their houses are still there, and the streets are fine
Mosul now is good and safe
Like the other provinces
Like the region, there is safety here
Let them return
So we can see Mosul full of life, and beautiful
God willing they will return