They brought me here in an
H1 vehicle
A closed one
Blindfolded the entire way
They dropped us off at Bourj [Tower] Prison
The road leading to the prison
was paved with gravel, not cement
They brought us down
Even the ones waiting for
us knew me by name
Interviewer: Describe in detail
how you were taken to the prison
We entered
The entrance was gravel, they
dropped us off from the car here
There was a small door
within the main gate
He opened the small door and said, lift your feet
so we could enter. We were blindfolded of course
We went inside
We walked about ten steps
They ordered us to face the wall
and left us like that for about an hour
We stood facing this wall
for about an hour
Then they continued
with us further inside
They brought us in
through a small door here
A small door
They brought us inside
Again we stood facing the wall
Again we stayed for half
an hour or more
Here, through this door
We entered here
They stopped us in the middle of the room then
made us spin around to disorient us
Then they stood us
facing the wall
Of course no one knew
which direction they faced
We stood here at this wall
We stood here for half an hour
After that they started
taking us one by one
To the interrogation room to
take our full information
To get the name and create a file,
all of it was done using a laptop
After that I was transferred
to a solitary cell
The solitary cell fits two mattresses
here and two mattresses there
Meaning it fits
only four mattresses
The most we reached in
the solitary cell was eight people
We started sleeping sideways
We pulled the mattresses toward the door where there was a space of about
one tile (40 cm), pulled the mattress and laid a blanket over it
And it became enough
for eight people to sleep on
Of course we slept, if you will
pardon me, like dogs inside it
And the toilet is over there
Its width is roughly two mattresses wide,
between one meter and a meter and a half
No more
Interviewer: Did you hear the names or noms de
guerre of the jailers you saw in the prison?
The interrogator's name
was Abu al-Baraa
He had green eyes and a
stocky build, decent looking
And there was also Abu Sulaiman,
he used to come to our door
This man was vile
He only ever called us pig
and similar insults
I will cut you to pieces,
and you I will throw over there
That was Abu Sulaiman, a tall man
And there was also a young man named Khaled,
known as Abu al-Walid, whose foot was amputated
A respectful young man, fifteen
or sixteen years old
His foot was amputated. He was also a jailer but he
came to the door with complete respect
Abu Sulaiman was filthy and Abu
al-Baraa had absolutely no fear of God
Interviewer: What was the charge they
brought against you to put you in prison?
At the start of the interrogation
they accused me of espionage
They were looking for
a phone on me
I told them, you opened internet cafes and the
shop owner registers names
In our neighborhood there was an
internet cafe owned by a man named Fahd
Of course he was
an informant for them
And now he has fled
I told him, this is my phone, I smashed it
in front of him and said take it and hand it to them
From the start of the name registration, I smashed
my phone and gave it to him
I did that so no one
would come after me
You can control yourself from the inside but you
cannot control those on the outside from crossing lines
Right?
Many people were killed
because of a phone
Because of blasphemy, people imprisoned with us received messages
containing blasphemy and they were told, you are accountable for it
Of course in this case
there is personal enmity
Interviewer: What dominated this place?
What did you feel while in this place?
Of course fear
was always present
The fear was not of dying in an airstrike but
of being killed
When interrogation summons began,
everyone fell silent
Everyone listened to what happened
in the interrogation room
Beatings to the head,
breaking of hands
And lifting us and slamming us
against the walls, that was the torture
Interviewer: Tell us about the
torture methods you experienced
Torture methods, I told you about
when I first entered
The first five days
I was still conscious
After that
He hit me with a tile hammer
It was white with a short green handle
Because he showed it to me and said,
I will make this eat from your skull
And indeed he did, this is the
mark of a blow on my head
And here is something like
a fracture in my skull
I remained unconscious for fifteen
to seventeen days, not knowing where I was
When I regained consciousness I felt like I had
slept the night before and woken up today
That was all I knew
Interrogation started at 12:05
and went until 3 in the afternoon
Sometimes until 2:30,
sometimes until 3:30
That was the interrogation
schedule of course
It was not ordinary beating, he was
hitting me with the hammer on my head
Meaning, do not hide anything
You know how
interrogation works
For example he asks you, how many times
did you travel outside ISIS territory
And you had answered twice,
once for work and once to visit
Then he says, you traveled twice,
and hits you on the head
He does not give you room to make
a mistake with any information
Of course from the start of the interrogation he
records you on the laptop with audio and video
He talks to you with headphones on,
listening to your previous recordings and comparing
Even if you spoke one word and there was a difference in dialect
between the rural Jazira dialect and the urban city dialect
He would beat
you for it
He demands you speak
as you spoke before
I endured a month of the
same daily interrogation
Perhaps only one day a week
passed without interrogation
But most of the month
they interrogated me
Of course there was no one left in the town
of Tabqa the interrogator did not ask me about
Of course most of his questions
were about people close to me
What is your job? What do you do at night? Do you sleep
or go to work? Where do you go?
Of course they were
afraid of assassinations
And anyone who had been with the
Free Syrian Army, they were wary of
Especially if they had not undergone
repentance, they remained under surveillance
Of course when they
came to my house
They sent a young man who was
one of my friends ahead of them
To make sure I was home,
then they came after him
Only two people came for me
In an H1 vehicle. One of them told me, Abu Muhammad al-Amni
wants you to come answer a few questions
From the moment I got in the car he treated me respectfully,
he said here is your blindfold, cover your head
Interviewer: During the interrogation,
did you know they were recording you?
Yes, I could hear
the laptop sound
When he talked to me he said, I will ask
you a question and you must answer
For example he asks me, what is your name? I say Humaidi,
he says wait and starts typing on the laptop
Of course how did I know they were recording me even though I was blindfolded
and handcuffed behind my back, kneeling
He told his assistant, point the camera
at him properly, he did not appear well
That is how I knew
I was being filmed
The second time they interrogated me he said, you know you were filmed
yesterday so do not make any mistakes with the information
I told him, whoever does something
does not make mistakes in it
More than once he asked me questions
that had nothing to do with them
Two people interrogated me
whose names I do not know
And a person named Abu al-Baraa whose role was
to finalize the information in the interrogation
He was like the prison director, he personally
verified the interrogation with you
In case you wanted to add information,
he would relay it to the previous interrogators
One of the interrogators whose name was mentioned
in front of me was Abu Ubada
At the start of my interrogation one of the members
mentioned his name and he said, shush, be quiet
Interviewer: Did something happen to you in prison that you
still remember, something stuck in your memory since that day?
All of my days with them
are unforgettable
You live your life here in constant terror, you cannot see
anyone, you cannot even see their faces
And your friends imprisoned with you, when one returns from the
interrogation room they would have told him, we will kill you
It was impossible to hear
any good news
Even your family does not know where you are
and there is no one to deliver news about you
The interrogators I went to, no one came out from them alive. Most of
those they interrogated were executed
Most of them were killed. Eventually only five of us from
the town of Tabqa remained and they took us
Among them was a young man named Idris, a Kurdish man
they arrested because of his son's birthday party
He remained imprisoned
for about four months
And also Shakir, they arrested
him and his wife
And there were also Kurdish
young men whose names I forgot
Over the passing days
I forgot their names
And with us was also
Abboud al-Shawakh
They used to suspend
him from the door
This entire door was used
for shabeh [suspension]
Of course in this corridor you hear nothing
but the sound of torture, God protect us
Women crying and men crying, women being
dragged on the ground and men being dragged
Here of course
Of course they bring prisoners, we hear their
screaming but we cannot see them
They brought us from the group cells,
we were in the group cell
In the last group cell over there,
the one we were standing at
They took us from there
and brought us in here
There was a wall here
A black door, yes it was black
We enter through this corridor
This is the corridor for
the disciplinary cells
Of course it fits
half a mattress
Meaning half or three-quarters
of a mattress, no more
Full of water
Some prisoners here urinated
on themselves in the same spot
Interviewer: Did you see anyone in
the disciplinary cells during cleaning?
Yes, we saw one person and
he was one of our friends
We came to clean the disciplinary cells
to bring our friend back to the group cell
We told them we wanted them to bring our
friend, we had requested him back
He was an older man who did
not have the ability to endure
They asked who would clean,
and I said I would clean
We cleaned him up
and brought him out
Interviewer: What was
this person's name?
The person's name was
I do not know if he
is alive or dead
I think his name was
Nasser or Sulaiman
We went through many names in prison,
we no longer remember most of them
This was a long time ago, more than six
or seven years have passed, we no longer remember
I saw many people from inside the
town of Tabqa and from outside it
Like Sheikh Hassan al-Sannaa
And also Kurdish young men, Idris,
Shakir, and Mustafa
Of course there were many people including Abdullah al-Rajab,
he was killed downstairs in the solitary cell
They shot him on the day
of the airstrike on Bourj Prison
During the first strike, he even took me
to him and said, is this not your friend?
He took me
He told me, lift your blindfold.
There was a curtain behind the door
He directed me like this and said, lift your
blindfold and look at the door
He opened the door and told
him to face the wall
He faced the wall, raised his hands,
then they shot him three times with a rifle
And he told me, so you can
see that your fate is like this
Then he took me
to the group cell
Of course this is the group
cell I was in
Interviewer: Were you able to communicate with anyone
in the other solitary cells? Could you hear anyone?
I was here, next to me was
a cell for women
The women would call to us,
there was a water hose between us
The wall was not fully cemented, we could not
see through but we could hear
The women spoke to us in whispers, saying if you get out
tell them I am imprisoned in this place
If you get out, tell my family
or anyone about me
Interviewer: Do you remember their names
or the charges against them?
I remember one named Warda
and another named Samah
Fatima
These three women
are the ones I spoke with
Interviewer: What were
the charges against them?
One of them was charged with
photographing ISIS headquarters
They confirmed it through her phone,
they found the evidence against her
Of course she was executed
at a well by the river
Designated only for women
Of course the torture of women
was beyond description
The screaming of women
Interrogation of women was from
4 AM until 6 AM
This time was
designated for women only
From 4 AM until 5 or 6 AM
was the women's interrogation
Of course people could not
sleep from the fear
Also on the topic, Mondays and Thursdays
were distinguished by severe torture
The food on those days was rich
and the torture was harsh
Even those taken for interrogation were
brought back carried in a blanket
And there are people who
died under torture
One of them was a young man named
Khalaf from the village of Salhabiya
They took him to the corridor
and executed him there
He was executed
in the corridor
Interviewer: You mentioned women were in the solitary cell next
to you. Were there women working as jailers?
No
Interviewer: How were
the women treated?
The jailer would lead the
woman with a stick in his hand
He would slide the blindfold under
the door for her to cover her eyes
He opens the door and makes her hold the stick
and tells her to keep holding it, then leads her
We would hear him say, keep holding
the stick and lift your foot
Through this door, go inside
We would hear the sound of their heads being struck with
Lakhdar Brahimi, a hose used for torture
Of course we could hear
the sound of the blow to the head
They only struck the head, a woman
was only struck on her head
As for the food,
they served good food
There were breakfast,
lunch, and dinner meals
They served clean food
I swear to God
their food was clean
As a prisoner you never
lacked food
Whenever you knocked on the door asking
for food they brought it at any time
If you suddenly felt
hungry at night
You know, we were smokers and we entered prison and quit smoking,
so our appetite for food increased greatly
As for food, they served
plenty of it
Interviewer: What were the meals
they used to distribute to you?
They served breakfast in the morning with foul, msabbaha,
falafel, and sometimes maamouniya with cheese
That was breakfast
As for lunch, all the
meals were cooked
All of them had meat
Either chicken meat or lamb
Interviewer: Was there a special day
or special meals?
There were Mondays and Thursdays
Some prisoners fasted on those days
Inside the prison some
prisoners fasted
Monday
On Monday they served stuffed vegetables,
eggplant and zucchini stuffed with rice and meat
Or maqluba
[upside-down rice dish]
And on Thursday they served mandi plus cola,
of course with lamb
These were special days when some prisoners
fasted on Mondays and Thursdays
So they would separate
the fasting prisoners
They honored those fasting with food,
and also honored them during interrogation
Even when they took them for interrogation
they brought them back carried in a blanket
Interviewer: Did you witness sick cases in the prison?
Did you see a sick person or did you get sick yourself?
As for illness
They did not ignore any illness
Whenever you knocked on the door
and told them you were sick
They brought medicine to your cell. If you did
not improve, they took you to the hospital
And if you needed to stay in the hospital,
they allowed that
But the jailer is with you
The blindfold must not be removed from your
head even when you are sick
Then they return you to
the place you were imprisoned
I am one of the people who
fell sick inside the prison
I asked them to bring medicine and
they brought me the best medicine
They brought me injections and continued
treating me for two months
Due to the dampness and
our lack of sun exposure
Our bodies changed
As a result I developed
a severe allergic reaction
Yet they did not abandon us
Interviewer: How were the
bathroom conditions?
As for the bathroom
Of course hygiene inside the cell is not their concern,
it is your responsibility
They give you all types
of cleaning supplies
Like ludaelin [dish soap], giant brand, and Tai brand
cleaning powders, placed at the front of the bathroom
Divided by a cinder block wall
with a military blanket as a door
I was sentenced to execution
twice in this place
The first time he told me,
your sentence is slaughter
Of course I did not see a sharia judge.
The sentence is not pronounced like this
From our time here we learned that the
sentence is pronounced in front of you
The first time I was sentenced to slaughter, they dressed
me in an orange jumpsuit in the morning
They took me to the corridor
and brought me back
They told me, go take off the jumpsuit,
your sentence has been changed
He said these words, brought me back,
I took off the jumpsuit and gave it to him
In that moment the blood
froze in my veins
The second time, seven
or eight days later
Whoever entered my cell was not one of the
regular jailers, it was his first time coming to us
He told me, take this, your jumpsuit,
get yourself ready
Read the Quran, pray, and make your supplications.
Tomorrow morning you will be shot in public
At the Shasha roundabout,
as they used to call it
Of course in that moment all you
can say is God is sufficient for me
You take the jumpsuit
without doing anything
You take the jumpsuit and entrust
yourself to God, that is all
Of course your fellow prisoners
gather around you for comfort
The next day they came
and took me
They led me to the outer door
then brought me back
He told his fellow jailer that the sharia
judge had called them
And requested that no one be
executed until he arrives
I heard these words myself
That they would not execute anyone,
then they returned me to the group cell
He said, God has saved you,
what is happening with you
I told him I do not know
Perhaps I am innocent and God does
not want you to be the cause of my death
Then he returned me
After that I completed four months
and they sentenced me to repentance
Of course he told me that in five days
we will know when we are getting out
They took us from
here to Raqqa
Interviewer: When you finished the repentance,
did they give you anything in Raqqa to help with that?
Tell us about how you
did the repentance
I did the repentance,
I am an illiterate person
So I spent six months with sheikhs
and memorized from them
I memorized. The questions I could answer were questions that
literate people could not answer
Among them two lawyers who did not
achieve the results I achieved
Of course all prisoners study from books. I would listen to
what they read and review it once in my memory
During the repentance they
gave me a non-harassment order
They gave it to me because I saw one of their faces after
I removed the window to look at people
I just wanted to
see human beings
The repentance center was on the second floor,
the room door was not a prison door
The repentance room door was a wooden
door but the prison was below
Interviewer: Do you remember anyone who
was with you during the repentance?
During the repentance Idris was with me
and Kurdish young men
The same Kurdish young men,
Shakir and Nazim
These were the Kurdish young men who
were with me, and Mustafa as well
There were also four or five young men with me but I no
longer remember their names, they were from the town of Tabqa
There was also someone from the Junaidat family,
all of us did the repentance
Even one of the young men with us in the repentance
named Idris committed blasphemy
He was a Kurdish young man arrested
because he held a birthday party
He committed blasphemy
outside of the repentance
Who heard him?
Me and the young man who had a dispute with him,
and the problem happened between them, also Kurdish
I was the only one sitting with them. They were reading from
books and I was listening to them to memorize
So the jailer called for me because
he did not trust the Kurdish young men
He took me downstairs and made me
swear on the Holy Quran
I pray to God to forgive me because by doing
so I did not cause harm to anyone
And if I had testified otherwise
he would have been killed
Because he had completed repentance
and then apostasized afterward, as they told me
The sin falls upon you. Did
he commit blasphemy or not?
He pressed me greatly,
his name was Abu Muhammad al-Amni
Even when he saw that I had seen his face from the window
while he was getting into a white Kia car
He looked at the window and saw me standing,
so I closed the window immediately
He came upstairs masked, called
for me, and took me downstairs
He allowed me to call my family for three
minutes on the landline phone
He told me, I gave you this opportunity so you
do not tell anyone that you saw me
He had a distinctive
birthmark on his face
He was a person with clear
and distinctive features
He was a good and respectful man,
he had no business with us
I told you before, our room door was a
repentance door, not a prison door
Sheikhs came to us daily to teach
us creed, jurisprudence, and Quran
Those were the lessons they taught us. They also
encouraged us to watch the propaganda videos
They took our friends who were with us in prison and
brought us their execution videos to watch
This group cell faces the interrogation room and holds
prisoners who would stay for a long period
They assigned them most tasks like
going to the kitchen and cleaning it
With me was Abboud and some young men from city
neighborhoods, and some of them were killed
There was Abu al-Nour from the town
of Tabqa, also among the imprisoned youth
There are many names that were with us but I cannot
remember them. Idris was with us too, and Shakir
Interviewer: What was the difference between
the group cell and the solitary cell?
The solitary cell only fits four mattresses
while the group cell is very large
The group cell is a room
but much larger in size
The group cell is approximately eight
meters long and eight meters wide
Of course there is no ventilation hole,
no exhaust fan, nothing at all
There is a toilet and a
qazan [water heater]
Interviewer: Did anyone among you
think about escaping this place?
There was absolutely
no possibility of escape
Because when you look around you see
very thick iron bars
You look at the window and find it sealed with cement,
you cannot even see daylight, only the lightbulb
Interviewer: Was the light controlled
by them or by you?
No
Controlled by them, but they never turned it off
because of the cameras, they cannot monitor us without it
Sometimes the generator broke down
for five minutes
They would get anxious and fix it quickly,
it must not be off for more than ten minutes
Interviewer: How did they react
when the prison was bombed?
Of course we were prisoners in a basement,
we could not hear everything
We heard a sound from above during the first strike. We were
hit by three missiles and felt the building shake
But the sound was not too loud because the place
was fortified with sandbag barriers around it
As is visible in
that group cell
This group cell we lived in still
has the same bags to this day
These very bags, sandbags
As you can see, the thickness
of the concrete underneath
You cannot even think of escaping
and we were in a basement
There is no possibility
of digging to escape
Besides that, there were cameras
one here and another there
Interviewer: Did you write
a memory of yours here?
I am an illiterate person,
I cannot read or write
Interviewer: How did you
manage to get out of prison?
I spent four months
in Bourj Prison
The last strike on the prison was powerful. The next day
they gradually started transferring us to Raqqa prison
They took three of us out of this place,
with us was an Iraqi young man
And a young man named Mustafa
from Tabqa
We left here by car on the Jazira road, crossed the river
using barges that transport people and cars
The van boarded the barge
and we crossed to the city of Raqqa
At this point our sentence
had been handed down
We went to do the repentance
but when, we did not know
But after we arrived there
The interrogator Abu al-Baraa entrusted
us to them as a safekeeping
He tells them, these are entrusted to you
because the repentance course was closed
So when the current repentance course ends
they would include us in the new one
They left us at Point 11, at the Black
Stadium, which is well known
There is a room downstairs
that has mirrors
That was all we knew
I stayed there for a month and also
stayed a month for the repentance
Here things got confused for me,
I was sentenced to execution
And I saw judges who uncovered my
face and took me upstairs
They asked me my name. I told them Humaidi, they
looked at the name they had and it was Hamid
There had been a mix-up
in the names
Of course they removed my blindfold and I saw their faces because
I had been sentenced to execution by firing squad in public
When they realized they had the wrong name they
threatened me not to tell anyone I saw their faces
Then they returned me downstairs because I had dared to speak up. Since I was
going to die anyway, I told them how can you sentence me when I came as an entrusted person
He asked me my name, and here they remembered to ask
my name. They even broke my ID card
He broke my ID card
into four pieces, as you can see
I started looking at my name
This is my ID card
He broke it into more
than three pieces
He broke it from here and
split it lengthwise like this
When he saw the name he said, this is not the
person wanted for execution
Here they started warning me to pretend I saw nothing, and the last
thing they said was I would take this man's place if I said anything
Interviewer: Was there a difference in treatment
between Bourj Prison and the Stadium Prison?
Here at first the treatment was bad
until our sentence was handed down
We did not know our sentence had been handed
down, but things started to improve
We were placed in a group cell
and many things became available
There we would get a cup
of tea with every meal
Here there was a thermos for tea,
and you made your own coffee
Anything you wanted, he would take you to the
kitchen to get whatever you needed
Interviewer: What has changed about this place
between the past and the present?
The cinder blocks were removed, and the walls
dividing sections of the group cell were taken down
The group cell was divided,
it reached up to here
Its length went up
to this white paint mark
Its bathroom was in the back
The group cell bathroom was large
And the solitary cells were here
Interviewer: Was the bathroom flooded? Were hot
and cold water available?
As for the group cell bathroom,
the electrical switch is with you
The switch in the group cell
you can flip it on and off
In the solitary cells only
cold water was available
Everyone shares one
water tank
Meaning there is not enough
time for the water to heat up
Interviewer: Could you shower whenever you wanted?
Did they bring you shampoo?
However you wished
As for hygiene, they encouraged it and
provided all cleaning supplies
They provided shampoo and soap, whenever
you wanted these things they supplied them
And the bathroom switch is with
you in the group cell
And hygiene is your
responsibility
Of course they do not like
to see the place dirty
And a person in prison will not
dirty the place much