They brought me here in an
H1 vehicle
A closed one
Blindfolded the entire way
They dropped us off at Bourj [Tower] Prison
The road leading to the prison
was paved with gravel, not cement
They brought us down
Even the ones waiting for
us knew me by name
Interviewer: Describe in detail
how you were taken to the prison
We entered
The entrance was gravel, they
dropped us off from the car here
There was a small door
within the main gate
He opened the small door and said, lift your feet
so we could enter. We were blindfolded of course
We went inside
We walked about ten steps
They ordered us to face the wall
and left us like that for about an hour
We stood facing this wall
for about an hour
Then they continued
with us further inside
They brought us in
through a small door here
A small door
They brought us inside
Again we stood facing the wall
Again we stayed for half
an hour or more
Here, through this door
We entered here
They stopped us in the middle of the room then
made us spin around to disorient us
Then they stood us
facing the wall
Of course no one knew
which direction they faced
We stood here at this wall
We stood here for half an hour
After that they started
taking us one by one
To the interrogation room to
take our full information
To get the name and create a file,
all of it was done using a laptop
After that I was transferred
to a solitary cell