They brought us from the group cells,
we were in the group cell
In the last group cell over there,
the one we were standing at
They took us from there
and brought us in here
There was a wall here
A black door, yes it was black
We enter through this corridor
This is the corridor for
the disciplinary cells
Of course it fits
half a mattress
Meaning half or three-quarters
of a mattress, no more
Full of water
Some prisoners here urinated
on themselves in the same spot
Interviewer: Did you see anyone in
the disciplinary cells during cleaning?
Yes, we saw one person and
he was one of our friends
We came to clean the disciplinary cells
to bring our friend back to the group cell
We told them we wanted them to bring our
friend, we had requested him back
He was an older man who did
not have the ability to endure
They asked who would clean,
and I said I would clean
We cleaned him up
and brought him out
Interviewer: What was
this person's name?
The person's name was
I do not know if he
is alive or dead
I think his name was
Nasser or Sulaiman
We went through many names in prison,
we no longer remember most of them
This was a long time ago, more than six
or seven years have passed, we no longer remember