As for the food,
they served good food
There were breakfast,
lunch, and dinner meals
They served clean food
I swear to God
their food was clean
As a prisoner you never
lacked food
Whenever you knocked on the door asking
for food they brought it at any time
If you suddenly felt
hungry at night
You know, we were smokers and we entered prison and quit smoking,
so our appetite for food increased greatly
As for food, they served
plenty of it
Interviewer: What were the meals
they used to distribute to you?
They served breakfast in the morning with foul, msabbaha,
falafel, and sometimes maamouniya with cheese
That was breakfast
As for lunch, all the
meals were cooked
All of them had meat
Either chicken meat or lamb
Interviewer: Was there a special day
or special meals?
There were Mondays and Thursdays
Some prisoners fasted on those days
Inside the prison some
prisoners fasted
Monday
On Monday they served stuffed vegetables,
eggplant and zucchini stuffed with rice and meat
Or maqluba
[upside-down rice dish]
And on Thursday they served mandi plus cola,
of course with lamb
These were special days when some prisoners
fasted on Mondays and Thursdays
So they would separate
the fasting prisoners
They honored those fasting with food,
and also honored them during interrogation
Even when they took them for interrogation
they brought them back carried in a blanket
Interviewer: Did you witness sick cases in the prison?
Did you see a sick person or did you get sick yourself?
As for illness
They did not ignore any illness
Whenever you knocked on the door
and told them you were sick
They brought medicine to your cell. If you did
not improve, they took you to the hospital
And if you needed to stay in the hospital,
they allowed that
But the jailer is with you
The blindfold must not be removed from your
head even when you are sick
Then they return you to
the place you were imprisoned
I am one of the people who
fell sick inside the prison
I asked them to bring medicine and
they brought me the best medicine
They brought me injections and continued
treating me for two months
Due to the dampness and
our lack of sun exposure
Our bodies changed
As a result I developed
a severe allergic reaction
Yet they did not abandon us
Interviewer: How were the
bathroom conditions?
As for the bathroom
Of course hygiene inside the cell is not their concern,
it is your responsibility
They give you all types
of cleaning supplies
Like ludaelin [dish soap], giant brand, and Tai brand
cleaning powders, placed at the front of the bathroom
Divided by a cinder block wall
with a military blanket as a door