The solitary cell fits two mattresses
here and two mattresses there
Meaning it fits
only four mattresses
The most we reached in
the solitary cell was eight people
We started sleeping sideways
We pulled the mattresses toward the door where there was a space of about
one tile (40 cm), pulled the mattress and laid a blanket over it
And it became enough
for eight people to sleep on
Of course we slept, if you will
pardon me, like dogs inside it
And the toilet is over there
Its width is roughly two mattresses wide,
between one meter and a meter and a half
No more
Interviewer: Did you hear the names or noms de
guerre of the jailers you saw in the prison?
The interrogator's name
was Abu al-Baraa
He had green eyes and a
stocky build, decent looking
And there was also Abu Sulaiman,
he used to come to our door
This man was vile
He only ever called us pig
and similar insults
I will cut you to pieces,
and you I will throw over there
That was Abu Sulaiman, a tall man
And there was also a young man named Khaled,
known as Abu al-Walid, whose foot was amputated
A respectful young man, fifteen
or sixteen years old
His foot was amputated. He was also a jailer but he
came to the door with complete respect
Abu Sulaiman was filthy and Abu
al-Baraa had absolutely no fear of God
Interviewer: What was the charge they
brought against you to put you in prison?
At the start of the interrogation
they accused me of espionage
They were looking for
a phone on me
I told them, you opened internet cafes and the
shop owner registers names
In our neighborhood there was an
internet cafe owned by a man named Fahd
Of course he was
an informant for them
And now he has fled
I told him, this is my phone, I smashed it
in front of him and said take it and hand it to them
From the start of the name registration, I smashed
my phone and gave it to him
I did that so no one
would come after me
You can control yourself from the inside but you
cannot control those on the outside from crossing lines
Right?
Many people were killed
because of a phone
Because of blasphemy, people imprisoned with us received messages
containing blasphemy and they were told, you are accountable for it
Of course in this case
there is personal enmity
Interviewer: What dominated this place?
What did you feel while in this place?
Of course fear
was always present
The fear was not of dying in an airstrike but
of being killed
When interrogation summons began,
everyone fell silent
Everyone listened to what happened
in the interrogation room
Beatings to the head,
breaking of hands
And lifting us and slamming us
against the walls, that was the torture
Interviewer: Tell us about the
torture methods you experienced
Torture methods, I told you about
when I first entered
The first five days
I was still conscious
After that
He hit me with a tile hammer
It was white with a short green handle
Because he showed it to me and said,
I will make this eat from your skull
And indeed he did, this is the
mark of a blow on my head
And here is something like
a fracture in my skull
I remained unconscious for fifteen
to seventeen days, not knowing where I was
When I regained consciousness I felt like I had
slept the night before and woken up today
That was all I knew
Interrogation started at 12:05
and went until 3 in the afternoon
Sometimes until 2:30,
sometimes until 3:30
That was the interrogation
schedule of course
It was not ordinary beating, he was
hitting me with the hammer on my head
Meaning, do not hide anything
You know how
interrogation works
For example he asks you, how many times
did you travel outside ISIS territory
And you had answered twice,
once for work and once to visit
Then he says, you traveled twice,
and hits you on the head
He does not give you room to make
a mistake with any information
Of course from the start of the interrogation he
records you on the laptop with audio and video
He talks to you with headphones on,
listening to your previous recordings and comparing
Even if you spoke one word and there was a difference in dialect
between the rural Jazira dialect and the urban city dialect
He would beat
you for it
He demands you speak
as you spoke before
I endured a month of the
same daily interrogation
Perhaps only one day a week
passed without interrogation
But most of the month
they interrogated me
Of course there was no one left in the town
of Tabqa the interrogator did not ask me about
Of course most of his questions
were about people close to me
What is your job? What do you do at night? Do you sleep
or go to work? Where do you go?
Of course they were
afraid of assassinations
And anyone who had been with the
Free Syrian Army, they were wary of
Especially if they had not undergone
repentance, they remained under surveillance
Of course when they
came to my house
They sent a young man who was
one of my friends ahead of them
To make sure I was home,
then they came after him
Only two people came for me
In an H1 vehicle. One of them told me, Abu Muhammad al-Amni
wants you to come answer a few questions
From the moment I got in the car he treated me respectfully,
he said here is your blindfold, cover your head
Interviewer: During the interrogation,
did you know they were recording you?
Yes, I could hear
the laptop sound
When he talked to me he said, I will ask
you a question and you must answer
For example he asks me, what is your name? I say Humaidi,
he says wait and starts typing on the laptop
Of course how did I know they were recording me even though I was blindfolded
and handcuffed behind my back, kneeling
He told his assistant, point the camera
at him properly, he did not appear well
That is how I knew
I was being filmed
The second time they interrogated me he said, you know you were filmed
yesterday so do not make any mistakes with the information
I told him, whoever does something
does not make mistakes in it
More than once he asked me questions
that had nothing to do with them
Two people interrogated me
whose names I do not know
And a person named Abu al-Baraa whose role was
to finalize the information in the interrogation
He was like the prison director, he personally
verified the interrogation with you
In case you wanted to add information,
he would relay it to the previous interrogators
One of the interrogators whose name was mentioned
in front of me was Abu Ubada
At the start of my interrogation one of the members
mentioned his name and he said, shush, be quiet
Interviewer: Did something happen to you in prison that you
still remember, something stuck in your memory since that day?
All of my days with them
are unforgettable
You live your life here in constant terror, you cannot see
anyone, you cannot even see their faces
And your friends imprisoned with you, when one returns from the
interrogation room they would have told him, we will kill you
It was impossible to hear
any good news
Even your family does not know where you are
and there is no one to deliver news about you
The interrogators I went to, no one came out from them alive. Most of
those they interrogated were executed
Most of them were killed. Eventually only five of us from
the town of Tabqa remained and they took us
Among them was a young man named Idris, a Kurdish man
they arrested because of his son's birthday party
He remained imprisoned
for about four months
And also Shakir, they arrested
him and his wife
And there were also Kurdish
young men whose names I forgot
Over the passing days
I forgot their names
And with us was also
Abboud al-Shawakh
They used to suspend
him from the door
This entire door was used
for shabeh [suspension]
Of course in this corridor you hear nothing
but the sound of torture, God protect us
Women crying and men crying, women being
dragged on the ground and men being dragged
Here of course
Of course they bring prisoners, we hear their
screaming but we cannot see them