I saw many people from inside the
town of Tabqa and from outside it
Like Sheikh Hassan al-Sannaa
And also Kurdish young men, Idris,
Shakir, and Mustafa
Of course there were many people including Abdullah al-Rajab,
he was killed downstairs in the solitary cell
They shot him on the day
of the airstrike on Bourj Prison
During the first strike, he even took me
to him and said, is this not your friend?
He took me
He told me, lift your blindfold.
There was a curtain behind the door
He directed me like this and said, lift your
blindfold and look at the door
He opened the door and told
him to face the wall
He faced the wall, raised his hands,
then they shot him three times with a rifle
And he told me, so you can
see that your fate is like this
Then he took me
to the group cell
Of course this is the group
cell I was in
Interviewer: Were you able to communicate with anyone
in the other solitary cells? Could you hear anyone?
I was here, next to me was
a cell for women
The women would call to us,
there was a water hose between us
The wall was not fully cemented, we could not
see through but we could hear
The women spoke to us in whispers, saying if you get out
tell them I am imprisoned in this place
If you get out, tell my family
or anyone about me
Interviewer: Do you remember their names
or the charges against them?
I remember one named Warda
and another named Samah
Fatima
These three women
are the ones I spoke with
Interviewer: What were
the charges against them?
One of them was charged with
photographing ISIS headquarters
They confirmed it through her phone,
they found the evidence against her
Of course she was executed
at a well by the river
Designated only for women
Of course the torture of women
was beyond description
The screaming of women
Interrogation of women was from
4 AM until 6 AM
This time was
designated for women only
From 4 AM until 5 or 6 AM
was the women's interrogation
Of course people could not
sleep from the fear
Also on the topic, Mondays and Thursdays
were distinguished by severe torture
The food on those days was rich
and the torture was harsh
Even those taken for interrogation were
brought back carried in a blanket
And there are people who
died under torture
One of them was a young man named
Khalaf from the village of Salhabiya
They took him to the corridor
and executed him there
He was executed
in the corridor
Interviewer: You mentioned women were in the solitary cell next
to you. Were there women working as jailers?
No
Interviewer: How were
the women treated?
The jailer would lead the
woman with a stick in his hand
He would slide the blindfold under
the door for her to cover her eyes
He opens the door and makes her hold the stick
and tells her to keep holding it, then leads her
We would hear him say, keep holding
the stick and lift your foot
Through this door, go inside
We would hear the sound of their heads being struck with
Lakhdar Brahimi, a hose used for torture
Of course we could hear
the sound of the blow to the head
They only struck the head, a woman
was only struck on her head