I was sentenced to execution
twice in this place
The first time he told me,
your sentence is slaughter
Of course I did not see a sharia judge.
The sentence is not pronounced like this
From our time here we learned that the
sentence is pronounced in front of you
The first time I was sentenced to slaughter, they dressed
me in an orange jumpsuit in the morning
They took me to the corridor
and brought me back
They told me, go take off the jumpsuit,
your sentence has been changed
He said these words, brought me back,
I took off the jumpsuit and gave it to him
In that moment the blood
froze in my veins
The second time, seven
or eight days later
Whoever entered my cell was not one of the
regular jailers, it was his first time coming to us
He told me, take this, your jumpsuit,
get yourself ready
Read the Quran, pray, and make your supplications.
Tomorrow morning you will be shot in public
At the Shasha roundabout,
as they used to call it
Of course in that moment all you
can say is God is sufficient for me
You take the jumpsuit
without doing anything
You take the jumpsuit and entrust
yourself to God, that is all
Of course your fellow prisoners
gather around you for comfort
The next day they came
and took me
They led me to the outer door
then brought me back
He told his fellow jailer that the sharia
judge had called them
And requested that no one be
executed until he arrives
I heard these words myself
That they would not execute anyone,
then they returned me to the group cell
He said, God has saved you,
what is happening with you
I told him I do not know
Perhaps I am innocent and God does
not want you to be the cause of my death
Then he returned me
After that I completed four months
and they sentenced me to repentance
Of course he told me that in five days
we will know when we are getting out
They took us from
here to Raqqa
Interviewer: When you finished the repentance,
did they give you anything in Raqqa to help with that?
Tell us about how you
did the repentance
I did the repentance,
I am an illiterate person
So I spent six months with sheikhs
and memorized from them
I memorized. The questions I could answer were questions that
literate people could not answer
Among them two lawyers who did not
achieve the results I achieved
Of course all prisoners study from books. I would listen to
what they read and review it once in my memory
During the repentance they
gave me a non-harassment order
They gave it to me because I saw one of their faces after
I removed the window to look at people
I just wanted to
see human beings
The repentance center was on the second floor,
the room door was not a prison door
The repentance room door was a wooden
door but the prison was below
Interviewer: Do you remember anyone who
was with you during the repentance?
During the repentance Idris was with me
and Kurdish young men
The same Kurdish young men,
Shakir and Nazim
These were the Kurdish young men who
were with me, and Mustafa as well
There were also four or five young men with me but I no
longer remember their names, they were from the town of Tabqa
There was also someone from the Junaidat family,
all of us did the repentance
Even one of the young men with us in the repentance
named Idris committed blasphemy
He was a Kurdish young man arrested
because he held a birthday party
He committed blasphemy
outside of the repentance
Who heard him?
Me and the young man who had a dispute with him,
and the problem happened between them, also Kurdish
I was the only one sitting with them. They were reading from
books and I was listening to them to memorize
So the jailer called for me because
he did not trust the Kurdish young men
He took me downstairs and made me
swear on the Holy Quran
I pray to God to forgive me because by doing
so I did not cause harm to anyone
And if I had testified otherwise
he would have been killed
Because he had completed repentance
and then apostasized afterward, as they told me
The sin falls upon you. Did
he commit blasphemy or not?
He pressed me greatly,
his name was Abu Muhammad al-Amni
Even when he saw that I had seen his face from the window
while he was getting into a white Kia car
He looked at the window and saw me standing,
so I closed the window immediately
He came upstairs masked, called
for me, and took me downstairs
He allowed me to call my family for three
minutes on the landline phone
He told me, I gave you this opportunity so you
do not tell anyone that you saw me
He had a distinctive
birthmark on his face
He was a person with clear
and distinctive features
He was a good and respectful man,
he had no business with us
I told you before, our room door was a
repentance door, not a prison door
Sheikhs came to us daily to teach
us creed, jurisprudence, and Quran
Those were the lessons they taught us. They also
encouraged us to watch the propaganda videos
They took our friends who were with us in prison and
brought us their execution videos to watch