Here on this door they used to
shackle the prisoners
We could not see them but we spoke
to them from under the door
A friend of ours was also shackled
here, we used to talk to him
Interviewer: Can you
mention his name?
The young man's name was Abboud, he was
from our area, from the town of Tabqa
I kept talking to him
Even when the jailer came he would ask
him: Abboud, does your hand hurt?
He would say yes
Then he would tighten the handcuffs
until Abboud screamed in pain
Of course Abboud was suspended from the door because
of the blindfold incident in the interrogation room
Interviewer: Where was
the interrogation room?
The interrogation room is here
Of course there was a cinder block wall here dividing
the room, with a black door in it
From the moment you enter you take
off your shoes because of the carpet
You enter here and he would
be sitting like this
Sitting here
Of course it was laid out with
Gulf-style carpet and mattresses
From under the blindfold I could
see the color of the carpet
You sit kneeling with your
hands cuffed behind your back
He starts asking questions
and you answer them
Whatever question he asks
you must answer
Interviewer: Did they beat or torture you
in the interrogation room? How did they torture you?
They would sit you here with one person standing
behind you and another from this direction
Then you hear the sound of
a pistol being loaded
He tells the one holding the
pistol: finish him off
Then he runs his hand like this
past your ear
He keeps circling around you while the
other one strikes you with the hammer
Or with the Lakhdar Brahimi
hose on your knees or feet
Interviewer: What are the names of the torture
instruments you were tortured with or heard of?
There was the hammer,
I will never forget it
And the Lakhdar Brahimi
hose, it is well known
And there was the balingo
[hoist] for suspending prisoners
And here there was shabeh
[suspension] on the door
They suspended people, we heard their
screaming but we did not know who they were
Those we did not know,
we could not talk to them