This group cell faces the interrogation room and holds
prisoners who would stay for a long period
They assigned them most tasks like
going to the kitchen and cleaning it
With me was Abboud and some young men from city
neighborhoods, and some of them were killed
There was Abu al-Nour from the town
of Tabqa, also among the imprisoned youth
There are many names that were with us but I cannot
remember them. Idris was with us too, and Shakir
Interviewer: What was the difference between
the group cell and the solitary cell?
The solitary cell only fits four mattresses
while the group cell is very large
The group cell is a room
but much larger in size
The group cell is approximately eight
meters long and eight meters wide
Of course there is no ventilation hole,
no exhaust fan, nothing at all
There is a toilet and a
qazan [water heater]
Interviewer: Did anyone among you
think about escaping this place?
There was absolutely
no possibility of escape
Because when you look around you see
very thick iron bars
You look at the window and find it sealed with cement,
you cannot even see daylight, only the lightbulb
Interviewer: Was the light controlled
by them or by you?
No
Controlled by them, but they never turned it off
because of the cameras, they cannot monitor us without it
Sometimes the generator broke down
for five minutes
They would get anxious and fix it quickly,
it must not be off for more than ten minutes
Interviewer: How did they react
when the prison was bombed?
Of course we were prisoners in a basement,
we could not hear everything
We heard a sound from above during the first strike. We were
hit by three missiles and felt the building shake
But the sound was not too loud because the place
was fortified with sandbag barriers around it
As is visible in
that group cell
This group cell we lived in still
has the same bags to this day
These very bags, sandbags
As you can see, the thickness
of the concrete underneath
You cannot even think of escaping
and we were in a basement
There is no possibility
of digging to escape
Besides that, there were cameras
one here and another there
Interviewer: Did you write
a memory of yours here?
I am an illiterate person,
I cannot read or write
Interviewer: How did you
manage to get out of prison?
I spent four months
in Bourj Prison
The last strike on the prison was powerful. The next day
they gradually started transferring us to Raqqa prison
They took three of us out of this place,
with us was an Iraqi young man
And a young man named Mustafa
from Tabqa
We left here by car on the Jazira road, crossed the river
using barges that transport people and cars
The van boarded the barge
and we crossed to the city of Raqqa
At this point our sentence
had been handed down
We went to do the repentance
but when, we did not know
But after we arrived there
The interrogator Abu al-Baraa entrusted
us to them as a safekeeping
He tells them, these are entrusted to you
because the repentance course was closed
So when the current repentance course ends
they would include us in the new one
They left us at Point 11, at the Black
Stadium, which is well known
There is a room downstairs
that has mirrors
That was all we knew
I stayed there for a month and also
stayed a month for the repentance
Here things got confused for me,
I was sentenced to execution
And I saw judges who uncovered my
face and took me upstairs
They asked me my name. I told them Humaidi, they
looked at the name they had and it was Hamid
There had been a mix-up
in the names
Of course they removed my blindfold and I saw their faces because
I had been sentenced to execution by firing squad in public
When they realized they had the wrong name they
threatened me not to tell anyone I saw their faces
Then they returned me downstairs because I had dared to speak up. Since I was
going to die anyway, I told them how can you sentence me when I came as an entrusted person
He asked me my name, and here they remembered to ask
my name. They even broke my ID card
He broke my ID card
into four pieces, as you can see
I started looking at my name
This is my ID card
He broke it into more
than three pieces
He broke it from here and
split it lengthwise like this
When he saw the name he said, this is not the
person wanted for execution
Here they started warning me to pretend I saw nothing, and the last
thing they said was I would take this man's place if I said anything
Interviewer: Was there a difference in treatment
between Bourj Prison and the Stadium Prison?
Here at first the treatment was bad
until our sentence was handed down
We did not know our sentence had been handed
down, but things started to improve
We were placed in a group cell
and many things became available
There we would get a cup
of tea with every meal
Here there was a thermos for tea,
and you made your own coffee
Anything you wanted, he would take you to the
kitchen to get whatever you needed
What has changed about this place
between the past and the present?
The cinder blocks were removed, and the walls
dividing sections of the group cell were taken down
The group cell was divided,
it reached up to here
Its length went up
to this white paint mark
Its bathroom was in the back
The group cell bathroom was large
And the solitary cells were here
Interviewer: Was the bathroom flooded? Were hot
and cold water available?
As for the group cell bathroom,
the electrical switch is with you
The switch in the group cell
you can flip it on and off
In the solitary cells only
cold water was available
Everyone shares one
water tank
Meaning there is not enough
time for the water to heat up
Interviewer: Could you shower whenever you wanted?
Did they bring you shampoo?
However you wished
As for hygiene, they encouraged it and
provided all cleaning supplies
They provided shampoo and soap, whenever
you wanted these things they supplied them
And the bathroom switch is with
you in the group cell
And hygiene is your
responsibility
Of course they do not like
to see the place dirty
And a person in prison will not
dirty the place much