Name: Muhannad Mahmoud Saeed
From the right
side of the Old City
Born on April 18, 1993
Married
I work freelance
jobs to make a living
At the time of my arrest, I was
working on a potato machine
They arrested me even
though I had a permit from them
A permit to stay, since it was
during Friday prayer on Eid al-Adha
I got a permit from
them to guard the place
The games and the potato machine
The Hisba [religious police] car
came and saw me selling to children
He called out to me
but I did not notice
He told me to get in
the car and I refused
I told him I have a
permit, and I refused
He pushed me and shoved
me into a Hyundai Starex
There were two people inside
They were also prisoners, and
they brought them along with me
Interviewer: Alright, you said
exactly that it was during Eid
Witness: Yes,
during the major Eid
Interviewer: The potato machine,
was it for your work as a street vendor?
Or did you have a fixed
location to sell from?
No, I was standing on
the street next to the games
The machine is mobile
But during Eid I kept it
stationary next to the games
Interviewer: You mean the games are for
children? Witness: Yes, children's games
Interviewer: It was for the Eid
celebration? Witness: Yes, the major Eid
Interviewer: When
exactly was this Eid?
It was in the year
ISIS entered here
Ramadan came
first, then Eid al-Adha
Interviewer: You mean that
was in 2014? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: So at the very beginning of
their arrival? Witness: Yes, at the beginning
Interviewer: Alright, you
said you got permission
From whom did you get permission
to stay and not go to prayer?
From the Hisba, because there were
two of us on the machine, my brother and I
My brother goes to prayer
and when he comes back, I go
The one who gave me the
permit was far away from me
He was heading to the Clock Tower
area, sweeping through the shops
Calling out, To
prayer, to prayer
Then a Starex car
came from a distance
And at that time
Children came to me wanting to
buy as they were heading home
It was forbidden. According to ISIS,
selling during prayer time was prohibited
But I saw they were children who
wanted to go home since it was noon
And as I was selling
to them, they saw me
So they grabbed me
Interviewer: When he
saw you not at prayer
And did not know
you had a permit
Alright, after he learned you had
a permit, did he not let you go?
I told him I have a permit.
He said, No, you are selling
I told him I have a permit to
guard the games and the machine
I told him there are
two of us on the machine
He goes to prayer and
when he comes back, I go
It is not the first time
Because during Ramadan we were
selling on the Grand Mosque street
After breaking the fast
During the evening prayer,
one of us stays at the machine
And the other goes to prayer
When my brother comes back
from prayer, he takes my place
And I go to the mosque
Interviewer: He was not convinced?
Witness: No, and he told me to get in
I argued with them, then one
of them came and pushed me
And shoved me into the car
Interviewer: How many
ISIS members arrested you?
There were two in the car
Interviewer: No, I mean
from ISIS members
Yes, the driver and
another person with him
And there were two
prisoners in the car
Interviewer: There were other
prisoners in the car? Witness: Yes, two
Interviewer: So you
became three? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And only two
ISIS members? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Alright,
during the car ride
From the place of arrest
until they took you to the prison
Did it not cross your minds to free yourselves
since you were three and they were two?
We could not, because the road
was full of their cars coming and going
And they were spread
out all over the street
At first, they took us from
the Saraj Khana intersection
The Saraj Khana intersection
had one of their posts
And there is the other intersection,
the Shaarin Market intersection
That was also their post,
and this was their main street
Where the Hisba and
others were, all of them here
They were heavily
deployed on this street
Interviewer: The two people
arrested before you who were in the car
Where were they arrested from? Do
you remember what their charges were?
One of them was brought
from Bab al-Sham gate
He was at a wedding procession
Interviewer: You mean he
had a wedding procession?
He was participating
in a wedding procession
Interviewer: You mean at a
wedding? Witness: Yes, a wedding
At Bab al-Sham gate
they pulled him out of a car
He had shaved his
beard and drawn it in
And the other person was
for something related to prayer
No, they did not
blindfold us or tie us up
But he kept saying that their
conquests were delayed because of us
They no longer had conquests,
and I do not know either
Because you are not cooperating
and you are neglecting prayer
And you do not support us.
That is the kind of talk they used
Interviewer: What did
he mean by conquests?
Meaning they wanted to
conquer Baghdad, to reach it
Reaching Baghdad was like the devil
dreaming of paradise, as the saying goes
Interviewer: You mean he was telling you that
because of you they could not achieve victory?
Yes, they could not
achieve victory because of us
And another thing, they
believed they could conquer Rome
Interviewer: You mean they
blamed you for their losses in battle
Because you do
not perform prayers?
Yes, they would say God does
not grant us success because of you
You do not pray, you do not
help us, you do not pray for us
Interviewer: This conversation
was inside the car? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did you or
any of the people with you try
To respond to them
or argue with them?
You cannot respond to them
Interviewer: Alright, when they
brought you to the prison by car
And since these are old neighborhoods with
narrow alleys that cars cannot pass through
Where exactly did
they stop the car?
And how did they march
you to the prison gate?
There is a square
near the Biya church
There is a square there
He drove the car all the way
in, and they made us get out
In the square, and you
know this area is considered
A military zone
belonging to them
This means no one could escape
Because they were heavily
present in this area in particular
Interviewer: Why did they make
this particular area a military zone?
Because they seized the churches
belonging to our Christian brothers
They seized the
opportunity and took them
And turned them into
prisons and sharia courts
Interviewer: You mean because most
of this area's residents were Christians?
Yes, because most
residents were Christians
Interviewer: And they
took their money and homes
Yes, they took everything
And not only from Christians
but from Muslims too
They took their money
and seized their homes
Interviewer: I mean
why this particular area?
This area specifically because it
belonged to our Christian brothers
Interviewer: So they brought you
to the square near the Biya church
After that, how did they treat you
until they brought you to the prison?
They made us walk in a
line, one behind the other
One of them in front of
us and another behind us
And two of them on the sides,
and they brought us from this road
From there until
they took us inside
Interviewer: How far was
the distance you had to walk?
How far in meters, for
example 100 or 200 meters?
It was not a long distance
From this road, then that
one, in the Biya church square
Interviewer: Did they leave your
eyes uncovered? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And your hands
too? Witness: Yes, the same
Interviewer: Alright, as you were passing
through the square where the car stopped
Until they brought
you to the church gate
Which was the second
prison they put you in
Was it normal for people
around to look at you?
Yes, it was normal
But it was a Friday
and it was Eid
There were not
many people around
Only children and
young men were around
Interviewer: So they did not direct
abusive language at you or humiliate you
Interviewer: Did you not feel humiliated
when they marched you like this?
Yes, of course
Interviewer: Describe
the feeling you had
I was walking as if I were a
criminal, yet I had done nothing
According to them,
I was a criminal
As if I had committed something
terrible, yet I had done nothing wrong
Why would they make me walk in
front of people like a captive, powerless?
Interviewer: You mean you
felt humiliated? Witness: Yes
It is a feeling I
cannot describe
They were the scum of society,
and now they controlled us
Interviewer: So the
people who arrested you
Can you describe their
appearance, ages, and dialects?
Were they from the city of
Mosul, the outskirts, or the villages?
Were they from other governorates
or were they of other nationalities?
No, they were from Mosul, its
outskirts, and from the villages
Their dialect was not
the Mosul city dialect
Interviewer: Describe their
appearance and approximate ages
They were roughly
in their twenties
Because an older, aware person
would know their true nature
They did have older
people among them
But they had joined their ideology from
the beginning, believing they were right
But among the newer recruits, there
were not many older knowledgeable men
Men of knowledge
and understanding
Rather, those who
joined them were ignorant
And those who had no work
And those who took
pride in carrying weapons
And the result was what happened
Interviewer: Were they
masked when they arrested you?
No, they were not wearing masks
When they first arrived,
they were masked
When they attacked Mosul
But after that, they
removed their masks
Interviewer: So they
brought you to the prison gate
After that, did they
enter the prison with you?
Or did they hand you
over to other people?
No, they brought us to the
gate and others took over
And they closed the church door
Interviewer: When you entered
the church that served as a prison
How did they treat you and
what was their approach?
Did they take you
directly to the prison hall?
Or was there an interrogation,
recording of information and details?
How did they handle
your personal belongings?
And what kind of
questions did they ask you?
When we first entered
The person told the other
that this one neglected prayer
And that one was brought from
a wedding and was clean-shaven
When he heard that one of us neglected prayer and
the other was clean-shaven, he lost his temper
As if I had committed
something terrible
I swore to him that I
was not neglecting prayer
He said, Yes you are. Get inside
They recorded our information
and took our belongings
And during the search,
they found cigarettes on me
Interviewer: Where were the cigarettes?
Witness: I was keeping them here
I was wearing pants at the time
I was keeping cigarettes here, one
pack for me and one for my brother
Interviewer: After they found
cigarettes on you, how did they treat you?
They shouted and pushed me
And asked me where I got them
I told them they were mine, from a
while ago when I was working in the market
I had stocked up, and
this was what remained
Interviewer: And what happened
after that, after you went in?
They recorded
information like full name
Mother's name, and
place of residence
He took me inside. I told him I was not
neglecting prayer and that I had a permit
He said, No, you
are neglecting prayer
He pushed me and
shoved me into the hall
Interviewer: Alright, the person
who recorded your information
Do you think this man
knew you from before?
Interviewer: Or you did not know
him? Witness: No, I did not know him
Interviewer: How old was he
approximately? What did he look like?
He was about 30 or 28 years old
Dark-skinned with a black beard
Wearing the Qandahari
outfit and the Hisba robe
Interviewer: Was this person
specifically assigned to this task?
Or could any one of
them take the information?
There was a person
sitting at the table
He recorded the information,
then took the notebook and left
He went to that church
To the main computer to enter
the information, I do not know
Interviewer: Then where did they send
you? Witness: They sent us to the hall
We stayed in the hall, and
when afternoon prayer time came
They brought us in here
I performed ablution here
We prayed the afternoon prayer,
then about an hour after prayer
They brought us all out
and divided us into groups
They took us
upstairs to that room
They took us upstairs, and when
you looked at the prisoners there
This one was there for smoking, that one
for fighting, another for missing prayer
You look at it as
a tragic situation
There was no fear of being there
The fear was only from a possible
attack, bombing, or something like that
Then you would disappear,
and no one would know about you
Because they did not provide
you with any information
When they came to the Hisba
looking for me, they did not tell them
When they came asking there, they said, We do
not have anyone. We did not bring anyone here
And that went on until the
afternoon, until you found one of them
And you asked him and
begged him to give you a lead
In the hall you could not
talk because security was tight
You never knew. One of their members
could be planted and sitting among you
Gathering information and such
You could not speak.
Everyone sat in a corner
Or if you had a friend inside,
you sat with him in a corner
No one could mix
with the others at first
Because you did not know the
true identity of those around you
And they did not provide water
or food. They gave us nothing
There was one of them
who led the prayers
And they focused specifically
on the supplication prayer
They prayed over us, God,
deal with the oppressors
God, deal with the apostates
God, deal with America
And other supplications
They did not realize this
prayer would come back on them
Interviewer: Can you describe
the hall and what was in it?
The furniture inside it?
The bedding, curtains and
their colors, the wall color?
Can you describe the
smell of the place itself?
The place is currently destroyed
But previously it
was clean and tidy
And carpeted with red carpet
Striped carpet
like mosque carpet
And there were Qurans
And it was lit and painted
The place was clean
and well organized
Interviewer: You entered
this place without shoes?
No, without shoes. You take off
your shoes at the stairs and enter
Interviewer: Describe to me, was there
one of their flags hanging on the walls?
A wall clock for example,
or any of their slogans?
Their slogans and flags
were hung everywhere
Here a flag hanging,
and there another
And I think inside
there was a flag too
And there was a place closed off by a
curtain. We did not know what was behind it
We were sitting until just before
sunset, then they took us upstairs
Interviewer: The hall
they first put you in
Do you remember what it was
used for inside the church before?
No, I had never
entered it before
The first time I
entered this hall
Was during ISIS's time
But before that, we used to pass by here
since we are from these neighborhoods
When we went to the river,
we passed in front of the church
But we did not know
what was inside it
Interviewer: Alright,
inside the hall
Were you allowed to talk
among yourselves freely?
You could not talk freely
If you spoke and
raised your voice a little
He would immediately shout
from outside, Quiet. No one talks
Do not make any noise
Interviewer: When you
first entered the prison
When they took your
information and belongings
And put you in this hall as
a temporary prison at first
During all this time, did you not hear
prisoners being tortured and screaming?
Did you not hear anything
suspicious or strange sounds?
Did you not hear any
women's voices, for example?
No, severe torture
did not happen here
Severe torture happened when a
person was tried or did not confess
Would not confess, for example,
that he sold or traded cigarettes
Or for taking sedative pills
And most of them
were taking them
Pills like Tisirom and
others, and their needles
And there is a torture method
called hantoura [bed-like contraption]
With it, you would confess
even if you had done nothing
Interviewer: Was there
a hantoura in this place?
No, not in this place.
In another location
We were about 20 or more
people in the room, upstairs
In this small room,
roughly three by four meters
We sat next to each other,
leaning on one another
We just sat there doing nothing
Interviewer: Was there inside the room
mattresses or foam for sleeping and blankets?
There was no foam
The floor was just carpeted
Interviewer: Carpeted with
what? Witness: With carpet
Interviewer: You mean you
also entered without shoes?
Yes, we took off our
shoes and entered
Interviewer: Were there curtains
and windows in this room?
All the windows were
closed and sealed with iron
As you saw, they
were all sealed with iron
There was only a small opening
that let in some light and air
Interviewer: When
you entered this room
Did you expect to find this
number of prisoners with you?
No, I did not expect it
When I entered, I was
shocked that this small room
Had more than 20 people in it
Can you imagine what the air would
be like from everyone breathing?
Interviewer: What were
their approximate ages?
From the youngest to the
oldest prisoner in this room
And can you tell me what
exactly were their charges?
Most of them were young men
This one for smoking, that
one for being late to prayer
That one for shaving his
beard, others for fighting
They were of average young age
And some were older,
about 30 or 35 or less
Interviewer: You mean
there were no elderly people?
No, there were no elderly people
Interviewer: You mean the
oldest person was about 40?
Yes, approximately
When I first entered
The situation was tragic
You became a criminal in
their eyes for something trivial
As if you committed a
crime over something trivial
When you saw the situation before
you, it caused psychological distress
Some had been there four days,
others three, and others five days
And that was for minor issues
And there were worse cases
Some of them died
under torture at their hands
Interviewer: In this prison?
Witness: No, in another prison
The torture here was not considered
severe. There was flogging and such
When they transferred
you to another place
Then suffering was
written for you by God
Interviewer: Alright, from the
beginning when you entered the hall
Then they transferred
you to the room
And in between, you
went out for ablution
Did it not cross
your mind to escape?
Yes, it crossed my mind
I looked around hoping
to find a way to escape
And since I am from this area
I could escape over the rooftops of houses
and come down from any house to the street
But when I looked, I found
it too difficult, very difficult
You could not because
first, they were armed
And second, he could kill you
easily without caring about you
As if he killed a cockroach
Interviewer: Did you hear of
a prisoner who tried to escape
And they tried to kill him or did kill
him? Did you hear of such a case?
Not only in this prison but in
general, during your life under ISIS?
Yes, there was a case
of a person who escaped
He did not escape from
the prison but from the car
They chased him and
could not catch him
So they opened fire
on him and killed him
Interviewer: How was their
relationship with the victim's family?
Were they forced to keep
silent about his killing?
Or did they give
them blood money?
They were forced to keep
silent. No one could talk to them
The simplest thing for them was
killing. It was the simplest thing
Interviewer: Did any of them
point a weapon at you? Witness: No
Interviewer: Did they not point weapons
at other prisoners who were present?
Interviewer: When he argued with
them or debated them, for example
Witness: No one
could argue with them
Even if you were right, you
could not argue with them
Interviewer: You say no
one could argue with them
And as a young man, was the reason you did
not argue out of fear from within yourselves?
Or did you think arguing
with them was useless?
Arguing with them was
useless, and I am telling you
You feared losing your life
At the hands of people
who are scum, worth nothing
He would kill you, and that
was the simplest thing for him
Everyone here was Arab
There were no others among them
Interviewer: By Arabs, you
mean they held Arab nationalities?
Meaning they were
from Iraq, Iraqis
And most of them were
from the outskirts of Mosul
Interviewer: From the villages? Witness:
From the villages and surrounding areas
I personally did not see anyone
among them from Mosul city
Interviewer: You did not
see? Or there were none at all?
There were people from Mosul,
but not from our neighborhoods
Rather from areas like
Rajm Hadid and Hay al-Tank
And areas even farther away
But I did not see anyone from
the original residents of Mosul
As I told you, whoever argued
with them and pushed further
They dealt with him differently
That is why you could not speak
Whatever he told you, you had
to say yes, alright, you are right
You were expected to listen
Their words went in
one ear and out the other
Because he would sit
there preaching to you
Urging you and asking you
to pledge allegiance to them
You would look at him and think to
yourself, This is a prophet sent from heaven
Interviewer: Did they ask you to
pledge allegiance while in prison?
Personally, they
did not ask me here
I had a situation
at the hospital
At that time, my
daughter had a seizure
And her treatment
was by injection
I had her examined and she
was diagnosed with meningitis
The injection was expensive
because it was rare during ISIS's time
The doctor told me there
were injections available
In their internal pharmacy
Go down to them and see
if they will give you some
I went down to them
Their official was sitting there
I greeted him and he
returned the greeting
I told him, Sheikh, my
situation is such and such
This is my daughter and her
treatment is injections available here
He said, Yes
Are you one of the brothers?
I said, No
Interviewer: What did he mean by the
brothers? Witness: Meaning their group
Interviewer: Meaning ISIS members?
Witness: Yes, they called them brothers
He asked me, Are you
a supporter? I said, No
He said, Then we
will not give you any
I told him these injections
are available here
This is an emergency,
and I have no money
You know during
ISIS, a person worked
Just to get enough for
his family's daily food
He said, Pledge allegiance and
then we will give you the treatment
I looked at him and said, You
want me to pledge allegiance?
I told him she is a small
child, eight months old
If God has decreed
that she should die
Then God will take
back what is His
I told him, Do you want me to
lose my entire clan and my brothers?
Just to get injections?
If God has decreed death
for my daughter, she will die
And if He has decreed
life for her, she will live
He said, What are you saying? Seek God's
forgiveness. I said, I swear, as I told you
And if you want to execute me,
then do it and rid me of this life
I left him and walked out
Interviewer: Alright,
the ISIS members
The cigarettes they took from you or
from others or from cigarette dealers
Did they destroy them or
take them somewhere else?
They sold them
Interviewer: They themselves? Witness:
Yes, the members themselves sold them
They sold them. Let us say for
example from here they confiscated
Five or six boxes
They distributed them
among themselves
And sold them. They went back
to the market to be sold again
Interviewer: Are you saying this from
knowledge and experience or is it speculation?
No, from experience. There were people
who bought cigarettes from ISIS members
Interviewer: You mean they
sold cigarettes? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And they were the ones banning them?
Witness: They used to buy from me and smoke them
Interviewer: Basically,
they had the ban as a rule
Interviewer: The ban was on the basis that
it was forbidden Witness: It is forbidden
Interviewer: They ban
cigarettes yet they seek them out?
Yes, they sold them. They confiscated
them from you and sold them to another
And they sent another group
to confiscate them from him
Interviewer: Do you have a specific case of
an ISIS member selling or buying cigarettes?
Yes, they used to
buy cigarettes from me
I sold to the ISIS member at a
slightly higher price than the market
For example, at the
beginning of their arrival here
There was no severe siege yet
The selling price of a
cigarette was 1,500 or 2,000
And I sold it to him
for 3,000 or 5,000
Until the last
cigarette I sold to them
One cigarette for 25,000
I kept a personal
stock for myself
I stopped selling because
I could no longer go out
Because I used to bring them from
areas like Yarmouk, Tammuz, and Zanjili
There was constant
bombing every time I went out
I could not go out anymore
And there were five or six
of us who smoked at home
If I had not been selling
cigarettes and stocking up for us
Our daily earnings from work
would have gone to buying cigarettes
Interviewer: According to what you said, the price
of one cigarette was about 20 dollars at the time?
Witness: Yes. Interviewer:
One cigarette? Witness: Yes
As I told you, the
last pack I bought
A full pack that
they sold wholesale
Because wholesale
is different from retail
The pack was 250,000
When you went to the bathroom
It was outside prayer times
You would knock on
the door for the guard
And tell him you want to go to
the bathroom so he opens the door
During prayer times,
it got a little crowded
You had to be quick
So you did not delay those behind you from
praying, because they would be punished
Especially during
the dawn prayer
You had to be ready, and he would
wake you up an hour before prayer
Until you finished ablution
And went down to prayer
Interviewer: How was
the water? Witness: Cold
Interviewer: Was there soap or
cleaning supplies? Witness: Yes, soap