Name: Muhannad Mahmoud Saeed
From the right
side of the Old City
Born on April 18, 1993
Married
I work freelance
jobs to make a living
At the time of my arrest, I was
working on a potato machine
They arrested me even
though I had a permit from them
A permit to stay, since it was
during Friday prayer on Eid al-Adha
I got a permit from
them to guard the place
The games and the potato machine
The Hisba [religious police] car
came and saw me selling to children
He called out to me
but I did not notice
He told me to get in
the car and I refused
I told him I have a
permit, and I refused
He pushed me and shoved
me into a Hyundai Starex
There were two people inside
They were also prisoners, and
they brought them along with me
Interviewer: Alright, you said
exactly that it was during Eid
Witness: Yes,
during the major Eid
Interviewer: The potato machine,
was it for your work as a street vendor?
Or did you have a fixed
location to sell from?
No, I was standing on
the street next to the games
The machine is mobile
But during Eid I kept it
stationary next to the games
Interviewer: You mean the games are for
children? Witness: Yes, children's games
Interviewer: It was for the Eid
celebration? Witness: Yes, the major Eid
Interviewer: When
exactly was this Eid?
It was in the year
ISIS entered here
Ramadan came
first, then Eid al-Adha
Interviewer: You mean that
was in 2014? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: So at the very beginning of
their arrival? Witness: Yes, at the beginning
Interviewer: Alright, you
said you got permission
From whom did you get permission
to stay and not go to prayer?
From the Hisba, because there were
two of us on the machine, my brother and I
My brother goes to prayer
and when he comes back, I go
The one who gave me the
permit was far away from me
He was heading to the Clock Tower
area, sweeping through the shops
Calling out, To
prayer, to prayer
Then a Starex car
came from a distance
And at that time
Children came to me wanting to
buy as they were heading home
It was forbidden. According to ISIS,
selling during prayer time was prohibited
But I saw they were children who
wanted to go home since it was noon
And as I was selling
to them, they saw me
So they grabbed me
Interviewer: When he
saw you not at prayer
And did not know
you had a permit
Alright, after he learned you had
a permit, did he not let you go?
I told him I have a permit.
He said, No, you are selling
I told him I have a permit to
guard the games and the machine
I told him there are
two of us on the machine
He goes to prayer and
when he comes back, I go
It is not the first time
Because during Ramadan we were
selling on the Grand Mosque street
After breaking the fast
During the evening prayer,
one of us stays at the machine
And the other goes to prayer
When my brother comes back
from prayer, he takes my place
And I go to the mosque
Interviewer: He was not convinced?
Witness: No, and he told me to get in
I argued with them, then one
of them came and pushed me
And shoved me into the car
Interviewer: How many
ISIS members arrested you?
There were two in the car
Interviewer: No, I mean
from ISIS members
Yes, the driver and
another person with him
And there were two
prisoners in the car
Interviewer: There were other
prisoners in the car? Witness: Yes, two
Interviewer: So you
became three? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And only two
ISIS members? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Alright,
during the car ride
From the place of arrest
until they took you to the prison
Did it not cross your minds to free yourselves
since you were three and they were two?
We could not, because the road
was full of their cars coming and going
And they were spread
out all over the street
At first, they took us from
the Saraj Khana intersection
The Saraj Khana intersection
had one of their posts
And there is the other intersection,
the Shaarin Market intersection
That was also their post,
and this was their main street
Where the Hisba and
others were, all of them here
They were heavily
deployed on this street
Interviewer: The two people
arrested before you who were in the car
Where were they arrested from? Do
you remember what their charges were?
One of them was brought
from Bab al-Sham gate
He was at a wedding procession
Interviewer: You mean he
had a wedding procession?
He was participating
in a wedding procession
Interviewer: You mean at a
wedding? Witness: Yes, a wedding
At Bab al-Sham gate
they pulled him out of a car
He had shaved his
beard and drawn it in
And the other person was
for something related to prayer
No, they did not
blindfold us or tie us up
But he kept saying that their
conquests were delayed because of us
They no longer had conquests,
and I do not know either
Because you are not cooperating
and you are neglecting prayer
And you do not support us.
That is the kind of talk they used
Interviewer: What did
he mean by conquests?
Meaning they wanted to
conquer Baghdad, to reach it
Reaching Baghdad was like the devil
dreaming of paradise, as the saying goes
Interviewer: You mean he was telling you that
because of you they could not achieve victory?
Yes, they could not
achieve victory because of us
And another thing, they
believed they could conquer Rome
Interviewer: You mean they
blamed you for their losses in battle
Because you do
not perform prayers?
Yes, they would say God does
not grant us success because of you
You do not pray, you do not
help us, you do not pray for us
Interviewer: This conversation
was inside the car? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: Did you or
any of the people with you try
To respond to them
or argue with them?
You cannot respond to them