Interviewer: When you entered
the church that served as a prison
How did they treat you and
what was their approach?
Did they take you
directly to the prison hall?
Or was there an interrogation,
recording of information and details?
How did they handle
your personal belongings?
And what kind of
questions did they ask you?
When we first entered
The person told the other
that this one neglected prayer
And that one was brought from
a wedding and was clean-shaven
When he heard that one of us neglected prayer and
the other was clean-shaven, he lost his temper
As if I had committed
something terrible
I swore to him that I
was not neglecting prayer
He said, Yes you are. Get inside
They recorded our information
and took our belongings
And during the search,
they found cigarettes on me
Interviewer: Where were the cigarettes?
Witness: I was keeping them here
I was wearing pants at the time
I was keeping cigarettes here, one
pack for me and one for my brother
Interviewer: After they found
cigarettes on you, how did they treat you?
They shouted and pushed me
And asked me where I got them
I told them they were mine, from a
while ago when I was working in the market
I had stocked up, and
this was what remained
Interviewer: And what happened
after that, after you went in?
They recorded
information like full name
Mother's name, and
place of residence
He took me inside. I told him I was not
neglecting prayer and that I had a permit
He said, No, you
are neglecting prayer
He pushed me and
shoved me into the hall
Interviewer: Alright, the person
who recorded your information
Do you think this man
knew you from before?
Interviewer: Or you did not know
him? Witness: No, I did not know him
Interviewer: How old was he
approximately? What did he look like?
He was about 30 or 28 years old
Dark-skinned with a black beard
Wearing the Qandahari
outfit and the Hisba robe
Interviewer: Was this person
specifically assigned to this task?
Or could any one of
them take the information?
There was a person
sitting at the table
He recorded the information,
then took the notebook and left
He went to that church
To the main computer to enter
the information, I do not know
Interviewer: Then where did they send
you? Witness: They sent us to the hall
We stayed in the hall, and
when afternoon prayer time came
They brought us in here
I performed ablution here
We prayed the afternoon prayer,
then about an hour after prayer
They brought us all out
and divided us into groups
They took us
upstairs to that room