Interviewer: Alright, when they
brought you to the prison by car
And since these are old neighborhoods with
narrow alleys that cars cannot pass through
Where exactly did
they stop the car?
And how did they march
you to the prison gate?
There is a square
near the Biya church
There is a square there
He drove the car all the way
in, and they made us get out
In the square, and you
know this area is considered
A military zone
belonging to them
This means no one could escape
Because they were heavily
present in this area in particular
Interviewer: Why did they make
this particular area a military zone?
Because they seized the churches
belonging to our Christian brothers
They seized the
opportunity and took them
And turned them into
prisons and sharia courts
Interviewer: You mean because most
of this area's residents were Christians?
Yes, because most
residents were Christians
Interviewer: And they
took their money and homes
Yes, they took everything
And not only from Christians
but from Muslims too
They took their money
and seized their homes
Interviewer: I mean
why this particular area?
This area specifically because it
belonged to our Christian brothers
Interviewer: So they brought you
to the square near the Biya church
After that, how did they treat you
until they brought you to the prison?
They made us walk in a
line, one behind the other
One of them in front of
us and another behind us
And two of them on the sides,
and they brought us from this road
From there until
they took us inside
Interviewer: How far was
the distance you had to walk?
How far in meters, for
example 100 or 200 meters?
It was not a long distance
From this road, then that
one, in the Biya church square
Interviewer: Did they leave your
eyes uncovered? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And your hands
too? Witness: Yes, the same
Interviewer: Alright, as you were passing
through the square where the car stopped
Until they brought
you to the church gate
Which was the second
prison they put you in
Was it normal for people
around to look at you?
Yes, it was normal
But it was a Friday
and it was Eid
There were not
many people around
Only children and
young men were around
Interviewer: So they did not direct
abusive language at you or humiliate you
Interviewer: Did you not feel humiliated
when they marched you like this?
Yes, of course
Interviewer: Describe
the feeling you had
I was walking as if I were a
criminal, yet I had done nothing
According to them,
I was a criminal
As if I had committed something
terrible, yet I had done nothing wrong
Why would they make me walk in
front of people like a captive, powerless?
Interviewer: You mean you
felt humiliated? Witness: Yes
It is a feeling I
cannot describe
They were the scum of society,
and now they controlled us
Interviewer: So the
people who arrested you
Can you describe their
appearance, ages, and dialects?
Were they from the city of
Mosul, the outskirts, or the villages?
Were they from other governorates
or were they of other nationalities?
No, they were from Mosul, its
outskirts, and from the villages
Their dialect was not
the Mosul city dialect
Interviewer: Describe their
appearance and approximate ages
They were roughly
in their twenties
Because an older, aware person
would know their true nature
They did have older
people among them
But they had joined their ideology from
the beginning, believing they were right
But among the newer recruits, there
were not many older knowledgeable men
Men of knowledge
and understanding
Rather, those who
joined them were ignorant
And those who had no work
And those who took
pride in carrying weapons
And the result was what happened
Interviewer: Were they
masked when they arrested you?
No, they were not wearing masks
When they first arrived,
they were masked
When they attacked Mosul
But after that, they
removed their masks
Interviewer: So they
brought you to the prison gate
After that, did they
enter the prison with you?
Or did they hand you
over to other people?
No, they brought us to the
gate and others took over
And they closed the church door