When I first entered
The situation was tragic
You became a criminal in
their eyes for something trivial
As if you committed a
crime over something trivial
When you saw the situation before
you, it caused psychological distress
Some had been there four days,
others three, and others five days
And that was for minor issues
And there were worse cases
Some of them died
under torture at their hands
Interviewer: In this prison?
Witness: No, in another prison
The torture here was not considered
severe. There was flogging and such
When they transferred
you to another place
Then suffering was
written for you by God
Interviewer: Alright, from the
beginning when you entered the hall
Then they transferred
you to the room
And in between, you
went out for ablution
Did it not cross
your mind to escape?
Yes, it crossed my mind
I looked around hoping
to find a way to escape
And since I am from this area
I could escape over the rooftops of houses
and come down from any house to the street
But when I looked, I found
it too difficult, very difficult
You could not because
first, they were armed
And second, he could kill you
easily without caring about you
As if he killed a cockroach
Interviewer: Did you hear of
a prisoner who tried to escape
And they tried to kill him or did kill
him? Did you hear of such a case?
Not only in this prison but in
general, during your life under ISIS?
Yes, there was a case
of a person who escaped
He did not escape from
the prison but from the car
They chased him and
could not catch him
So they opened fire
on him and killed him
Interviewer: How was their
relationship with the victim's family?
Were they forced to keep
silent about his killing?
Or did they give
them blood money?
They were forced to keep
silent. No one could talk to them
The simplest thing for them was
killing. It was the simplest thing
Interviewer: Did any of them
point a weapon at you? Witness: No
Interviewer: Did they not point weapons
at other prisoners who were present?
Interviewer: When he argued with
them or debated them, for example
Witness: No one
could argue with them
Even if you were right, you
could not argue with them
Interviewer: You say no
one could argue with them
And as a young man, was the reason you did
not argue out of fear from within yourselves?
Or did you think arguing
with them was useless?
Arguing with them was
useless, and I am telling you
You feared losing your life
At the hands of people
who are scum, worth nothing
He would kill you, and that
was the simplest thing for him