They took us upstairs, and when
you looked at the prisoners there
This one was there for smoking, that one
for fighting, another for missing prayer
You look at it as
a tragic situation
There was no fear of being there
The fear was only from a possible
attack, bombing, or something like that
Then you would disappear,
and no one would know about you
Because they did not provide
you with any information
When they came to the Hisba
looking for me, they did not tell them
When they came asking there, they said, We do
not have anyone. We did not bring anyone here
And that went on until the
afternoon, until you found one of them
And you asked him and
begged him to give you a lead
In the hall you could not
talk because security was tight
You never knew. One of their members
could be planted and sitting among you
Gathering information and such
You could not speak.
Everyone sat in a corner
Or if you had a friend inside,
you sat with him in a corner
No one could mix
with the others at first
Because you did not know the
true identity of those around you
And they did not provide water
or food. They gave us nothing
There was one of them
who led the prayers
And they focused specifically
on the supplication prayer
They prayed over us, God,
deal with the oppressors
God, deal with the apostates
God, deal with America
And other supplications
They did not realize this
prayer would come back on them
Interviewer: Can you describe
the hall and what was in it?
The furniture inside it?
The bedding, curtains and
their colors, the wall color?
Can you describe the
smell of the place itself?
The place is currently destroyed
But previously it
was clean and tidy
And carpeted with red carpet
Striped carpet
like mosque carpet
And there were Qurans
And it was lit and painted
The place was clean
and well organized
Interviewer: You entered
this place without shoes?
No, without shoes. You take off
your shoes at the stairs and enter
Interviewer: Describe to me, was there
one of their flags hanging on the walls?
A wall clock for example,
or any of their slogans?
Their slogans and flags
were hung everywhere
Here a flag hanging,
and there another
And I think inside
there was a flag too
And there was a place closed off by a
curtain. We did not know what was behind it
We were sitting until just before
sunset, then they took us upstairs
Interviewer: The hall
they first put you in
Do you remember what it was
used for inside the church before?
No, I had never
entered it before
The first time I
entered this hall
Was during ISIS's time
But before that, we used to pass by here
since we are from these neighborhoods
When we went to the river,
we passed in front of the church
But we did not know
what was inside it
Interviewer: Alright,
inside the hall
Were you allowed to talk
among yourselves freely?
You could not talk freely
If you spoke and
raised your voice a little
He would immediately shout
from outside, Quiet. No one talks
Do not make any noise
Interviewer: When you
first entered the prison
When they took your
information and belongings
And put you in this hall as
a temporary prison at first
During all this time, did you not hear
prisoners being tortured and screaming?
Did you not hear anything
suspicious or strange sounds?
Did you not hear any
women's voices, for example?
No, severe torture
did not happen here
Severe torture happened when a
person was tried or did not confess
Would not confess, for example,
that he sold or traded cigarettes
Or for taking sedative pills
And most of them
were taking them
Pills like Tisirom and
others, and their needles
And there is a torture method
called hantoura [bed-like contraption]
With it, you would confess
even if you had done nothing
Interviewer: Was there
a hantoura in this place?
No, not in this place.
In another location