Interviewer: Did they ask you to
pledge allegiance while in prison?
Personally, they
did not ask me here
I had a situation
at the hospital
At that time, my
daughter had a seizure
And her treatment
was by injection
I had her examined and she
was diagnosed with meningitis
The injection was expensive
because it was rare during ISIS's time
The doctor told me there
were injections available
In their internal pharmacy
Go down to them and see
if they will give you some
I went down to them
Their official was sitting there
I greeted him and he
returned the greeting
I told him, Sheikh, my
situation is such and such
This is my daughter and her
treatment is injections available here
He said, Yes
Are you one of the brothers?
I said, No
Interviewer: What did he mean by the
brothers? Witness: Meaning their group
Interviewer: Meaning ISIS members?
Witness: Yes, they called them brothers
He asked me, Are you
a supporter? I said, No
He said, Then we
will not give you any
I told him these injections
are available here
This is an emergency,
and I have no money
You know during
ISIS, a person worked
Just to get enough for
his family's daily food
He said, Pledge allegiance and
then we will give you the treatment
I looked at him and said, You
want me to pledge allegiance?
I told him she is a small
child, eight months old
If God has decreed
that she should die
Then God will take
back what is His
I told him, Do you want me to
lose my entire clan and my brothers?
Just to get injections?
If God has decreed death
for my daughter, she will die
And if He has decreed
life for her, she will live
He said, What are you saying? Seek God's
forgiveness. I said, I swear, as I told you
And if you want to execute me,
then do it and rid me of this life
I left him and walked out