Everyone here was Arab
There were no others among them
Interviewer: By Arabs, you
mean they held Arab nationalities?
Meaning they were
from Iraq, Iraqis
And most of them were
from the outskirts of Mosul
Interviewer: From the villages? Witness:
From the villages and surrounding areas
I personally did not see anyone
among them from Mosul city
Interviewer: You did not
see? Or there were none at all?
There were people from Mosul,
but not from our neighborhoods
Rather from areas like
Rajm Hadid and Hay al-Tank
And areas even farther away
But I did not see anyone from
the original residents of Mosul
As I told you, whoever argued
with them and pushed further
They dealt with him differently
That is why you could not speak
Whatever he told you, you had
to say yes, alright, you are right
You were expected to listen
Their words went in
one ear and out the other
Because he would sit
there preaching to you
Urging you and asking you
to pledge allegiance to them
You would look at him and think to
yourself, This is a prophet sent from heaven