We were about 20 or more
people in the room, upstairs
In this small room,
roughly three by four meters
We sat next to each other,
leaning on one another
We just sat there doing nothing
Interviewer: Was there inside the room
mattresses or foam for sleeping and blankets?
There was no foam
The floor was just carpeted
Interviewer: Carpeted with
what? Witness: With carpet
Interviewer: You mean you
also entered without shoes?
Yes, we took off our
shoes and entered
Interviewer: Were there curtains
and windows in this room?
All the windows were
closed and sealed with iron
As you saw, they
were all sealed with iron
There was only a small opening
that let in some light and air
Interviewer: When
you entered this room
Did you expect to find this
number of prisoners with you?
No, I did not expect it
When I entered, I was
shocked that this small room
Had more than 20 people in it
Can you imagine what the air would
be like from everyone breathing?
Interviewer: What were
their approximate ages?
From the youngest to the
oldest prisoner in this room
And can you tell me what
exactly were their charges?
Most of them were young men
This one for smoking, that
one for being late to prayer
That one for shaving his
beard, others for fighting
They were of average young age
And some were older,
about 30 or 35 or less
Interviewer: You mean
there were no elderly people?
No, there were no elderly people
Interviewer: You mean the
oldest person was about 40?
Yes, approximately