Interviewer: Alright,
the ISIS members
The cigarettes they took from you or
from others or from cigarette dealers
Did they destroy them or
take them somewhere else?
They sold them
Interviewer: They themselves? Witness:
Yes, the members themselves sold them
They sold them. Let us say for
example from here they confiscated
Five or six boxes
They distributed them
among themselves
And sold them. They went back
to the market to be sold again
Interviewer: Are you saying this from
knowledge and experience or is it speculation?
No, from experience. There were people
who bought cigarettes from ISIS members
Interviewer: You mean they
sold cigarettes? Witness: Yes
Interviewer: And they were the ones banning them?
Witness: They used to buy from me and smoke them
Interviewer: Basically,
they had the ban as a rule
Interviewer: The ban was on the basis that
it was forbidden Witness: It is forbidden
Interviewer: They ban
cigarettes yet they seek them out?
Yes, they sold them. They confiscated
them from you and sold them to another
And they sent another group
to confiscate them from him
Interviewer: Do you have a specific case of
an ISIS member selling or buying cigarettes?
Yes, they used to
buy cigarettes from me
I sold to the ISIS member at a
slightly higher price than the market
For example, at the
beginning of their arrival here
There was no severe siege yet
The selling price of a
cigarette was 1,500 or 2,000
And I sold it to him
for 3,000 or 5,000
Until the last
cigarette I sold to them
One cigarette for 25,000
I kept a personal
stock for myself
I stopped selling because
I could no longer go out
Because I used to bring them from
areas like Yarmouk, Tammuz, and Zanjili
There was constant
bombing every time I went out
I could not go out anymore
And there were five or six
of us who smoked at home
If I had not been selling
cigarettes and stocking up for us
Our daily earnings from work
would have gone to buying cigarettes
Interviewer: According to what you said, the price
of one cigarette was about 20 dollars at the time?
Witness: Yes. Interviewer:
One cigarette? Witness: Yes
As I told you, the
last pack I bought
A full pack that
they sold wholesale
Because wholesale
is different from retail
The pack was 250,000