Of course, this was a mysterious secret for the prisoners
We felt something unnatural in the prison
Whenever any door opened, the
humidity level rose in a strange way
And in summer, the air became cold, and
very cold air came from the tunnel
Of course, we didn’t know there was
a tunnel until the prison was bombed
There was shelling on the prison
At that time, I had already been released, about a week earlier
Then Russian aircraft began bombing Burj Prison
They took the Muslim prisoners, as they
considered them, down into the basement
And the so-called infidel prisoners stayed in the main prison
Meaning that even if it was bombed, it didn’t matter,
they could die, they were already as good as dead
That’s when most of the prisoners
got to know each other in the basement
They hadn’t known they were imprisoned together
Of course, we left the basement because the humidity
level rose, and I started having trouble breathing
We couldn’t stay any longer
Because the humidity was extremely high
I still don’t know how they used that tunnel
or how they kept the prisoners down there
They even blindfolded them
At first, when they brought them in, they were
blindfolded, then they removed the blindfolds
And then they blindfolded them again—how those
prisoners endured and stayed alive, I don’t know