We will enter the prison now, and this here is the vehicle entrance
Into the basement
And the first step
In the prison routine
You go down and drive the vehicles into
the basement, and this was the car garage
For the prisoners’ vehicles and
for the jailers’ and interrogators’ cars
This entire area was a car garage
Sometimes a person would go out
They take him out of prison without a
blindfold, and he notices the prisoners’ cars
Someone might recognize them
This is the door of the investigation room and the group cells
And this is the main prison gate
We enter from here, and the first room
is the custody and investigation room
We enter to the right, where the solitary cells and group cells are
And on the left side, there is a kitchen belonging to them
There is a hidden group cell
And there is a regular group cell
From here we enter the corridor
of the solitary cells and group cells
Here comes the first group cell, then the second
And here were the solitary cells. They have
cleaned the area and removed the partitions
This room was divided into three solitary cells
The first, second, and third solitary cells
I visited all these solitary cells
I was imprisoned in the second one
On both my right and left sides, we
could communicate with each other
Interviewer: Faraj, tell us about
the days you spent in that solitary cell
When I first entered, they put me in the third solitary cell
I stayed two days, then they moved me to another
group cell for about a month, then back to this one
Here I lived the most tragic period of my imprisonment
Because on both sides of me there were women
We could hear the sounds of interrogation and torture
And worse than that, the ventilation opening of the cell
Overlooked the basement and the car garage
So when a prisoner was taken for execution
We knew he would be executed before he left
Because they carried digging tools, and we
heard them through the ventilation opening
They placed the prisoner opposite me in the corridor,
asked him some questions, then took him away
They disappeared for two hours or
more and returned without the prisoner
We used to communicate with each
other, as there was a bathroom at the back
We communicated with those to the
right and left, we could hear each other
After the women had left, they placed one of my
relatives, Huthaifa al-Haj Abd, who was killed
And Faisal Saad Rajoub, a young man from Homs, was also killed
We eventually gathered in one cell, the sixth solitary cell
It was the most dangerous solitary cell in
the prison, as few people ever came out of it
It was designated as a solitary cell without
a ventilation opening toward the garage
It was a small room where they placed those sentenced to death
So they had no chance to escape
It was far from the investigation room;
we never knew who entered or left it
In the other solitary cells, we could feel
when prisoners were brought in or taken out
Here, we never knew what was happening outside
Witness: We could only communicate a little
Interviewer: How many days did you stay here?
I stayed here 15 days
At first, they left me alone for about 10 days
Then they brought the young man, Faisal Saad Rajoub
We stayed five or six days together, and a little
further from our cell was another with two women
They brought in...
A well-known prisoner, so they changed everyone’s places
The young man and I
Were placed in the group cell, and
the women were moved to solitary cells
They took one woman, and the other stayed two days before leaving
After several days, they brought the male prisoner and placed him here
I communicated with him through the bathroom; that’s how we talked
He told me his name was Ahmad al-Hassan al-Ibrahim
He was imprisoned for the second time because of his brother Musleh
Who had been sentenced to death and was in the first solitary cell
He was chained to prevent him from escaping
This was the group cell, which was all divided but later dismantled
There was a ventilation opening here
Sometimes they would fire bullets
through the opening to break our spirits
Here, there used to be a door
There was a door here. Sometimes we
stood and saw a faint light in the corridor
Because in the end, we only ever saw the jailers
Everyone here wrote his memories
Then they repainted the prison
But later new prisoners came and wrote new memories again
Very few
Witness: At first, they gave a little...
Interviewer: Read us something that was written on the wall
For example, it says, Do not lose heart or
grieve, for you are superior if you are believers
This was likely written by an ISIS member,
because they often imprisoned their own here
There was much mutual accusation among them
The ISIS prisoner considered himself the victim, and so did the jailer
Interviewer: Were you tortured
during your time in solitary confinement?
Yes, in the first solitary cell where I was imprisoned, I was tortured
This place was designated for shabeh [suspension]
From the solitary cells, we could see
who was suspended and recognize them
I was suspended here
For about 10 hours, more or less
I was suspended here, then they brought a young man from Homs
He was kept hanging for three or four days
until he confessed to what they wanted
Faisal asked them, What do you want from him?
They told him
He had to confess that he was going to Idlib to join the Free Army
He said, As you wish, just to save himself
This solitary cell
When you first go to the investigation
room, the first group cell is right in front
They open the doors. My father
was imprisoned in the first group cell
So he could hear our voices as we were
tortured—me, my brothers, and my cousins
When the interrogator finished torturing us, he opened
my father’s window and said, How are you, are you fine?
Just to break him down
Interviewer: Faraj, you mentioned earlier that there were
disciplinary solitary cells. What was their size approximately?
Exactly, these are the ventilation openings
for the disciplinary solitary cells
Here they are, and there are eight disciplinary cells
The door entrance was here, but they later reopened…
All the partitions together, as if it had now become a storage room
Each cell’s area was no more than half a meter
Sometimes a person had to sleep on one side
Meaning that a slightly overweight person couldn’t sleep on his back
Interviewer: Approximately how many solitary cells were there?
The regular solitary cells were six
As for the disciplinary ones, there were eight
Eight disciplinary cells on one side and five on the other, so a total of 13
Interviewer: How long did you stay in the disciplinary cell?
I stayed in the disciplinary cell from one week
to 10 days, meaning my time there was intermittent
Interviewer: Tell us how you communicated
with each other in the disciplinary cells
When we were in the disciplinary cell, they would
let us go to the bathroom during prayer times
And the bathroom was on this side
We would communicate with the second group cell
The one next to us
Through the long ventilation opening. If you
called out through it, those beside you could hear
So we used to call each other from this side
Once there was a young man named Khaled al-Harbi, who was killed
He used to talk to me. My father and I were in the cell
when the jailer heard us and sent me back to solitary here
So through the ventilation openings we
used to communicate between solitary cells
But in a low voice because the investigation room was very close to us
Interviewer: Which group cell is this? We saw a label written on the wall
Which group cell is this?
This is the second group cell
My father and I were imprisoned
here for a month, then they separated us
Interviewer: Can we see the other group cells?
The other group cells have another door
Of course, this one
This iron door was completely closed, and when it was opened
Cold air would rush in
We’ll talk about that shortly
We enter from here
And here was the first group cell
This is the first group cell, where I was imprisoned twice
The first time I stayed for four days, not counting
this whole period of imprisonment I’m describing
Here were all the prisoners’ memories
I was imprisoned here with someone named Abdul Razzaq al-Barish
I was released, but he wasn’t. He and his brother Faisal were killed
We were imprisoned here together
And here my father and all my brothers were imprisoned
There was an electrical socket on this wall
We used it to communicate with group cell four,
whose door is far from here. We’ll see it shortly
We communicated from here, as there was a power
socket, and through it we could talk to each other
Just by hearing a knock on the
wall, we knew a prisoner wanted to talk
We would immediately come here and
speak to him, and the sound would be clear
Interviewer: What was the most
striking phrase you saw written here in the prison?
As I told you, there was a man named
Abu Madian, who influenced me the most
They erased all his writings in the other group cells
But here he had a small inscription
It was written here, though I don’t know if
it’s still visible. He wrote his son’s name
This is Madian
He used to write on the pillows and mattresses—wherever
you went, you’d find the names Madian and Abu Madian
His real name was Muhammad al-Hateel, but he was known as Abu Madian
He had spent 110 days in prison
And he was killed
He was a calligrapher, may God have mercy on him
Interviewer: Who were the people with you in
the group cell, if you still remember them?
In this group cell, there was Hassan al-Ibrahim imprisoned with me
Hassan Ibrahim al-Sheikh
Walid al-Haji and Mutasim al-Haji
And Muhammad Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi
And Ghanem al-Ibrahim. We were imprisoned together, along with several others whose names I forgot
Witness: But I’ve forgotten their names
Interviewer: Do you have any memories on the prison wall?
I didn’t write anything myself, but
there’s a note from my brother Ibrahim
We were imprisoned together for a while.
That’s his name here—Ibrahim al-Salama
He also has another name written here
And I didn’t write any memory here
Most of my memories were in the solitary cells
because I spent most of my imprisonment there
They painted the walls so no one could recognize
What happened to the prisoners
Now we’ll go to group cell four
Interviewer: During torture, where did it take place?
From where did you hear the screams of those tortured?
From the investigation room. It’s very close
So those in the first group cell, the other cells,
and the solitary ones all heard the torture
This is the investigation room
They used this door to hang the tortured prisoners
Like the other door, and this one too
Sometimes they would hang three people at the same time
You could only hear the groaning of those tortured
Sometimes the beating happened here
Then we’d hear that they were outside the investigation room
They might drag someone out here and start beating him
Interviewer: You and your father
tried to escape using a piece of metal
Yes, of course
Interviewer: From where and which direction did you try to escape?
Over there is group cell four, which is far from here
It’s a bit distant and separate from the
other detention areas and solitary cells
That’s where we were imprisoned in the beginning
So I tried to escape along with the others who were with me
ISIS used to take out one or two prisoners every four or five days
So we kept telling ourselves maybe we’d be next, maybe not
Then we were left alone
Here there was a large group cell, as they had removed the partitions
And this was the entrance door
The prison was entirely underground
And as we see, it had a ventilation opening about half a meter high
Here there is an old external staircase
to the basement, built since its founding
They sealed it off with bricks and cement in this way
We realized there was a staircase
and a door here, but it was blocked
There was an iron rod that one of the former prisoners
is believed to have pulled from the ventilation window
He left it there
We saw the rod and started planning to escape when the escape period began
They moved us to another group cell
That’s when I met my father in the first group cell
I told him that I and the guys with me were thinking of escaping
He asked me, How? Escape is impossible
I said, Yes, there’s a staircase, an outer door,
and an iron rod placed in the ventilation window
There was a young man named Ahmad Sinu and
another named Hamad, and they were listening to us
Time passed, and they separated us, and my father stayed there
Interviewer: Weren’t you afraid that Ahmad
Sinu and the others might be informants?
No, because we had been together for a long time, and
Ahmad Sinu had escaped some time ago from Raqqa Prison
So we already knew him before entering prison
He managed to escape, but they caught him again
He was sentenced to one year in prison
on charges of smuggling a Yazidi woman
When they first entered the group cell, they recognized
it because it was the largest one among all the cells
They found the staircase and saw the
iron rod still in place. No one had moved it
After some time, they began
The jailer ordered them to carry the winter bedding
Since summer had come, they
placed it on this side opposite the door
My father was an old man, unable to dig with them
So he stood by the door and kept watch
While they moved the bedding, they started
digging between the stones of the wall
Each day they dug a little, for a week
When they finally opened the wall,
they waited until the evening prayer began
Once the prayer had started, they escaped from the prison
Interviewer: How many people escaped?
Those who escaped were my father and two young
men, one named Ahmad Sinu and the other Hamad
Interviewer: Can we see the openings
through which you used to communicate?
This is exactly the electricity opening
where there used to be a socket
We communicated with each other through it
We weren’t afraid of the jailers then because they
were far away, and we could sense when they approached
We could talk freely, but those on the other side couldn’t
Interviewer: Did you have a specific time for the jailers’
rounds, or did you have a clock inside the prison?
We would hear the call to prayer and the
Iqama, during the prayer, they would pray
That’s when we took the chance to talk for five minutes or more
Until they finished, because the jailer
would then start his round of inspection
Interviewer: After your father and the
others escaped, you stayed in prison
Interviewer: Tell us about the changes
and movement that happened afterward
The next morning, the prison changed completely
ISIS became confused. We realized something
strange had happened
We knew that a prisoner had managed to escape
They gave us a standard uniform
and took away all our civilian clothes
They installed cameras in all the group cells and solitary cells
They even put up a curtain behind the door
They hung it on their side, not ours
Outside the door, there was a curtain
from the top to the bottom of the door
So we couldn’t see, because they sensed what had happened
Interviewer: What about the jailers who were on duty?
Weren’t they punished or transferred to another prison?
No, I stayed for 15 days or more
I never noticed anything like that
Interviewer: Did their behavior toward you change?
Yes, their behavior changed. They
stopped treating the prisoners with any respect
Before, we could ask them for small
things, and sometimes they would agree
But afterwards, they cut off all communication completely
They started checking the ventilation openings daily
Interviewer: Were you allowed to
go out for fresh air or see sunlight?
No, that was completely forbidden. They
never even thought of allowing it
Sometimes we went out to clean the corridor
But only by order
You could say it was a punishment
Interviewer: Did they give you
ideological lessons in the prison?
Never, no religious or ideological lessons at all
Sometimes we asked for books; they might bring them or not
Interviewer: You mentioned earlier that when you
prayed or recited the Quran aloud, they forbade you
What was the reason?
Because we all knew each other here
Sometimes they told us someone had
confessed to something and had been released
Then we’d hear him reciting the Quran aloud
They realized it, and eventually they banned
reciting the Quran aloud, and even banned prayer
Interviewer: When they took people
for executions and you heard the sounds
Tell us how the process went, and what you felt at that moment
It was psychological destruction. What hurt
me most was for the one being taken to die
He had no idea. As soon as I
heard them carrying the digging tools
I knew they were taking someone to kill him
It could be my turn next, and I could be that
person, not knowing that my time had come
They would tell most of the prisoners being taken
Your behavior is good, stay committed
to religion, try to join us, and so on
So that he wouldn’t think of escaping while being led to execution
Interviewer: Were there cameras
in the solitary cells and group cells?
Before my father and the others
escaped, there were only two cameras
One at the beginning of the corridor and one
at the end; those were the only visible ones
After my father escaped, they placed a
camera in every solitary cell and group cell
Interviewer: When they released you from prison
Did they release you from the same place,
or transfer you somewhere else first?
No, they released me from the same place while
I was blindfolded, after the sunset prayer
And I was out
I was released normally, from the same place I had entered
I left from the car garage, and
they threw me out in the market
One of them asked me, Do you know
where you were imprisoned? I said, No
But he knew that I knew where I had been held
For a reason of his own