We will enter the prison compound, and here, of course, is the vehicle entrance
Into the basement
And the first step
In the prison procedure
You go down, and the vehicles drive into
the basement. This area was the car garage
For the prisoners’ transport vehicles,
and for the guards’ and interrogators’ cars
This whole section, of course, was a parking area
Sometimes a person would be taken out
They would take him out of prison, and if his eyes were
not blindfolded, he would notice the prisoners’ vehicles
Someone might recognize them
And this is the door to the
investigation room and the group cells
And this is the main prison gate
We enter through here, and the first room is the
custody room, which was also the investigation room
We go to the right side, where the
solitary cells and group cells are located
And on the left side, there is a kitchen belonging to them
And there is a hidden group cell
And there is a regular group cell