When I first entered, they put me in the third solitary cell
I stayed there for two days, then they moved me to another
group cell for about a month, then back to this one
Here I lived the most tragic period of my imprisonment
Because on both sides of me there were women
We could hear the sounds of interrogation and torture
And worse than that, the ventilation opening of the cell
Overlooked the basement and the car garage
So when a prisoner was taken for execution
We knew he would be executed before he left
Because they carried digging tools, and we
heard them through the ventilation opening
They placed the prisoner opposite me in the corridor,
asked him some questions, then took him away
They disappeared for two hours or
more and returned without the prisoner
We used to communicate with each
other, as there was a bathroom at the back
We communicated with those to the
right and left. We could hear each other
After the women left, they brought one of my
relatives, Huthaifa al-Hajj Abd, who was later killed
And Faisal Saad Rajoub, a young man from Homs, who was also killed
We eventually gathered in one cell, the sixth solitary cell
It was the most dangerous solitary cell in
the prison, as few people ever came out of it