It was designated as a solitary cell without
a ventilation opening toward the garage
It was a small room where they
placed those sentenced to death
So they had no chance to escape
It was far from the investigation room–
We never knew who entered or left it
In the other solitary cells, we could feel
when prisoners were brought in or taken out
Here, we never knew what was happening outside
Witness: We could only communicate a little
Interviewer: How many days did you stay here?
I stayed here for 15 days
At first, they left me alone for about 10 days
Then they brought the young man, Faisal Saad Rajoub
We stayed five or six days together, and a little
further from our cell was another with two women
They brought in...
A well-known prisoner, so they changed everyone’s places
The young man and I
Were placed in the group cell, and
the women were moved to solitary cells
They took one woman, and the
other stayed two days before leaving
After several days, they brought
the male prisoner and placed him here
I communicated with him through
the bathroom; that’s how we talked
He told me his name was Ahmad al-Hassan al-Ibrahim
He was imprisoned for the second
time because of his brother Musleh
Who had been sentenced to
death and was in the first solitary cell
He was chained to prevent him from escaping