This was the group cell, which
was all divided but later dismantled
There was a ventilation opening here
Sometimes they would fire bullets
through the opening to break our spirits
Here, there used to be a door
There was a door here. Sometimes we
stood and saw a faint light in the corridor
Because in the end, we only ever saw the jailers
Everyone here wrote his memories
Then they repainted the prison
But later new prisoners came and wrote new memories again
Very few
Witness: At first, they gave a little... Interviewer:
Read us something that was written on the wall
For example, it says, Do not lose heart or
grieve, for you are superior if you are believers