This place was designated for suspension [shabeh]
From the solitary cells, we could see
who was suspended and recognize them
I was suspended here
For about 10 hours, more or less
I was suspended here, then they
brought a young man from Homs
He was kept hanging for three or four days
until he confessed to what they wanted
Faisal asked them, What do you want from him?
They told him
He had to confess that he was
going to Idlib to join the Free Army
He said, As you wish! Just to save himself
This solitary cell
When you first go to the investigation
room, the first group cell is right in front
They open the doors. My father
was imprisoned in the first group cell
So he could hear our voices as we were
tortured—me, my brothers, and my cousins
When the interrogator finished torturing us, he opened
my father’s window and said, How are you, are you fine?
Just to break him down