Here they are, and there are eight disciplinary cells
The door entrance was here, but they later reopened…
All the partitions together, as if it had now become a storage room
Each cell’s area was no more than half a meter
Sometimes a person had to sleep on one side
Meaning that a slightly overweight person couldn’t sleep on his back
Interviewer: Approximately how many solitary cells were there?
The regular solitary cells were six
As for the disciplinary ones, there were eight
Eight disciplinary cells on one side
and five on the other, so a total of 13
Interviewer: How long did you stay in the disciplinary cell?
I stayed in the disciplinary cell from one week
to 10 days, meaning my time there was intermittent
Interviewer: Tell us how you communicated
with each other in the disciplinary cells
When we were in the disciplinary cell, they would
let us go to the bathroom during prayer times
And the bathroom was on this side
We would communicate with the second group cell
The one next to us
Through the long ventilation opening. If you
called out through it, those beside you could hear
So we used to call each other from this side
Once, there was a young man
named Khaled al-Harbi, who was killed
He used to talk to me. My father and I were in the cell
when the jailer heard us and sent me back to solitary here
So through the ventilation openings we
used to communicate between solitary cells
But in a low voice because the
investigation room was very close to us