And here was the first group cell
This is the first group cell, where I was imprisoned twice
The first time I stayed for four days, not counting
this whole period of imprisonment I’m describing
Here were all the prisoners’ memories
I was imprisoned here with someone named Abdul Razzaq al-Barish
I was released, but he wasn’t. He and his brother Faisal were killed
We were imprisoned here together
And here my father and all my brothers were imprisoned
There was an electrical socket on this wall
We used it to communicate with group cell four,
whose door is far from here. We’ll see it shortly
We communicated from here, as there was a power
socket, and through it we could talk to each other
Just by hearing a knock on the
wall, we knew a prisoner wanted to talk
We would immediately come here and
speak to him, and the sound would be clear
Interviewer: What was the most
striking phrase you saw written here in the prison?
As I told you, there was a man named
Abu Madian, who influenced me the most
They erased all his writings in the other group cells
But here he had a small inscription
It was written here, though I don’t know if
it’s still visible. He wrote his son’s name
This is Madian
He used to write on the pillows and mattresses—wherever
you went, you’d find the names Madian and Abu Madian
His real name was Muhammad al-Hateel, known as Abu Madian
He had spent 110 days in prison
And he was killed
He was a calligrapher, may God have mercy on him
Interviewer: Who were the people with you in
the group cell, if you still remember them?
In this group cell, Hassan al-Ibrahim was imprisoned with me
Hassan Ibrahim al-Sheikh
Walid al-Hajji and Mutasim al-Hajji
And Muhammad Abdul Fattah al-Oweihi
And Ghanem al-Ibrahim. We were imprisoned together,
along with several others whose names I’ve forgotten
Witness: But I’ve forgotten their names. Interviewer:
Do you have any writing on the prison walls?
I didn’t write anything myself, but
there’s a note from my brother Ibrahim
We were imprisoned together for a while.
That’s his name here—Ibrahim al-Salama
He also has another name written here
And I didn’t write anything here
Most of my writings were in the solitary cells
because I spent most of my imprisonment there
They painted the walls so no one could recognize
What happened to the prisoners