Over there is group cell four, which is far from here
It’s a bit distant and separate from the
other detention areas and solitary cells
That’s where we were imprisoned in the beginning
So I tried to escape along with the others who were with me
ISIS used to take out one or two prisoners every four or five days
So we kept telling ourselves maybe we’d be next, maybe not
Then we were left alone
Here there was a large group cell, as they had removed the partitions
And this was the entrance door
The prison was entirely underground
And as we see, it had a ventilation opening about half a meter high
Here there is an old external staircase
to the basement, built since its founding
They sealed it off with blocks and cement in this way
We realized there was a staircase and a door here, but it was blocked
There was an iron rod that one of the former prisoners
is believed to have pulled from the ventilation window
He left it there
We saw the rod and started planning
to escape when the escape period began
They moved us to another group cell
That’s when I met my father in the first group cell
I told him that I and the guys with me were thinking of escaping
He asked me, How? Escape is impossible.
I said, Yes, there’s a staircase, an outer door,
and an iron rod placed in the ventilation window
There was a young man named Ahmad Sinu and
another named Hamad, and they were listening to us
Time passed, and they separated us, and my father stayed there
Interviewer: Weren’t you afraid that Ahmad
Sinu and the others might be informants?
No, because we had been together for a long time, and
Ahmad Sinu had escaped some time ago from Raqqa Prison
So we already knew him before entering prison
He managed to escape, but they caught him again
He was sentenced to one year in prison
on charges of smuggling a Yazidi woman out
When they first entered the group cell, they recognized
him because it was the largest one among all the cells
They found the staircase and saw the
iron rod still in place—no one had moved it
After some time, they began
The jailer ordered them to carry the winter bedding
Since summer had come, they
placed it on this side opposite the door
My father was an old man, unable to dig with them
So he stood by the door and kept watch
While they moved the bedding, they started
digging between the stones of the wall
Each day they dug a little, for a week
When they finally opened the wall,
they waited until the evening prayer began
Once the prayer started, they escaped from the prison
Interviewer: How many people escaped?
Those who escaped were my father and two young
men, one named Ahmad Sinu and the other Hamad
Interviewer: Can we see the openings
through which you used to communicate?
This is exactly the electricity opening
where there used to be a socket
We communicated with each other through it
We weren’t afraid of the jailers then because they
were far away, and we could sense when they approached
We could talk freely, but those on the other side couldn’t
Interviewer: Did you have a specific time for the jailers’
rounds, or did you have a clock inside the prison?
We would hear the call to prayer and the
iqama. During the prayer, they would pray
That’s when we took the chance to talk for five minutes or more
Until they finished, because the jailer
would then start his round of inspection
Interviewer: After your father and the
others escaped, you stayed in prison
Interviewer: Tell us about the changes
and movements that happened afterward
The next morning, the prison changed completely
ISIS became confused. We realized something
strange had happened that night
We knew that a prisoner had managed to escape
They gave us a standard uniform
and took away all our civilian clothes
They installed cameras in all group cells and solitary cells
They even put up a curtain behind the door
They hung it on their side, not ours
Outside the door, there was a curtain
from the top to the bottom of the door
So we couldn’t see, because they sensed what had happened
Interviewer: What about the jailers who were on duty?
Weren’t they punished or transferred to another prison or place?
No, I stayed for 15 days or more
I never noticed anything like that
Interviewer: Did their behavior toward you change?
Yes, their behavior changed. They
stopped treating prisoners with any respect
Before, we could ask them for small
things, and sometimes they would agree
But afterwards, they cut off all communication completely
They started checking the ventilation openings daily
Interviewer: Were you allowed to
go out for fresh air or to see sunlight?
No, that was completely forbidden. They
never even thought of allowing it
Sometimes we went out to clean the corridor
But only by order
You could say it was a punishment
Interviewer: Did they give you
ideological lessons in the prison?
Never, no religious or ideological lessons at all
Sometimes we asked for books;
they might bring them or not
Interviewer: You mentioned earlier that when you
prayed or recited the Quran aloud, they forbade you
What was the reason?
Because we all knew each other here
Sometimes they told us someone had
confessed to something and had been released
Then we’d hear him reciting the Quran aloud
They realized it, and eventually they banned
reciting the Quran aloud, and even banned prayer
Interviewer: When they took people
for executions and you heard the sounds
Tell us how the process went,
and what you felt at that moment
It was psychological destruction. What hurt
me most was for the one being taken to die
He had no idea. As soon as I
heard them carrying the digging tools
I knew they were taking someone to kill him
It could be my turn next, and I could be that
person, not knowing that my time had come
They would tell most of the prisoners being taken
Your behavior is good, stay committed
to religion, try to join us, and so on
So that he wouldn’t think of escaping while being led to execution
Interviewer: Were there cameras
in the solitary cells and group cells?
Before my father and the others
escaped, there were only two cameras
One at the beginning of the corridor and one
at the end; those were the only visible ones
After my father escaped, they placed a
camera in every solitary cell and group cell
Interviewer: When they released you from prison
Did they release you from the same place,
or transfer you somewhere else first?
No, they released me from the same place while
I was blindfolded, after the sunset prayer
And I was out
I was released normally, from the same place I had entered
I left from the car garage, and
they threw me out in the market
One of them asked me, Do you know
where you were imprisoned? I said, No
But he knew that I knew where I had been held
For a reason of his own