This door was for suspension [shabeh], and
their method of suspension had different types
There was this one for the balingo [hoist], which
was located here, and another for light suspension
They cuffed the hands behind the back with shackles
They tied you up this way, and after a
while, they came back and lifted your hands
Step by step, that’s how it went. He started at
first, and every so often, he lifted them higher
Every hour or two, he came and lifted you a bit, to tighten it on you
So your muscles would relax, then he
raised your hands as high as he could
You stayed like that for two, three, or four hours, sometimes even 10 hours
Some prisoners stayed like that for days, and only
during prayer time would he release them to pray
He let them go to the toilet, drink some water, then brought
them back. Of course, he left them thirsty for a while
A man might remain hanging for two or three
days until he confessed to what they wanted
You’d hear him saying, Write whatever you want
in the report, I’ll say exactly what you tell me
He was even ready to record a video confession about it
Just to save himself from that torment
Here, of course, there was more than one door
And this was the door where I was most often
suspended, because they used to hang me on it
And directly behind it was the group cell where my father was
So he could hear my voice and the groans of
torture. They placed us this way on purpose
And on the opposite side, they put
my brother in a nearby solitary cell
So he would also hear the same sounds
In that situation, I would often suppress
The sounds of torture and my groaning, I held them in
To spare my father’s feelings, so he wouldn’t hear that
Because at the same time, he was making duaa
[supplication], silently, without letting out any sound
He was crying, and I didn’t want to hear his voice either
Because hearing his voice would make me break down even more
The psychological torture was worse than the
physical one, especially for the prisoners
I used to envy the prisoner who didn’t have a father
or brother detained with him in the same prison
When you’re imprisoned alone, you
carry your sorrow and pain by yourself
But in this case, we all carried each other’s grief
Your worries, your father’s worries, and your
brother’s worries—all the same, all shared
And also the worries of my brothers
outside. I had younger brothers
Was my father grieving for us, or
for himself, or for his children outside?
That was what affected me and my father most deeply
That they tortured me right in this area
Or in the investigation room. They
opened the door, it was right nearby
They opened the investigation room door
and this door, so the sound would carry
The sound of torture reached the prisoners
more clearly, for psychological effect
And there were many doors. Sometimes
there were more than two or three
Or even four people suspended at the same time
Sometimes I was suspended here, and this door opened and closed
Sometimes they hung people from it for two or three hours
You’d see people go numb—you could only hear faint groaning
Once, I was suspended beside
another man, hung right next to him
He had been hanging for a day or two
Two hours passed, maybe more, before I even
realized someone was suspended beside me
The interrogator came and spoke to
him, and I started answering instead
He said to me, I’m not talking to you, and then I
heard the voice of the prisoner hanging next to me
I hadn’t even realized he was there, because
he had been tortured so much that he couldn’t speak