This tunnel, of course, they recognized each other
Ahmad al-Hassan al-Ibrahim
and Abdullah al-Hassan al-Salama
Ahmad al-Hassan knew that Abdullah
was imprisoned, but Abdullah did not know
They saw each other in the prison and checked on each other
Because they were Muslims, according to ISIS’s standards
They were taken down into the
basement, and that made them feel relieved
They felt they would not be killed, God
willing, but were sad for those they left behind
They were considered part of the disbelievers’ section,
among them was a young man named Alaa from rural Aleppo
Of course, this basement, we knew there was
something abnormal happening in the prison
But we did not know what it was until the prisoners came out
Those who had entered that basement told us its story
And this tunnel, of course, extended to the third neighborhood
They had built it for escaping in case fighting broke out
So they could go in and out freely, but they rarely used it
They would open the door only occasionally
But we did not know what was inside
Even if there were prisoners inside, we did not know them
We did not know about this matter,
because every day or every two days or more
The door would open and close, but we never knew what was behind it
Interviewer: From what you said, how did you know the door was opened?
This door, of course, had some modifications and wall divisions made
Some walls were removed and others built during the last period
But when the door opened, we could see it through the window
We knew there was a door opposite
the entrance door and the garage door
There was a door that, when opened, we could hear its sound clearly
And right afterward, the humidity would rise
And in summer, the air became unusually cold
We knew something was there, but we did not know what it was