Of course, I remember the prison days,
and I remember the people I lived with
It was one of the worst periods of my life that I lived here, with them
It was... I don’t even know how to describe it to you
I was released before them, and I wished they
had been released after me, but they weren’t
Interviewer: You mentioned people who were executed.
What were their names, and who were they to you?
They were death’s companions, and we were all destined for death
One of them was Harith al-Hajj Abd, one of my relatives
And Faisal Saad Rajoub, a young man from Homs, from Bab al-Sebaa
And Khaled al-Alou, a young man from the city of Tabqa
And Alaa, a young man from southern Rural Aleppo who
came here for a visit, and after a week he was detained
And there were young men whose voices I used to hear from the
al-Boukhamees clan, from Mansoura, from the al-Hateel family
I read their writings and loved them for the sake
of God in prison without ever seeing them
I used to communicate with them, and I
wished I could see them outside, not here
We all had hope of getting out,
but Alaa felt he would never leave
He was afraid of that, even though we kept
reassuring him that he would be released from here
And Faisal Saad Rajoub asked me to deliver a message to his mother
That he had tried as much as he could,
even to the point of death, just to see her
Because he hadn’t seen his mother for more than five years
And all that was to reach her, but he never did
Interviewer: Where was Faisal that he couldn’t reach her?
Faisal was trapped in Homs, and his family had left the city
He stayed there under siege for two or three years
Then he left, but he was imprisoned by the Assad regime for a year
After that, he returned here, and he intended to go to Jordan
He stayed in Daraa for some time, but couldn’t leave
His family contacted him and told him,
We’re going to Turkey, you must come
So he could go to Turkey to meet them,
since he hadn’t seen them for five years
When he entered ISIS-controlled areas, someone
recognized him—a man who had been with the Free Army
That man caught him and said that the
battalion he belonged to was now in Idlib
He said he was going to rejoin it, and
that’s when they accused him of that charge