I am Ahmad from the
town of Tabqa, 25 years old
I was imprisoned by ISIS in
2016, during Ramadan, for 33 days
They put me in their prison for 33 days, during which I
was tortured unjustly. I had not committed any offense
Because of one of my friends who had committed
some wrongdoings, I used to hang out at his place
I left his house and he told me he had something entrusted to
him and asked me to bring it on my way from the town of Mansoura
I went and they caught me there. I was standing in
front of a shop when a car came and masked men got out
Only their eyes were visible and they wore
black. They arrested me immediately by name
They put me in the trunk of the car, locked it, and asked me,
where is Abdul Latif? Of course with beating and humiliation
Punches to my stomach and back. They locked the trunk
on me and went looking for my friend Abdul Latif
Neither of us knew what the issue was. They took us
and put us in the Finance building in the town of Tabqa
In a basement, in a solitary cell,
and of course they separated us
They also brought in someone else we had been
with the night before, named Nasser al-Ammar
They took us and searched for him for an hour and a half to
two hours. He had fled because he knew he had done something
They brought him and put him with us on the balingo [hoist
for suspension] and kept us in prison for three days
Then they brought us to Bourj [Tower] Prison, to the basement. Of
course we were blindfolded and did not know where we were going
But since we were from the area, we knew where they
were taking us. We felt we were in Bourj Prison
We went down and they put us in a dark place. The lights
stayed on around the clock. We could not tell night from day