This is the entrance they
brought us through, by bus
They brought us down one by
one toward that door and we walked
They lined us up, and our eyes were covered. In the bus
too we were blindfolded, we could not see anything at all
At this door, this entrance
here, we will show it to you
They brought us in through this door one
by one, pressed against the wall like this
They did not bring us in directly,
rather we walked along the wall like this
Along this side we walked one by one next to the wall.
They brought us in through that door, I will show it to you
They brought us in through this door. Of course we
could see people here in shabeh [suspension] and these
Are the devices they used to suspend
people, located in that area like this
Of course we walked through this
corridor, also in a line along the wall
They lined us up. Here there were group cells, and here
there was also a small group cell and a solitary cell
The solitary cells are here, in this area.
The solitary cells I was in are in this spot
This solitary cell, this is where it was. Of course they have now
removed the cinder blocks and taken them apart. Here is a vent
Of course the lights here in this place were on
day and night. We could not tell night from day
Here there is a door. In this place
we could hear them calling the prayer
When they brought food they did not open the door. There is a small
hatch through which they gave us food and then closed it on us