These are the suspension
spots, right here
And this is the interrogation
room, the interrogation room is here
And here the balingo [hoist for suspension]
is in the ceiling, hanging from the ceiling
And here there is a table with
batteries and an electrical panel
Of course electric shock. They connect the electricity
to the handcuffs and shock you during interrogation
The interrogators present numbered two or three. Of course
we could hear what seemed like recording inside the room
They have cameras here, placed in the room, and
they even placed cameras in the solitary cells
Interviewer: What are the names
of the torture methods they used?
For example, the hose they call
Lakhdar Brahimi. They use it for flogging
Electric shock, and the common one is suspension,
and beating with a whip while you are suspended
Interviewer: Is there anything
left on your body from the torture?
Of course, here where the handcuffs
were, their marks are still on my hands
The clasp went into my hand
because of how tightly they pressed it
Of course this skin was protruding outward like
this. I spent three months with my hands trembling
Interviewer: How long did
the interrogation sessions last?
One or two hours, and sometimes the
interrogation lasted four hours with beating
Suspension was sometimes three hours, sometimes two
hours, sometimes you stayed suspended for half an hour
As for the beating, sometimes they
beat you for an hour along with suspension
Interviewer: Did they
insult you or curse at you?
Cursing or insulting, no. They
never cursed during interrogation
They would say things like, you will
be executed. That was routine for them
Your execution is tomorrow or in a week. Get ready.
You will not leave here except for execution, and so on
Interviewer: What scared you most
when you were taken to interrogation?
I feared execution. I feared they
would say, you will be executed
Every time they took us to interrogation we wondered, they
told us last time we would be executed, they will behead you
So every time they took you to interrogation you felt like you were
being taken to your execution. They made you live with that feeling
Interviewer: Did they take anyone
else with you for interrogation?
No, we only heard their voices. They did not take two or
three at once, only one person at a time for interrogation
Interviewer: Do you know the names
or noms de guerre of the interrogators?
Their noms de guerre, for example, they called the
interrogator Abu Usama. When we called him Abu Usama
He would say, I am not Abu Usama. Who told
you I am Abu Usama? They concealed their names
The guard they called Abu
Safwan, from the Arabian Peninsula
I asked him, are you Saudi? He scolded me and said,
I am not Saudi, I am from the Arabian Peninsula
Interviewer: How did
the guards treat you?
As guards, their treatment was decent and they did
not bother us. If you asked for food they brought it
You call him, if you need medicine they bring it. That is it,
he has nothing to do with anything else and does not talk to us
Unless you need something. You knock on the door and he
opens the small hatch. He is masked and wears all black
You tell him what you want
and he gives it to you, he brings it
Interviewer: Did any prisoner
get sick from the torture?
Did they take any prisoner to a doctor? Or
did you ask for medicine and they brought it?
As for medicine, we asked and they brought it. But
I never saw a sick prisoner taken out for treatment
Since you are with them here, if
you need medicine they bring it
Cough syrup for example, or
anti-inflammatory pills, that is it
If you had a heart condition or something similar, they brought your
medication, and whenever the prescription ran out they renewed it
Interviewer: What did
this place smell like?
The smell of dampness of course. This place has a
strange smell. The ceiling has a damp smell, that is all
And coughing was always widespread.
There were people coughing constantly
That is it. It was summer
and the smell was damp
Interviewer: After they tortured you, how
did they bring you back to the solitary cell?
Interviewer: Describe
your condition for us
After the interrogator finishes with
you, you are blindfolded and handcuffed
He leads you while you are handcuffed
along the wall, slowly, the guard walks you
He takes you out walking along
the wall and leads you toward
The solitary cell you were in, toward this door.
He returns you along the wall and tells you quietly
At this point you are exhausted from the
interrogation and from the hoist, and he takes you
Toward the solitary cell you were in,
returns you to it, and brings someone else
He takes another person in
your place, toward the spot
Toward the solitary cell, he
returns me to the solitary cell here
Toward the solitary cell, he returns you to your
place, and you hear that he has taken someone else
He takes someone else and interrogates them.
You hear only the screaming and beating