I got to know someone I spoke with through the wall. The
wall has small holes, I could see his face through them
I asked him his name. He said, Ali al-Wudaihi.
They beat him severely and humiliated him
Two of them would carry him and slam him against the wall. I could
hear the sound of him being beaten, until his bones shattered
He was next to me for four days, but I no longer heard his
voice. He was in the room but there was no sound from him
After that I could not reach him. I called out, Ali,
Ali, but he could not hear me and did not respond
Did they transfer him or did he die? I believe he died, because when
I got out and asked about him, they told me they tortured him to death
Interviewer: Were there sukhra [forced labor]
punishments such as cleaning and other tasks?
We were in solitary cells, they never took us out for forced labor at all. We never
went out even a single meter except for interrogation, inside the solitary cell
Interviewer: Did they
insult you during the torture?
I did not hear insults, just beating
and humiliation. No, no one cursed
The ones they tortured the most were those they
accused of being affiliated with the Free Syrian Army
Those had a special status. They
were tortured heavily. Some people died
And suspension on the walls, and harsh
methods. The suspension was here on the walls
The worst torture methods here were for people who had been
with the Free Syrian Army and those involved in smuggling people
Like Hayel al-Ghadban, this
person was tortured severely
They told him, you were a sniper during the Free
Syrian Army, and you fought against ISIS. As an example
Those were the sounds I would hear, and his screaming, I
did not do anything, while he was suspended on the wall
Like Abdullah al-Naji from Jarniya. They arrested him
and told him, you have 13 rifles and you must bring them
He said, I do not have any. He was severely tortured.
They did not let him off easily, they tortured him heavily
Also, four young men who had found
cameras and ammunition in a room
They wanted to sell them, and
it seems someone reported them
That there was ammunition and informed on them. They found them by
chance, arrested them, and humiliated them severely for a long time
Interviewer: What was the dominant sound
in this place that you heard the most?
The sound of torture. Every
day they took two or three in order
These would have a torture session. They would not leave
them until after torture on the hoist, flogging, and beating
And humiliation and heavy electric
shock. Those were the sounds in this place