They tortured us with psychological warfare by saying, tomorrow you will
be executed, in a week you will be executed, you will not leave here
They wanted you to live in an
atmosphere as close to death as possible
The guard opens the small hatch on you and says, get ready, pray,
and make your supplications, you will be executed in two days
You wait for those two days to
pass, wishing they would never end
Because after that you will die,
and you have believed every word
Interviewer: Did they show
you their propaganda videos?
They did not show anything, no videos or anything else.
We were in solitary cells, we could not see anything
Interviewer: They had a newspaper called
al-Naba. Did they distribute it to you in prison?
As for things they brought us, they only brought food.
They never distributed a newspaper or showed a video at all
Interviewer: How do you feel
standing in this place now?
My feelings are very difficult. Standing
in this place where I was imprisoned
Is harder than the mind can imagine. I saw
things I will never forget as long as I live