The solitary cell is a meter and a half
wide and about two and a half meters long
It has a toilet and two mattresses.
Sometimes they put two or three people in it
They keep them in it for two
or three days then move them
After that they take them away from me, and I would have gotten to know
them. Among them, as I told you, was Hajj Walid from the village of Hamam
And among them was Abu Yousuf, a
vegetable seller in the first neighborhood
And Ali al-Wudaihi, I spoke
with him through the wall
And there was Ammar from
Mansoura, his name was Ammar al-Raji
And there was Hammadi al-Aziz from
Musheirfa, and Fattouh was with him
And another young man whose name I
forgot, because it has been a long time
These are the people I knew. Also
Hayel al-Ghadban was with me there
I do not know, and they do not
tell you why they put you in solitary
You cannot say a single word. They put you
here and that is it, you must stay silent
Of course they put cameras here, in
every solitary cell they put a camera
The barrier between the area where you sit and the
toilet is a sheet, a cloth cover used as a divider
Of course there are no nails in the wall, just
two mattresses, two pillows, and two blankets
The weather was very hot. There is a vent, and something strange
happened inside the prison. I heard about it from the commotion
Someone escaped from inside the prison, even
though it seemed impossible for anyone to escape
After that they brought welders. We could hear
the sound of welding and they started welding
He escaped from the group cells. He prepared a
spot and escaped from it, and managed to get away
As for the solitary cells, there is nothing in them
but this window, and it is reinforced with iron
They welded iron bars onto it. It is impossible to think
about getting out. There is absolutely no way to escape
I spent my time in the solitary cell sitting,
and when it was time for prayer I prayed
We spent most of the time eating. The food was mostly canned
goods like mortadella and other things. We opened the cans and ate
And whoever was imprisoned with me, I listened to his story. He
told me what happened to him, and each person had a different story
We kept each other company, because the
situation was boring and prison was hard
You live in fear and try to distract yourself
because you believe you will be executed tomorrow
There is no hope of getting out. If you entered
this place it seemed impossible to leave
Of course during that time, a masked
person would come and mock us
He would point his pistol at us and say, I will kill you, or tomorrow you will be executed,
or tomorrow morning they will take you to the roundabout for execution, to intimidate us
And during that period we believed everything we heard.
We did not expect that what they said could be a lie
Or that it would not happen to us. But every person was
exposed to anything, based on the torture I saw and heard about
Interviewer: What did you do inside
the cell, any games or anything?
We could not do anything. There were very fine pebbles we picked
from the wall. I tried with some of them but they refused to play
It became routine for us. We will die?
No problem, we are already like the dead
Interviewer: Tell us about the
game you used to play, what was it?
A game where we moved a stone like this, to
entertain ourselves. It was not really a game
The point was to kill
time, to make it pass faster
From here we could hear the call to prayer. They had someone
with a beautiful voice when he called the prayer, we heard him
We knew it was afternoon or midday prayer, but we could
not see daylight. We wished we could see the light
When they took us out of the prison and on the road
removed the blindfold from our eyes, I felt dizzy
My friend and I had not seen the sun for 33
days. We had no idea what was happening
Interviewer: Tell us about
the meals, what were they like?
As for meals, one time
someone brought me a rice dish
Stuffed eggplant with rice. He gave me three pieces,
knowing that I was known among them for loving food
Since we were smokers and there were no
cigarettes, our appetite for food increased a lot
They brought me canned meat,
cheese cubes, bread, jam, and halva
Boiled potatoes, tomatoes,
and cucumbers, things like that
Cooking and hot meals were only
for the group cells, from what I heard
Tea in a plastic cup, poured for me when I asked. Sometimes
I asked and they gave it, and sometimes they did not
Sometimes he would call me
and say, take this, drink your tea
The group cells were different. Tea and food whenever we wanted.
In the solitary cell I only had whatever food they gave me
Interviewer: Was food served on a
regular schedule, breakfast, lunch, dinner?
The food was organized. And for the sick,
they brought medicine and gave it to them
For example, you tell them you have a throat infection and need
anti-inflammatory pills. They give you the medicine, they bring it
Nail clippers, if I asked he gave them
to me. He stood there watching me
When I finished trimming, he took the
clippers back and left, closing the door
Of course there is a small hatch in the
door, a black door with a small opening
I knock on the door, he opens
the hatch and asks what I want
But if he wants to take you to interrogation, he opens the hatch and
tells you, get ready, come out and put the blindfold on your eyes
Or he makes you face the wall, puts the
blindfold on you himself, and takes you out
Interviewer: How many people were with you?
And what were the charges brought against them?
The charges were varied. Each
person had a different charge
One person was charged with being Free Syrian Army, another
charged with communicating with the popular committees, and another
Was charged with taking money to smuggle people.
People had different charges, each person had a story
Most of the older people they brought
in were between 50 and 55 years old
Of course all of their charges were related
to dealing with the popular committees
Or they had relatives in the popular committees and were
arrested on charges that their relative was in contact with them
Interviewer: Did they prevent
you from talking inside the cell?
Yes, they prevented you. You are not
allowed to talk, unless you needed something
They prevented us from talking a lot. If you talked
too much you would be tortured and humiliated
They take you out for interrogation,
for example, and torture you on the hoist
Just the mention of the hoist and you go silent
automatically. There is no reason to talk
Interviewer: How many
ISIS members did you see?
During interrogation I saw four people: the
guard, the interrogator, and two others with him
These two assisted in the torture.
Other than that we did not see anyone
Interviewer: What
were their names?
They did not have names, just noms de guerre like
Abu so-and-so. Each person had a nom de guerre
Like Abu Islam. Of course he was the
guard. And with him was a Saudi person
I said to him, you are Saudi. He scolded me
and said, I am from the Arabian Peninsula
They called him Abu Safwan and he
was Saudi. The interrogator was Abu Usama
We would call him Abu Usama. He would say, I am not Abu Usama,
and did not give us a name. That is all that happened with me
Interviewer: How did
they take you for torture?
The method was blindfolding, and
handcuffing with metal handcuffs
They turn your back toward
the wall, toward the toilet
He enters and puts a black cover
over your eyes. You cannot see anything
He grabs you by the handcuffs behind your back, leads you,
and tells you if there is something in front to lift your foot
Until he gets you inside, to
them, in the interrogation room
And he goes and waits outside until you
finish interrogation, then brings you back
Of course you walk there on your
feet, but you come back crawling
Interviewer: Was the toilet
or bathroom inside the room?
There was nothing called a bathroom, just a
toilet. You relieve yourself there and bathe there
It is about half a meter, very small, with a cloth
curtain. You bathe and relieve yourself inside the toilet
There is no such thing as a bathroom. You go out
at prayer time and pray in the same solitary cell
On the mattress. You
cannot move right or left
Sometimes in this solitary cell, which is two
and a half meters, they put three or four people
Interviewer: Was ludaelin [dish
soap] or regular soap available?
In the solitary cell, every
Thursday they made us clean it
Of course they gave us cleaning supplies, then we took our
things out, he took them from us and locked the door on us
We cleaned until it dried and then they gave us our
things back while we were inside. We never left it at all
Interviewer: Did the toilet ever
get clogged while you were there?
No, we never had a clogged toilet or any malfunction. Just
a water faucet and a floor drain for the toilet, that is all
Interviewer: Did
you have hot water?
There was no hot water, only cold water. We never
saw hot water at all, just cold water from the faucet