I was sitting and the guard opened the door
on me. No, I think it was the interrogator
He told me, tomorrow you will go out for execution.
I said, there is no power but God's, of course
In the morning, or at around midnight,
they took me and flogged me 40 lashes
He told me, this is called taazir [discretionary punishment], you
must be flogged. My eyes were covered and I endured the flogging
On my back with a whip, and
I returned to the solitary cell
They put me in the solitary cell, and the next
morning around 10 o'clock they took me out
And brought me back at 11. A guard came and
told me, come, you and your friend Abdul Latif
They took us out blindfolded, assuming
we were going to execution. We were silent
We reached the market in Tabqa
and he said, remove the blindfolds
We removed the blindfolds. He said, get out and I do
not want to hear a sound. We got out and went home
Abdul Latif and I, when we
opened our eyes, felt dizzy
He dropped us off and left. Because of the
fear we lived in, we could not even look back
Interviewer: From what you saw, who was the
Emir? Who had the authority in this place?
The Emir present was never seen by us. We only saw the guard and the
interrogator, nothing else. We heard, the Emir has come, the Emir has left
About five days
before I was released
An older masked man came. My eyes
were blindfolded and he spoke to me
He scolded us and said, join
up, be with ISIS, it is better for you
And words like that, advising us. It was like advice, but
he punched me in the stomach and put me back in the room
And closed the door on me. Four days
after that, it was time for our release
Interviewer: What was his
name or nom de guerre?
I only heard of two older men.
People inside said, this is Abu Luqman
Known by the nom de
guerre Emir Abu Luqman