As for the guards, they
wore black and had masks on
With an inscription that read, there
is no god but God. He opens the door
He talks to us. The clothing was black,
nothing but black. I only saw black clothing
That is it. This is the
clothing the guards wore
Interviewer: Was there special
clothing for the prisoners?
No, clothing was given to some
people but not others. I did not see them
But it is said that some prisoners were given orange
clothing, while the rest stayed in their own clothes
Of course I was wearing my regular clothes,
but from the sweating my shirt tore
I was wearing a shirt and it was summer
and people were fasting for Ramadan
Interviewer: Since that period was
during Ramadan, how was their treatment?
During the day no one spoke to you.
Interrogation started at midnight, after 11 or 12
They took people out for interrogation in order. Every
day three or four during Ramadan, three or four at most
Interviewer: Did they bring you a suhoor
[pre-dawn Ramadan meal] and what was it?
They brought the pre-dawn meal.
The guard brought it from the daytime
Jam, cheese cubes,
mortadella, tomatoes, bread
It was kept with you
inside the solitary cell
Interviewer: Did you write any of
your memories while in the solitary cell?
Yes, I wrote my memories in this
place. Here is where the toilet was
And here was a wall, and here was the
toilet wall. Of course my pillow was here
There was nothing in the room to write with except a stone we
used to carve into the wall. Of course the wall has been removed
The spot where I carved is no longer
there because the wall has been removed
We carved memories into it with a smooth stone.
We carved the wall to keep ourselves occupied
Interviewer: When they took you for
interrogation, how many people came to get you?
One person. The guard would come
and tell me, turn your face to the wall
Then he would put the blindfold on me and handcuff me, then
take me from the solitary cell to the interrogation room
Interviewer: How many people
conducted the interrogation?
My eyes were blindfolded,
but based on the interrogation
There were two or
three people, two or three
Interviewer: Was the interrogation
being recorded on video?
Yes, they did record the interrogation. I did
not see it, but I felt they were recording
They were recording me on video of course. It seems there were
people watching elsewhere what was happening during interrogation
But my eyes were blindfolded during
interrogation. I could not see anything
Interviewer: What were the
charges brought against you?
The charges against me were many, including taking money to
get prisoners out. Of course I never joined any faction at all
I was hanging out at a friend's place. It seems my friend had problems
with them, and I was taken to prison without any fault of my own
Interviewer: Did your friend get
out or was he still imprisoned?
My friend stayed in prison for three months, and it turned
out he was working with them, and I had no knowledge of that
He died while working with them. After that I
cut my ties with him and had no more contact
Interviewer: What were the
torture methods they used?
What I saw and heard about: suspension on the hoist, and
handcuffing hands behind the back with metal handcuffs
They hang the hoist and lift you up,
then someone jumps and grabs your feet
To increase the weight on you while you are
hanging above the ground, and beating with a whip
And suspension on the wall for three to five
hours, hanging on a piece of iron fixed to the wall
They hang you on it and lift you off the ground,
and your weight falls mostly on your hands