My name is Ali Zaki Suleiman al-Omari
My education ended at primary school
I’m married and I have children
I’m 48 years old
I work as a carpenter in decoration and design
I was detained three times
I was detained because of cigarettes
And because of prayer, and because of the izar [long pants]
Interviewer: In what year and month were you detained in this prison?
And what was the charge that was brought against you?
The first time was in 2015
I was detained because of cigarettes
When they started banning them gradually, then banned them completely
They caught me smoking a cigarette, so they detained me
I stayed six days because of cigarettes
They caught me again
That was the second time, because of the izar of my pants
They whipped me and imprisoned me for four days
The third time was for one day because of prayer
He told me in the street, Go into the mosque. I said, I’ll go in
But I didn’t, I turned from the other side, and he caught me
They imprisoned me for just one day
Interviewer: Do you remember the details of your arrival at this place?
Yes, the first time this was their base
When they caught me the first time this was their base
Meaning the interrogation was inside
They took me out of the car and brought me here on foot
When we entered there was a reception desk where they wrote your name
And the room inside was for interrogation
When you go in, you see it there
It was for interrogation
When interrogation ended, they took you to prison
The prison wasn’t in the same place, it was behind, over there
Now it’s destroyed
It used to be a church too
In prison you were blindfolded
They blindfolded you when they whipped you for example
Or during interrogation, so you wouldn’t know who it was
Interviewer: Did they beat you while bringing you here?
No, they didn’t beat anyone outside
But when you arrive in the prison, they beat you
Interviewer: Did you know about this prison before you came here?
No, I didn’t know. We only knew it was a Hisba base
But we didn’t know what was inside
Interviewer: What did you feel when you arrived at this place?
I don’t know what to tell you. It was a feeling of fear
Fear would be in your heart
Because you don’t know if you’ll get out or not
You don’t know if they’ll beat you or kill you, you don’t know
When you go in, you don’t know what your fate is
Do you understand what I mean, you don’t know what your fate is