They were three when we arrived
They tie your hands like this with a plastic strip
And one of them holds you from here
And drags you behind him
When we came, we entered from here
When we arrived, one of them was sitting in this room
It was for reception, he only records your name
He records your full name and your date of birth
And they take you inside to a room for interrogation
And the interrogation starts inside
Honestly, when you enter here
When you see their looks, you lower your eyes out of fear
Because of fear, you can’t look at them
And this was real
We really feared them
There were many of them, spread out here, not just one or two
They were present in large numbers
Every moment one comes in, five go out, four enter, and so on
But from fear, you can’t look at them
And you can’t talk to them
When they question you inside during interrogation
You answer with just one word
If you answer with more than one word
He silences you, and God alone knows what
he’ll do to you, they don’t accept that
And out of fear, you answer him while trembling