What I know is this was only an information office
And that was the interrogation room
As for the other rooms, I don’t know what’s inside
We don’t know what’s inside them, we only know ISIS were here
But we don’t know what these rooms are
Interviewer: When you entered this place
Did you see ISIS members you knew?
Or did you see people brought here to be imprisoned
Who were your friends or people you knew?
Yes there were, but we didn’t know the ISIS members
The ones who were here, the ones standing here
And the one sitting here, the one inside
They were ISIS we didn’t know
But the prisoners they brought in, we knew of course
Because they were all from the area
You’d see someone they’d brought from the market
Another of your neighbors, another from a bit further away they also brought
They imprisoned them with you
Some of my friends were imprisoned with me, and my neighbors too
But we didn’t know the ISIS members
We didn’t know any of them
Interviewer: How were the sounds and the atmosphere?
What were they talking about and in what language?
Did they shout for example?
Did they play their jihadi chants?
For me, when I came here for interrogation
Only their voices could be heard
But in the prison hall in the other building
Which was in the church behind us, their prison
You could hear voices there
You’d hear the sound of torture here, and there someone being whipped
And over there someone being interrogated and beaten
But we didn’t know who they were
For me, when I was imprisoned in this place
And now I look at it again
Honestly I can’t believe this
Because the person imprisoned here doesn’t know if he will leave or not