When they brought me in from outside, there were three people
And from here to inside, one person escorted me
One of them escorted me from there to here
And the ones who brought me here were three people
They took me to the door, left me, and left
We entered and sat inside
The interrogation room was here
This is the interrogation room
There was a table at the front of the room and one person sitting
And there were a number of people sitting here, and others standing
Waiting to be punished
Or to be interrogated for something they had done
When I came, I was standing here next to the door
Later he asked me, What’s your charge
The one outside told him they brought me in on the charge of smoking
He brought me inside and told me, Sit down
And he started interrogating me
He started interrogating me about why I smoke
And why I don’t pray
Why did you stay here, and why didn’t you leave
Why were you in the areas of the apostates
That’s how their interrogation was
I told him I had been a smoker for a long time
I had been smoking for a long time, I couldn’t stop suddenly
He asked me, Can’t you quit, and I answered, I can’t
So he told them to take me to prison and whip me ten lashes
They took me, whipped me ten lashes, and put me in prison
The prison was on the other side
The one who interrogated me was one person
And in this room there was only one person
They had a walkie-talkie to communicate with each other
When he needed something, he called them and they came immediately
If he needed something, he called them directly
But in the interrogation there was one person, and he spoke Arabic
I don’t know if he was from Mosul, or an Arab, or from somewhere else
Or Kurdish, I don’t know exactly
I don’t know where he was from, honestly
Because the long beard doesn’t let you tell a man’s age from his face
And on the other hand, when he interrogates you, he sends you off right away
It doesn’t take long, and he doesn’t let you talk or explain too much
If you talk too much, he whips you more
Interviewer: How many times were you interrogated?
I was interrogated three times
The first time here, the second time somewhere else
And the third time they interrogated me in the street and put me in prison
Interviewer: When you arrived the first time
And the second time, was it in the same room?
No, here only once, the second time was in a house
A family lives in it now
Now we can’t go to that house so I can explain to you, because a family lives there
The second time was in the house, they were settled there
And it was turned into an interrogation place
Here was the first time, there was the second time
And the third time, without interrogation, straight to prison
When we entered, my eyes were open
When he asked what charge they’d brought me for
And they told him smoking, he said to me, Sit down
There were chairs we sat on
And there were people being interrogated
And there were people filing complaints
I don’t know who they were
When they left, he started interrogating me
And when he finished interrogating me, they took me to prison
The interrogation didn’t take long
Interviewer: Was the interrogation recorded, or was someone filming you?
Or was your trial recorded with a camera or an audio recorder?
Honestly no, I didn’t notice
We didn’t notice that
As for recording, no one was recording
They just talk to you, that’s all
Interviewer: Were you threatened by the interrogator?
Did he threaten you with beating, whipping, or execution?
Or did he threaten you with long prison terms during interrogation?
Yes, of course, he didn’t threaten me
But he ordered me to be whipped during the interrogation
And he told me if I kept smoking and was caught
They’d whip me more
More additional lashes
If now it was 20 lashes
Next time it’d be 40 lashes
That’s how he threatened with whipping
Interviewer: Were you threatened with harm to a family member if you repeated it?
No, they didn’t do that, the threat was only against me
They only threatened me with whipping or killing
But they didn’t threaten my family
Interviewer: Did the interrogation involve any physical or psychological torture?
Witness: You mean how, by beating?
Interviewer: I mean did someone come and beat you?
Or grab you strongly for example?
I mean, what kind of torture was it?
Torture by beating, or psychological torture?
Do you mean in the interrogation?
Interviewer: Yes
The first time was a normal interrogation
But when he took me to prison
There was also interrogation there
There was a judge upstairs in the prison
On the second floor, and also on the ground floor
There were interrogators they called judges, who worked for them
The fear there was worse than here
When they interrogated us there,
our eyes were blindfolded, not like here