He takes you through this path
He grabs you at this place
Then he takes you out through that door
He brings you into the prison upstairs
Their prison was there, not here
Interviewer: When you came up from here, how many ISIS members were with you?
From here, one person took me
He alone held my hand and led me from here to the other side
Then to the other door and from there to the prison
Interviewer: Do you remember if you saw anything
in front of you when you came up here now?
When I came up, I also saw people
Other people besides me being brought inside
They had brought civilians too, for reasons I didn’t know
We were walking on our way
Because when he took me out, he didn’t blindfold me the first time
He took me straight there
After he brought me into the prison
When he takes you out for interrogation
He blindfolds you and whips you
Interviewer: Can you continue to tell us how the ISIS member took you to prison?
When we went out the door, he held me here
Here he was holding me with his hand and I was walking behind him
Until we reached the door
One part of the door was open, not both sides
Only one part of this door was open
Both sides were not open
When we went out, the prison was behind us
Now it is destroyed, they blew it up
Interviewer: Describe to me how you felt when they sentenced you
It was six days, right?
He didn’t sentence me to six days
In their early days, you didn’t know your sentence
They don’t sentence you for a month, for example
We were not in a military court of our state
Meaning if you were guilty, they gave you a set sentence
They didn’t have that here, they don’t give you two days, for example
It’s unknown, it’s however long they want
Your stay or release is up to their will
Or they might bring you back again
We lived like this
Interviewer: How did you feel when you came out of the interrogation...
and when the jailer took you to enter the prison cell?
When he took me out from the interrogation
And took me to prison
I was anxious and afraid
I was afraid
Because I was going into prison and didn’t know if I’d ever get out