This is the road we were going to take, but it’s closed now
Because there is construction work
Because it was blown up, then they started rebuilding it
I’ll take you another way
So you can see what it was, and which side they were on
I’ll show you from here
Because the road is closed on that side
Because an organization is doing construction
We’ll go up here so I can show you which side the prison was on
This is the place
This place, as you see it now
They are rebuilding it
There used to be a two-story building here
The prison was upstairs, and the investigative judges were downstairs
And this was also the main Hisba headquarters
So the prison was upstairs, and as you can see now
The place was blown up, and they are rebuilding it now