The prison was upstairs
When they took me upstairs
He whipped me a few lashes the first time
My eyes were blindfolded and shut
And they brought me to the prison door
He opened the door, uncovered my eyes, then pushed me inside
When he gave me those first lashes, I entered the prison
I told myself, I’m going to die, may God have mercy on me
You don’t know whether he’ll let you out or not
You don’t know if he’ll send you home or to Wadi Okab
Interviewer: What’s Wadi Okab? Witness: It’s our graveyard
Interviewer: How long did you spend in the cell you were in?
And how did you feel being detained there?
The feeling was anxiety and fear
I was detained with them for six days the first time
But the anxiety, fear, and overthinking
Because of that you can’t focus, and you lose your appetite
And you don’t even want to drink water
We lost our nerves because we had no cigarettes for six days
As you know, I’m a smoker
And I’ve been smoking cigarettes for a long time
I’m the type who can’t stay away from a cigarette for more than an hour
So when I stayed six days without cigarettes, I lost my nerves
And I say thank God I didn’t lose my mind
Whether from torture, not smoking, or from the stress
Interviewer: How did you spend your time inside the room?
I spent most of my time asking forgiveness and in duaa [prayer]
I spent my time praying to God to deliver me from them
Interviewer: Did they stop you from talking inside the rooms?
And were you detained alone in that room?
Or how many were with you?
No, there were prisoners already there before me
So when I entered, there were already prisoners inside
Some were brought in for smuggling
Or for doing something else, for example
Or for smoking cigarettes
Or for praying
There were many prisoners, not just one or two
Interviewer: Could you talk among yourselves?
We used to talk quietly
I mean, in a low voice
Interviewer: What did you talk about? Witness: We just talked among ourselves
Because we knew each other
When I came in, I saw two or three I knew from my area
So we talked in low voices
We didn’t want anyone to hear us, because we were afraid
Interviewer: What did you talk about?
About what each of us had, and when they might release us
Or whether they’d execute us, we didn’t know
That was our talk
And most of the talk was about worrying for our children
Because you’re not alone
You left behind a family, that’s the fear
Interviewer: What sounds did you hear while you were inside the room?
And how did the place smell as well?
We used to hear sounds
They brought in people
Their voices were loud during torture
And during interrogation they screamed
That was from beating or whipping
Or from electric shocks, no one knew what it was
No one knew what they were doing to him
But it was clear from his voice that he was being interrogated
So they screamed, saying, By God, I didn’t do that
And if you swore by anything other than God, they’d beat you even harder