Interviewer: How many people were with you in the room?
Do you know what their names were?
Honestly, I don’t remember them
Because I didn’t know all of them
I knew two of them
There were two people, one of them was named Hussein
And the other was named Ahmad
They were both from here, from our area
They were imprisoned because of cigarettes
But the other people, I didn’t know them
They brought them from other areas
Interviewer: After two or three days
Didn’t ISIS plant one of their members
To act as a spy among you prisoners?
It wasn’t after two days
From the moment I arrived, there was already a spy among them
But we didn’t know who he was
We didn’t know him
When I entered the prison
I didn’t know all the people
But as you know, from being around people
You see each person’s true intention
And we had a little experience regarding that
Because I was imprisoned before ISIS existed
I had an understanding of the people in prison
And I could see each person’s goal
They had a spy who stayed with you in prison
And was present all day long
And from what I heard, they replaced him from time to time
They would take him out and put another in
So that the other could leave prison
To take leave, for example, or do something else
So yes, they had a spy
Interviewer: How did you know he was a spy?
I didn’t know him specifically
I didn’t know that this one was the spy
I didn’t know exactly whether it was him or not
Because there were many
There were two or three among them
Whenever they saw two people talking, they would come closer
Or when a group of prisoners talked together
They would approach them too
So I suspected one of them
And I suspected another as well
You didn’t know exactly who it was
These movements were obvious in prison
When you see someone talking and another approaches
That means the second one is a spy
So it was obvious
It wasn’t necessary for him to tell you he was a spy
Or for you to tell him
Interviewer: Did any of the prisoners in the room with you die?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Or was anyone tortured?
Witness: Yes, there was torture
Interviewer: How so?
Witness: By flogging and beating
But no one who was with me died
Interviewer: Was there anyone among the prisoners sentenced to death?
Witness: No