They used to bring us rice and broth
At noon and at sunset
In the morning they brought us cheese, samoon [bread roll], and tea
Because my detention was in the first year of ISIS’s presence
The heavy siege hadn’t happened yet
And supplies were available during my detention
Meaning I wasn’t imprisoned during the liberation period
At the time of food and drink shortages
No, I was imprisoned in the first year of ISIS
I was imprisoned in the first year of their entry
There was food, they brought us rice and broth
In the morning, cheese or yogurt with samoon and tea
That was the food they gave
And they gave you water
But it was tap water, not filtered
Interviewer: Was the amount of food enough?
The amount was reasonable
Even if it wasn’t filling
You don’t really feel like eating
Because of the fear and anxiety
You have no appetite to eat
You feel like you’d rather stay hungry for a month
Just to know you’ll get out
Interviewer: During the six days you stayed there
Interviewer: Were the meals given at regular times?
Witness: No
Sometimes they brought dinner with the sunset call to prayer
And sometimes after the night call to prayer
So not tied to time, not at fixed hours
There were no regular times
Interviewer: Were there illnesses in the room?
Were there people with scabies, lice, or diarrhea?
When I arrived
It was still in the beginning
Even electricity was continuous
There were also generators working
When I came in, electricity was available
So there weren’t such cases, I didn’t see that
There were people with mild symptoms
Like a light headache or stomachache
But there wasn’t scabies
The place was clean the first time
But not the second time
You couldn’t tell what was inside because of the dark
It was a basement of a house
You couldn’t tell what it had
You didn’t know if there were snakes, scorpions, or cockroaches
Interviewer: Was there medical care for the prisoners?
Like if you had a headache, would they bring you medicine?
That was in the first time I was imprisoned
The first time, they would give you a pill
A pill for inflammation
But the second time they didn’t bring anything
Even if you were close to death, they gave you no medicine
Interviewer: When they brought you a meal and it wasn’t enough
And you wanted to eat more
Could you ask them for another meal?
No, I couldn’t tell them
You couldn’t say to them that you were hungry
You couldn’t ask them for food