The toilet was in the prison
They don’t open the door for you
In the prison, meaning when you are in the cell
There was a toilet in it
The toilet was in it
So there was no need to tell them you wanted to go out
It was in the room
But in another prison, the cell was separate from the toilet
Interviewer: And when you go to the toilet, are you alone?
Yes, there’s no one else
It’s in the same cell, placed in one corner
And in the same prison cell
Interviewer: Was water and everything available there?
Meaning, could you use water as you wanted?
Yes, there was water the first time
The first time, there was water and you could use it as you wanted
And it was available later on too
Interviewer: Was the place in the toilet clean?
Not really
It was so-so
It wasn’t 100 percent clean
And not 100 percent dirty
It was in between
Interviewer: Tell me, how did you shower?
There were no showers
Do you want to shower with tap water in freezing cold
I was imprisoned in cold weather
That was in February, the first time
No, the first time was in December
And the second time was in February, it was also cold
You couldn’t shower, when we got out we showered at home
Interviewer: In which month was that?
In December and in February
Interviewer: So you didn’t shower at all?
Didn’t you ask them to let you go to the bathroom to shower?
No, I didn’t ask them that
I didn’t ask, we only did wudu [ablution] for prayer
And prayer was mandatory
It wasn’t optional, whether you wanted to or not
Everyone, before ISIS or after they left
Prayer was between him and his God
But for them, you had to pray compulsorily
Interviewer: Was the water cold or hot?
It was very cold, it was tap water
Also the tank water is colder than the tap water
Because it was winter, and there was no hot water