As for the names, like I told you, they’re all fake names
Abu Talha
Abu Aisha
Any of these names, they never call each other by real names
So you don’t know what his name is
And when you leave, you can’t see who is torturing you
Because your eyes are blindfolded
And you don’t know who he actually is
Interviewer: What were the nationalities
of those who were flogging or torturing?
I don’t know exactly what their nationalities were
Like I told you, some of them spoke Arabic
And some of them spoke Russian, I think
And some of them spoke Chinese or Japanese
Or something similar, I don’t know
And some of them spoke a language that sounded Indian or Pakistani
Some of them spoke like that
Because their Arabic was really bad
They only knew a few Arabic words
Those were the same ones who weren’t Iraqis
They spoke a few Arabic words very badly
So it was obvious they weren’t Iraqis