On the fourth day I got someone to bring me a cigarette
Interviewer: How?
Witness: With money
With money, when you go in they take everything from you
You go in without anything on you
No money or anything else, they take it all
Imagine, when I got out my money was missing
I knew exactly how much I had handed in
Eighteen thousand was missing, they took it
Interviewer: Who took it?
Witness: Them, who else
They were the ones I gave the belongings to
They were supposed to be safe-keeping
Interviewer: Who brought you the cigarette?
Witness: Just someone
I swear to you it was one of them, I swear he was ISIS
I bought it from him and told him, When I get out
Come to me so I can pay you
The cigarette cost 25,000
And a whole pack outside cost 18,000
A pack was 18,000
And I bought the cigarette from him for 25,000
Interviewer: How did you smoke it and what happened?
How did I smoke it, of course he brought it hidden
He put it inside a samoon [bread roll]
When I took the loaf I put it in my hand and hid it
I wrapped it in clothes and inside my pants
We didn’t wear belts because they took them away
It was cold, and in the bathroom
There was an electric heater hanging on the wall
When the door closed, I smoked a little of it
Then I put it out
Then I wrapped it in my clothes and went back inside
I smoked it over two days, secretly
If they had seen me that would have been the end
My punishment was 20 lashes and it would have become 60
I was imprisoned for smoking
So imagine me smoking inside
They would have punished me much harder
Interviewer: Did anyone know you were smoking?
One person knew about it
He was a prisoner who found out about me
On the third time, half the cigarette was left
I wanted to smoke it, but suddenly someone noticed and knocked on the door
He said to me, God protect you, if you have one, give me just two puffs
Don’t worry, I swear I won’t tell anyone
I told him come in, I gave him two puffs then I put it out
A little was left, I smoked it three hours later
And the one who sold me the cigarette was one of their members
Interviewer: Did you know him before?
Witness: No, I didn’t
Interviewer: How did you manage to talk to him
And ask him to bring you a cigarette?
When they bring tea, they open the prison door
And there is a room across from the prison
They threw the cigarettes inside it
When they go down, they take two prisoners out
They took the same ones every day
When they confiscated cigarettes
Quantities could be five, six, or 10 cartons
They took those two, made them carry them upstairs
They carried them up
We told them, Steal something for us
We didn’t know them, I personally didn’t
I wanted to see who they were the first time
So I told them, Steal a pack and hide it
And bring it for us to smoke, but he refused
And when he brought in the tea I asked him, What are these cigarettes
He said, Don’t you know cigarettes are banned
I said, Yes I know they are banned
I told him, I haven’t smoked for four days
I swear I’m going to lose it and explode
He told me, Dry the tea leaves with heat
And roll them in paper and smoke them
I told him, That’s not enough
And when he brought tea at sunset and opened the door
The boy went to get the tea so I got up with him
I told him, Haj, your mouth smells of cigarettes
Don’t tell me that’s not true
He told me, I used to smoke before
And I realized he smoked too
I swear to you, the café where we used to sit
Didn’t we smoke hiding in the corner
I swear to you two of them wore jackets with Hisba written on them
They came in and opened the cigarette packs
Each one had his own brand
I remember one smoked Gauloises and I don’t recall the other
They smoked five, six, seven cigarettes
They drank tea while sitting then left
I swear to you, as I told you, they were smoking cigarettes