In this prison, when they caught me the first time
He first flogged me 10 lashes
I was blindfolded, then he put me in prison
Then after three days he took me out and flogged me again
Then they put me back in prison, and three days later they took me out
The second time, when they brought me
He put me in that house I told you about
Then they brought me back to prison
And also on the first day he flogged me and put me in prison
Then I was flogged again
And after that I was flogged again
I was flogged five times in this prison, five times
Every time they flogged me 10 lashes
Imagine that when I came out my back was all marked with lines
Like zebra stripes
Blue, red, and green because of the heavy beating
Because he doesn’t hit you lightly
He flogs you hard, until he makes you scream
And because I didn’t scream, he increased the beating
Interviewer: Did he want certain information from you while flogging you?
He asked me why I’d been brought in
Because maybe the one flogging me didn’t know the reason
That was my theory
Because he would ask me, Why am I flogging you?
And I would say, Because of cigarettes
Then he would flog me
He asked me, Do you smoke cigarettes? I said, Yes
Then he flogged me, then he asked, When you get out will you smoke again?
I said, No, I will quit, then he said, You’re lying
Then he flogged me, that’s how it was
If you told him you’d quit, he wouldn’t believe you
Even if you swore to God you’d quit, he wouldn’t believe you
Interviewer: What were the types of torture used inside the prison?
Especially while you were there
I mean what was the torture you saw with your own eyes?
Witness: With my own eyes?
Interviewer: Not with your eyes, I mean how were the prisoners with you tortured?
I mean the ones you heard
Because no one could see it directly
Even when they flogged you, they blindfolded you
So you couldn’t see in front of you
When they took you out they blindfolded you
They took you to a room, flogged you, talked to you, then brought you back
As for the torture used, it was flogging
We didn’t see other types of torture
No one saw the torture of others
Many people, when they came out, they talked
One said, They hung me, another said, They tied me to the wall
So there were many forms of torture
Interviewer: Did they make you do cleaning work inside the prison?
Yes, they made us work
Interviewer: How?
Witness: One of them came in and looked around like this
And said, You, sweep here
And you, clean the toilet
And you, wash this place
And you, wipe and clean the wall
It’s a prison, they don’t bring one of their own to clean
Interviewer: Did they use certain tools or means for torture?
Do you mean instruments?
Interviewer: Like beating on the feet, or kicking
I mean hitting you with their shoes
Yes, for me they didn’t kick me or anything like that
But they beat others, that happened during interrogation
While interrogating, he would hit him
So there were people beaten during interrogation
But I didn’t know who was being beaten
Because when we heard the sounds of torture
That meant someone was being tortured
Maybe they tortured him then took him somewhere else
We didn’t know, maybe not only in this prison
There might have been another prison
Interviewer: Did they curse during torture?
Me, I didn’t hear that
I didn’t hear them cursing
And they didn’t curse me either
They brought a boy and imprisoned him with us
We didn’t know what his charge was
Even in prison he was shackled hand and foot
They would take him and hang him
They beat him badly while he was hanging, then brought him back
I remembered now, they brought him in the last two days
Even in prison he was shackled
They didn’t remove the shackles while he was inside
We didn’t know his charge, and he didn’t speak
Interviewer: Did you experience special situations like escapes or shelling?
While you were sitting in prison
As for escaping, that wasn’t possible
There was no way to escape
But they turned off the lights at night
When there were planes in the sky
When they heard the sound of planes
They turned off the lights to make the place dark
If generators were running
They turned them all off to make the place dark
So nothing would show