With this he whipped me
Not exactly this one, he also whipped me with a water hose
Interviewer: When you see these things in the street?
Yes, I immediately remember that I was tortured with them
One time he whipped me with a bamboo stick
Once I was whipped with a water hose that made a sound
And I was also whipped with something like an electric cable
Do you see this hose
With a hose like this he whipped me
He also whipped me with the stick and it left marks on my body
And the other time the electric cable was harsher
The cable strikes harder, not like the hose or the stick which are lighter
The cable hurts more in torture
Its strike is harsher
And the pain is stronger
Because it is heavy, maybe it weighs 10 kilograms
Or five kilograms, or two kilograms
The strike of the cable hurts more
So imagine if it was 20 lashes, how would you feel
You need to know that when he hits you
He counts two or three times until seven if you don’t scream
And if you remain silent without screaming from the pain
If he was hitting lightly, he increases the force so you scream
I swear to God when they gave me 20 lashes I didn’t scream
He asked me, Didn’t it hurt? I said, Yes
He said, Why didn’t you scream? I told him, I’m not a woman to scream
So he said to them, Take him back to the
prison, meaning he wanted to release me
He was supposed to release me, but he sent me back to prison
Because I didn’t scream from the pain
Many people screamed because of the pain
Of course the one who couldn’t handle it screamed
And the one who endured the whipping got beaten harder
Interviewer: Is this the story you remember most?
Yes this is what I remember most from the torture
Especially when he tortured me with 20 lashes
Because I endured the beating and didn’t scream
He sent me back to prison again and didn’t release me
That’s what I remember most
He was supposed to whip me 10 lashes and release me
But he continued to 20 lashes and said, Go back to prison
Knowing there could be someone older or younger than him
As you know my eyes were blindfolded
But the one who was questioning me
I think he was sitting at a table or something
I don’t know because my eyes were blindfolded
He said, Whip him 10 lashes and release him
But he whipped me 20 lashes and sent me back
That’s how it was, and it affected me the most
Interviewer: In the end, would you like to add something?
Or mention something you haven’t yet?
I wish I couldn’t remember anything
Interviewer: Why?
Witness: Because I want to forget them
Because while I’m talking about all this I speak as if I’m living it
Like I’m living the event in this moment
I want to forget, that’s better for me