There was a TV screen
They showed the executions they carried out, and their attacks
And the killings they carried out
Yes, of course there was a screen in the prison
But honestly, I didn’t look at it
Because I can’t bear to see a Muslim killed
In fact, I can’t bear that for any human being, not just a Muslim
This doesn’t need explaining
When you see them killing someone
It’s hard to look at it
But the people who liked them
They even put up screens in the streets
There were screens in the middle of the streets, wherever you went
They would play them, and I don’t know how—maybe with discs
They broadcast the videos they filmed on those screens
And they showed them in the streets
A lot of people watched them
And some of them were happy with what they saw
I mean, from watching people when we walked around the market
I saw some of them watching, and some of them were happy
Meaning they were their supporters
Interviewer: Was the screen in the same room where you sat?
And did they show anything else?
Or did they only show executions, ISIS videos, and hand amputations?
And how did you feel when they showed those videos?
It was in the same room where we were imprisoned
Up above, there was a screen in the room itself
They showed only their ISIS videos
They didn’t show anything else
Only killing, beheading, and their attacks
That’s what they showed
I mean, they didn’t show an Indian movie
Or an Arabic movie, for example, for you to watch
No, only their ISIS videos were shown
Interviewer: Could you write on the wall?
I mean, did you see anyone else, or did you write a note on the wall?
No, that was forbidden
It was forbidden
Imagine that from the toilet window
I could see the roof of my house
Meaning when I entered the toilet to relieve myself
I would look toward my house to reassure myself about it
I had little girls who sometimes played on the roof
So I might see them
Because my house was close, I might see them
Interviewer: Did you learn who the jailers were who brought you the food?
Or the ones who gave you instructions, for example
And what were their names? Didn’t you know who the jailers were?
Who were they? Do you mean ISIS members?
No, we didn’t know any of them
They were all strangers
I mean their looks were unfamiliar to the area inside Mosul
There wasn’t anyone from inside Mosul
From this entire Old City area
Only ten from there were with ISIS
There were many of them from other areas
But here, honestly, we didn’t have that
There were only a few ISIS members who joined them
I mean very, very few
Just a few people, you could count them on your fingers
Because people here didn’t accept that