I couldn’t sleep on my back for a month after I got out from the whipping
That was because of the pain, since my
back became striped from the whipping marks
And because of the force of the beating, swelling would appear on my back
There would be swelling where I was beaten
It would stay for a month or more until it healed
Interviewer: Did it leave scars on your body?
No, there were no scars
Interviewer: And what about the psychological harm?
How long did you keep seeing nightmares when you slept?
They lasted until we were freed
Those nightmares kept haunting me until we were freed
Interviewer: What did you dream about?
I dreamed about many things
Not every day did we see those dreams
Sometimes when you’re sitting outside
I felt like a shell was going to fall on me
Or that they were coming to kill me or detain me
And I would stay afraid, thinking about my time in prison
When something happened, I feared they would arrest me and kill me