It's like walking into
an office or a court
Same thing, like now
when we enter the court
There are people and
there are ISIS members
There are visitors coming for
identity cards and other matters
All of this while
they are present
ISIS members are present,
each sitting in his place at his desk
Their own police
And the interrogators, I
mean the whole place is ISIS
Each one has his own task, and
there are young men and adults
They come here to sort
out their IDs and their affairs
And their documents—the main
thing they take is the documents
Interviewer: He took you from this
place and grabbed you by the hand
Yes, by my hand
And he took me
to their interrogator
Interviewer: Can we go there?
There were ISIS members here
Interviewer: What
was in this corridor?
There were people sitting,
people standing, and ISIS members
It was like any other office
we have in Mosul
You see people, you see
who sits, goes, and comes
Among them are ISIS
members and ordinary citizens
To collect their personal
papers and the like
Interviewer: What was the atmosphere like?
What did you hear—jihadi chants, or the Quran?
Were there screams?
Was anyone being tortured?
How was the overall atmosphere
when you entered this corridor?
Here it was just routine—people sitting, people
here for their personal business, and so on
A lot of people were here
Especially upstairs
in their prisons
They were even torturing them—taking
them to the flogging area to flog them