Interviewer: How did you feel as you left
the interrogation room for the cell?
You can’t describe it. A prisoner is
being led to prison—what can he do?
He can’t run away
or do anything else.
If I had known it would
end with flogging and torture,
I wouldn’t have gone
back to retrieve my ID card.
Interviewer: Could you tell us about
the ISIS escort who was with you?
I told him there was no
need for prison and flogging.
I hadn’t committed a crime.
He said, The judge is the
one who sentenced you,
to spend a full day in prison
and be released the next day
as a punishment because
you argued with the guards.
Tomorrow they’ll flog
you and let you go.
I stayed with the prisoners, and
the next day they called my name,
and they flogged me.
Interviewer: Did they tell you exactly
what time you’d be released the next day?
Yes, and he said, This is a
punishment so you won’t repeat it.
You’ll be jailed and
released the following day.
They’ll flog you one hundred
lashes and let you out.
The judge sentenced
me to one hundred lashes,
and I argued with him.
This place was full
of ISIS members.
Interviewer: When you arrived here, in
this hall where people were also detained,
was the door open?
No, the door was closed.
It wasn’t open; it was shut.
There were also many people.
There were a lot
of detainees inside.
Interviewer: And you
couldn’t see anything?
No, I couldn’t see.
It was like a prison, too.
But that detention
area is upstairs.
Interviewer: Do you have
memories of the upstairs area?
I do. When we
entered the prison,
it was crowded with prisoners.
It was packed, not just
one or two prisoners;
there were many.
Interviewer: Do
you see that corner?
That corner.
Interviewer: What
does it remind you of?
When I left I
didn’t see it well.
Interviewer: You
know nothing about it?
I don’t know. I left right away.
At the end of the liberation?
They confiscated all the
satellite broadcast devices.
They used to bring them to their
Hisba bases.
Satellite receivers
and their accessories.
They’d bring them and
store them with the Hisba.
Interviewer: Did they come to
your house and confiscate anything?
Yes, they came, took the
satellite receiver, and left.
So we wouldn’t know what
was happening in the news
Interviewer: And what about those who
don’t want to hand over the satellite dish?
Whoever doesn’t want to hand over
the device, they take him and detain him
And whoever they catch with a
satellite dish, they detain him too
For example, someone who hands over one
satellite dish and hides another from them
Then an informer’s
tip comes in about him
Because there were informants
walking among the people
I mean, the informants were
moving among the people
And they find out who
owns a satellite dish
They report on people
I mean, there were
informants in Mosul
They delivered the
information to ISIS
Like they would say, So-and-so is with the security,
so-and-so is a former policeman, and so-and-so
He has this item
And this one has a weapon
I mean, they would
inform on people