This was the interrogation room
Interviewer: What do
you remember now?
What do you remember now?
I remember their
interrogators being here
Interviewer: How
many interrogators?
There were three interrogators
Three interrogators
were sitting here
In this room, three were sitting
Interviewer: How
were they sitting?
They were sitting
at their tables here
One of them would
interrogate you
But they are three. Each
one has his own case
Because they are
cases, not a single case
And each interrogator specializes
in different cases, like personal IDs
And there are cases
for other charges
Harassment cases too. They
have these matters as well
Three interrogators
were sitting here
They sit at the tables,
at three tables I saw
Three sitting
Interviewer: Who
was sitting here?
When I entered here,
an interrogator was sitting
Their judge
And he said, What do you have?
I wanted to take my personal ID, which
was confiscated at al-Salam Hospital
He asked, Why was
it taken from you?
I told him, I saw a woman alone
He said, Why did you let her ride with you when she
had no mahram [male guardian] ?
So he took the IDs and said to
me, Why did you argue with him?
I said, What else did I say but, Are we
supposed to sit at home and not drive the taxi!?
And earning a living
was already hard
He said, Then leave
the job and stay at home
I said, And what about the ten people
in the house—who will support them?
He said, That's your problem
So he sentenced me to 100 lashes
They took me up to
the cell upstairs at noon
The next day they
called me at 10 a.m.
And they flogged me 100 lashes
After that I went to collect
my personal ID from the center
There was a center at
the beginning of the street
I took my ID from there and left
After being flogged
upstairs, they brought me here
The judge himself saw
my back after the flogging
To make sure my back was red
Then he said, Go
and receive your ID
So I left here and
went to collect the ID
They gave me a receipt slip
And he told the ISIS member,
Go with him and give him his ID
Interviewer: Describe your
feeling when you entered this room
When you entered, was
this door open or closed?
And when the interrogators were
in front of you, how did you feel?
I felt like someone walking
into prison—how would I feel?!
What would you feel, I mean?
You know you’ll be
flogged and imprisoned
Either you’re jailed, or
they flog you and let you go
One of the two
And because I argued
with them and yelled
They flogged me 100 lashes
Interviewer: Who interrogated
you—what was his nationality, his accent?
His age, his appearance?
And was he masked?
No, he wasn’t wearing a mask
His beard was long
Half of them were
from Mosul
Interviewer: You didn’t even know
the name of the person sitting there?
They don’t call themselves by name...
Only by noms de guerre
Abu Hurayra, Abu Omar
Those are the names
They don’t call
each other by name
Abu so-and-so—his real name is
different, but they call him Abu so-and-so.
He doesn’t have a
name they call him by
For example, you’re
so-and-so, you’re so-and-so
Like Ahmad or Muhammad—no.
Everyone chooses a
nickname for himself
They call him by his
nickname, not his name
So no one knows he’s
so-and-so, son of so-and-so
Because then his real
identity would be known
Interviewer: Can you describe that
moment exactly when you stood here?
This door was closed
All these windows were there
I walked in and there was a
table here, right in this spot
It was their table—the
ID judge’s table
He asked me
They handed him the
slip, they already had it.
They gave him the slip and said, This
is because he argued with the brothers
So he said, Why are you arguing?
I told him, I work as a
taxi driver, trusting in God
And I argued with them
He said, Why?
I told him, We’ll quit
working and sit at home
He told me, Quit working
and stay at home—don’t work.
Those were his exact words
He said, Come on, take
him to the detention upstairs
Interviewer: When they brought you
in here, were your eyes blindfolded?
No, they weren’t blindfolded
Because my case wasn’t criminal
Or a major charge
Only those who
had a criminal case...
A serious charge—are
shackled and blindfolded
But they brought me
from the center to here
My eyes were open, and I
was walking normally beside him
But when we arrived, they took
me upstairs to the detention area
After the interrogator
took my statement
he led me upstairs
to the detention area
He said, Let him learn
some manners for a while
Interviewer: Were you sitting on
a chair during the interrogation?
No, I was standing
I stood on my feet, he asked me
the questions, and then I went upstairs
Interviewer: Was the interrogation
recorded in audio or video?
I didn’t pay attention to that
Interviewer: What
questions did he ask you?
He saw the slip and said
to me, Why are you arguing?
I told him I wasn’t arguing; I just said,
We’ll quit working and stay at home
Interviewer: In the questions he asked you,
do you think he already knew about you...
before you entered, or did he begin
asking and learn from you when you came in?
When they brought us, they
didn’t take us in right away
They don’t let you in immediately;
they make you wait outside
You stand at the door,
and the guard goes in
He asks him about
the case, and they talk
Then he tells him, Bring
him in, meaning let him enter
So you go in and tell him
Interviewer: Were you brought
for interrogation only once?
Yes, and when they flogged me, they brought me
before the investigative judge afterward to confirm
He saw my back and the redness
He said, Take him out now
so I could go and retrieve my ID
Interviewer: Didn’t they threaten you with anything?
Witness: No, they didn’t threaten me
They just flogged me one
hundred lashes and released me
Interviewer: So they didn’t threaten that if you did
it again, they’d put you in prison for a longer period?
They tell you that the second time,
the reckoning will be without limit