We left here for the prison
But the place behind the stairs is
destroyed, so we'll leave from another place
This is the staircase
They brought me from here
They took me into that room
Interviewer: Okay, the ISIS member
came down the stairs and brought you here
When you entered this
place, what could you see?
This room had nobody in it
There were no prisoners in it
In this room
That room has prisoners in it
They put us into that room
The first room
next to the stairs
There were prisoners
with us inside
Interviewer: You
entered through this door
And one of the ISIS members
was holding your hand
When you went in,
what did you see?
What do you remember about
this place when you entered?
When I entered, there was
a guard sitting here at a table
There was a table,
and sitting there
An ISIS member
And there was also an ISIS
member standing in this spot
And this hall was empty
It held no prisoners
Because their surveillance
monitor and cameras were here
A monitor where they watched
what was happening outside
Interviewer: According to your description,
there were no prisoners in this place
There were no prisoners
when they brought me in here
When they took me up the
stairs to here, the hall was empty
There were only ISIS members
And they took us to
that room immediately
That small room
Interviewer: What sounds
did you hear in this place?
There was no one here, but
over there, there were prisoners
That's where they were held
Interviewer: Alright,
take a look at the place
They may have
turned it into a prison
But when they brought me
in from here, it wasn't a prison
Maybe after that, it was
converted into a prison
Meaning it was
turned into a prison
Interviewer: What is different between
when you first entered this place and now?
The place was bombed.
That's what changed
It was a solid room,
and now it's blasted
Interviewer: What
was in this place?
This was where the camera
surveillance monitor was
They had external cameras
Whoever entered or left their
prison, they watched them on the cameras
And the prisoners too
They had a camera
pointed at the prisoners
Interviewer: Did the ISIS
member take you straight inside?
Yes, he took me
straight into the cell
Interviewer: Is it possible
for you to show us the place?
There was a table here where
an ISIS member used to sit
And another ISIS member here
In this spot
And they put me in here
There were
prisoners in this room
Interviewer: How did you know
there were prisoners inside?
I heard them; they were talking
Interviewer: Could you hear them?
Witness: Yes, I could hear them
Was the door closed?
Witness: Yes, it was closed
Interviewer: And
what is this place?
This used to be a toilet
Interviewer: Did you come here?
They would open the door for you
and let you use the toilet normally
If you asked to go to the
washbasins, he would let you in
And this is the room we were in
They detained me in this room
I spent one day
and left the next day