They detained me in this room
I stayed for a day
and left the next day
I was in this place, we
were about 30 prisoners in it
I mean, a lot of
people were here
In the room
Interviewer: 30 people?
About 30 people
But you come in and see people
going out and coming in from here
And then it’s someone
else’s turn to go out
I mean, they take them
out and bring others in
Interviewer: When you came in, what
did you talk about with the people here?
We exchanged
greetings and I just sat
And each one had a case
Most of them were about
IDs and evidentiary documents
Like if you had argued
with them or pushed them
I mean, the light
sentences are here
Not the heavy ones
I came in here, they threw
me in, closed the door, and left
So I sat here
They asked, What’s your case? I said, It’s
to pick up my ID because I argued with them
So they brought me here
Interviewer: Where were you sitting?
Witness: I was sitting here
Right here in this spot
Interviewer: What was your
impression when you entered here?
My impression was
that it was a prison
You wait anxiously to get out
Just because of my ID—I
hadn’t done anything
Just because they
took my ID from me
Interviewer: The time
you spent was one day
Yes
Interviewer: How did you spend your time with
the prisoners? What did you talk about?
Were you afraid
of some prisoners?
You’re afraid to talk about them
To be honest, you’re
afraid to talk about them
To say this or that
Because there are informants
among them you don’t know
I mean, you can’t talk
about them or curse them
Because they place an
informant among the prisoners
To find out what
you said about them
Like if you say, Tomorrow
the army will come and free us
Or you say, conditions will return
to the way they were before ISIS
You can’t talk because there are
secret informants among the prisoners
The moment you speak,
they will pass it on to them
We talk about other things,
how they brought you and why
And what’s your charge,
and you, what’s your charge
And I told them it
was for a personal ID
I had given a woman a ride alone
Interviewer: Did they forbid
talking inside the room?
No, you can talk
but not about them
I mean, you talk and
get to know the others
But you can’t talk about ISIS
Interviewer: What sounds did you
hear while you were inside this room?
And how was the
smell of the place?
The smell of sweat and the
smell of people in the prison
Some of them had been here
for a week, or four days, or three
And there were no
showers for bathing
In fact you only went to
the washrooms once a day
Interviewer: Is there a story you remember, whether
funny or sad, that happened to you inside the prison?
In that situation everyone was sad.
Who would be happy in those days?
Everyone had had
their fill of oppression
I mean, look where we
were and where we’d ended up
Anyone would be
crushed by what had happened
I mean, you enter a detention center
and get imprisoned over an ID card
Now if you argue with a policeman he
hands you your ID and tells you to go
But those people had no mercy
They were not
merciful with people
Interviewer: You said you’re a smoker. How
could you go a whole day without smoking?
You can put up with that
You are forced to
I mean, they can prevent
you from having a cigarette
Interviewer: How many
people were with you?
We were about thirty people here
Interviewer: Do you
remember any of them?
They were folks from Mosul—people
from the villages and countryside
And from inside Mosul, some were
from the right bank and the left bank
If I saw him now I’d recognize
the face of the one who was with me
Interviewer: Didn’t
you make friends?
You can’t do that
in a day or two
We just exchanged
greetings, and I sat in this spot
And they all sat
lined up like this
And when you sleep the place
gets crowded with rows of sleepers
Interviewer: In which
row did you sleep?
I was here next to the window
where there was only a small opening
I was sleeping here
And the person’s
feet were toward you
We were lined up
almost one after another
Interviewer: Was it
winter or summer?
No, summer—around July
At that time, in the heat
And there was
only this ceiling fan
Interviewer: Wasn’t there an air-conditioning unit?
Witness: What?
Wasn’t there an
air-conditioning unit?
I mean cooling
There was no cooling
Air conditioners, I
mean—no, there weren’t any
Just this fan
Interviewer: What were the charges
against the prisoners who were with you?
Here they kept those
with light sentences
They didn’t have heavy sentences
These were light sentences here
Interviewer: Also
cigarette charges?
Yes, cigarettes and a quarrel
And for the IDs, those kinds
of things that happened here
Most of the charges were
about arguing with them
And you’d spend
two or three days
And get flogged
Interviewer: How was the
relationship among you prisoners?
The relationship
was good among us
Just a group sitting in a
prison, talking and laughing
Yes, but you couldn’t smoke
And you couldn’t talk about them
Because you feared the undercover
informant would pass on your words
He would go and tell them,
so-and-so is talking about you
Interviewer: Did you
feel there was a spy?
There is—in every prison they have an
undercover informant, but you don’t know who
I mean, among those thirty, one of them
is the informant, but you don’t know which
And he’s the one
who gets you talking
He tries to trap
you into talking
So people knew there was a spy
But he never reveals himself
Interviewer: Were these windows
closed or completely open?
Only this opening
Just this one for ventilation
For ventilation
Those are windows
Interviewer: And this?
This one is also closed, and
the upper part was for ventilation
This one was completely closed
There was only
one for ventilation
And these windows are closed
And up here there’s
only a spot for ventilation
Just so they could
breathe in these rooms
Interviewer: Do you
remember anyone dying here?
No, no one died here
I stayed one night and left
I didn’t stay for days or a week
Interviewer: Was anyone
tortured in this room?
No, they didn’t beat
anyone in front of me
Interviewer: Does this
blanket remind you of anything?
I haven’t seen it before
The floor was clean
and we sat directly on it
There were no mattresses
There were none in this hall
The tiles were clean
and we sat on them
You slept and sat on the tiles
Sometimes you’d sleep while sitting—if
there wasn’t space, you slept sitting
Interviewer: Was any
prisoner sentenced to death?
No, here the charges were light
Anyone sentenced to death was
taken somewhere else, another prison
Interviewer: Was there a screen
to show ISIS videos in this room?
No, there was no TV
screen for ISIS videos
Interviewer: Did prisoners
write memories on the wall?
Anything they try
to write on the wall
We don't have a
pen or anything else
They search you, empty your
pockets, and then they send you in