Interviewer: Didn’t you ask him on
the way where he was taking you?
I asked him where he was taking me, and
he told me he was taking me to the judge
To their own judge
He took me to the
investigative judge there
He looked at my slip and said,
You’re so-and-so. I said, Yes
He said, Take him for flogging
So they brought me
into that last room inside
There’s a room there
They flogged me in that room
Interviewer: The same room?
No, that room over there
That room inside, over there
Interviewer: Where
did you go in from here?
He took me up these
stairs and into the room
Interviewer: When you
came down, what did you see?
You were a prisoner
for one day in that room?
I also saw ISIS members
and other people there
Some were being released
And others were
being brought in here
On light and heavy
charges and sentences
They brought them in
Interviewer: Did you know
how many lashes you would get?
I didn’t know exactly
But I heard the judge sentence
me to one hundred lashes
The day before, when they took my
belongings, he said, One hundred lashes
He told me, You have
one hundred lashes
But go now to be disciplined
Go into the prison;
God is generous
Until tomorrow, God is generous
At ten in the morning
they brought me
They took me to the judge,
and he said, Take him for flogging
They took me into the
last room and flogged me
Interviewer: How many
lashes did they give you?
They flogged me
one hundred lashes
Interviewer: From where did the ISIS member take
you out when you left the investigation room?
He didn’t take me out from there;
he took me out via these stairs
Interviewer: Could you
take us to the room?
Sure
He didn’t take me out from here
He didn’t take me up these
stairs, but those stairs over there
Interviewer: What did you say to
him when he brought you here?
I didn’t talk to him
He held me by the hand and
brought me to the flogger who was here
I was flogged in this room
Interviewer: Didn’t you talk
while that was happening?
I didn’t talk
He told me, You’ll be flogged.
I said, I’ll be flogged, OK
Will I die from flogging?!
Interviewer: What did you
see in this room and that room?
ISIS members were
present in this room
In these rooms too
ISIS is here in great numbers
This is their prison
Headquarters
Interviewer: Were there people
waiting for their turn to be flogged?
No, there were not
They only bring the prisoner when he is sentenced
to flogging. No one waits for the other to finish
And when he said, 100 lashes,
he brought me to this place
The flogger took me inside
There is a flogger
specialized for these matters
He came with his whip
and flogged me 100 lashes
But at first the
lashes were light
He was counting them that way
Then he kept going, harder each
time, and flogged me very hard in the end
So it would show that the
prisoner had been flogged
Because if the judge sees your
back and it is not properly flogged
He orders that you
be flogged again
Saying your flogging was light
Meaning it was not strong
Meaning it depends on the lashes
If it is 50 or 60 lashes, they
are light and not very strong
After that the remaining
lashes have to be severe