I came in here and
the room was empty
And they flogged me here
They made me stand up, and I was wearing
trousers then, or rather sirwal
And a sweater. He
made me take it off
And he flogged me here
He tells you, while flogging, Ask your Lord
for forgiveness, ask God for forgiveness
Interviewer: How was your
posture? Were you standing upright?
Yes, I was standing right here
And wearing the sirwal,
and my sweater was off
And he lashed my
back with their whip
Interviewer: And your hands?
My hands were like this, forward
Interviewer: How many
people were in this room?
No one, just me and the flogger
These things weren’t
here—this was an empty room
The ISIS flogger brought
me in and made me stand
And he started flogging
Interviewer: Do you think they
did this to get information from you?
It was flogging for
punishment only
If they wanted information from
someone, they’d take it from him
I mean, he doesn’t beat you
to make you say this or that
He flogs for the ID
issue, just 100 lashes
Interviewer: What type of
torture was common in this prison?
I was only flogged; I
don’t know about the rest
And this isn’t their only
prison—they have many prisons
Across various Hisba bases—not just this one
There was Badush
Prison, which held detainees
And Mosul Tasfirat
Prison also had detainees
But this was a Hisba base
Interviewer: Was there sukhra [forced
labor] or did they order you to clean?
Inside the prison?
No, there wasn’t
I mean, they don’t throw trash
And tell you, come
and clean the trash
It wasn’t like that
Interviewer: What instrument
did he use to flog you?
Their flogging whip is a stick
With leather strips
like belt leather
And he flogs
Until it leaves a real
mark on the back
Interviewer: Did the flogger insult you
or use obscene words while flogging?
The flogger only stood, flogged, and
told me—Ask your Lord for forgiveness
He only says—Ask
your Lord for forgiveness
Interviewer: Was there sympathy
for the prisoners inside the cell?
You mean among
the prisoners, or how?
Interviewer: I mean, was there sympathy
from the ISIS member toward you?
No, he sympathized with no one
Only the washbasins
issue, as I said, that’s all
Interviewer: Could you hear the prisoners’
voices while they were being tortured?
I didn’t hear, but the torture
places existed, not in this place
I didn't see a torture room, but
there were dedicated rooms for torture
If someone was charged with a serious offense,
they took him elsewhere and tortured him
Not inside this place
Only minor charges
were handled here
The light detention was here
But anyone with a serious charge was
taken to another place, another prison
He was transferred to
another prison immediately
Interviewer: What about women?
I didn't see any women here
I mean, I didn't see
female prisoners here
Interviewer: The one who tortured or
flogged you—what was his nationality?
I don't know his nationality
But it's clear he was Iraqi
From his speech, it's
obvious he was Iraqi
Most of them are from
villages and rural areas
Those areas are outside
Mosul, not inside it
Interviewer: Was there any
prisoner who was with you
Whom they took out for flogging
and then brought back to the cell?
No. As I told you, when they flog
someone, they remove him afterward
Interviewer: Did the flogging
leave a physical mark on you?
Of course. Someone hits you
on your back with 100 lashes
I suffered with my
back for about a week
My back stayed red for a week
I used treatments and
ointments until the pain eased a bit
The flogged area is
obvious—its color is red
When anyone is hit with a
water hose or something else
The beating marks will appear
They stayed for about
a week or ten days
I couldn't sleep on my back
I slept on my stomach
Interviewer: What's
the story of your illness?
And what was the main cause?
When ISIS entered, I was
working with transport trucks
When they came in, I
could no longer work
I got older, but
not just from age
Livelihood was unavailable
I'm responsible for ten people
Because of that, I fell ill
I developed
cirrhosis of the liver
My lungs are fatigued
And the kidneys too
I underwent
catheterization twice
My blood sugar level reaches 600
And cataracts affected my eyes
I had surgery on one eye, and
the other still needs an operation
Thank God in every circumstance
Because of ISIS I
contracted all these diseases
I used to work, and after they
came I stayed home for a long time
There was no work
I was forced to
work as a taxi driver
I had to work as a
taxi driver for a while.
After the liberation,
I got sick, so I couldn’t get
back to working on trucks.
Because my line of
work is transport trucks.
Thank God.