Interviewer: Where did you
go once you left this place?
I left this place and
he took me to the judge
He witnessed my flogging
punishment, and gave me a receipt
He said, Take him
and give him his ID
There at the headquarters, at the center
that used to be the old police station
That’s where the IDs were
I went and gave him the receipt—he
pulled out my ID and handed it to me
I took it and went home
Interviewer: Do you still have the receipt?
Witness: Yes, it’s at home
Interviewer: The jailer
took you to interrogation
And from the
interrogation to there
Interviewer: Shall we go out?
Let’s go
Interviewer: Was the ISIS
member walking with you here then?
Yes, he was walking with me and brought
me in to the investigative judge here
Interviewer: After
he let you out?
After he let me out, I
walked with him normally
I went to pick up the ID from
the center and then home
Interviewer: Were you hurt?
How could I not be hurt!?
I even had trouble
putting on my sweater
When I got home I took the sweater off, for
ten days I couldn’t wear anything on top
Ten days, I couldn’t wear it
Because of the pain
the torture left in my back
Interviewer: Did it leave a
mark on your body until now?
No, no mark remains now
That detention was
seven years ago
The flogging didn’t leave a
deep pit or anything like that
The effect was like someone who had
swum under the sun and got sunburned
And he can’t sleep on his back
The same situation
But this was
flogging, not the sun
I left, took my ID,
and then went home
You can’t work
or do anything else
Ten days I slept on my face
Because of the pain in my back
Interviewer: Did you
leave through this door?
Yes, they took me
out through this door
From here they took
me to the main street
And to the center, that center I told you
about across from the Prophet Jirjis Mosque
It was an old police station
They were based there
I got my ID and left