They would stand here, their
guard post was in this spot
And when you called him,
he'd come and take you out
Interviewer: And where
are the washbasins?
These are the washbasins
Interviewer: Is this a bathroom?
It's a bathroom, but
there's no showering
They don't let anyone shower
You only go into the toilet
Interviewer: Is the
bathroom in the same place?
The washbasins are here
And here are the
other washbasins
Here we go in, take care
of our needs, and come out
I mean the washbasins
are only here
Interviewer: Were you put under
any pressure when you went in?
No, no, you went in normally
and took the time you needed
Interviewer: Where
did the jailer stand?
He stood here in this spot
We used to
call—hajji, washbasins
He'd come, open the door, and say—Who
wants to go out to the washbasins?
Then he'd take him out
He'd bring the person back once he was done
and ask—Does anyone else want to go in?
Each person was allowed
to go to the washbasins twice
Interviewer: Was
water available?
Yes, it was
Interviewer: How
was the cleanliness?
This chapel was clean
They used to wash it—he'd
hold the water hose and wash
And if no guards were around,
the prisoners cleaned it themselves
I mean they cleaned
in their own spots
I didn't see them
But they said they sometimes
went out and cleaned
That's what the guys who'd
been here more than ten days said
They'd go out to rinse and
clean and then go back inside
They only cleaned the washbasins
The corridors were
clean—there was no dirt
Interviewer: Were people harassed
when they went into the toilet?
Like the jailer banging on
the door to hurry them out?
No, you took your time, finished,
came out, and he put you back inside
Everyone called them hajji
No one used the word ISIS
Interviewer: Have there been
any changes to the place?
The place is the
same—it hasn't changed
Interviewer: Could you go
inside and show us the place?
This is the place
Interviewer: Nothing
has changed in it?
No, it's the same place
Interviewer: Was there
an open window here?
It was closed off
with this metal sheet
Just a spot for ventilation
But the sheet is here
and there's a square gap
Only for ventilation
Interviewer: Haven't you heard
of anyone who tried to escape?
No, no one
Interviewer: We saw some
prisoners go to the toilets
Just so they could sit
by themselves for a bit
Do you know people like that, or did
you yourself try to sit alone for a while?
No, no
People would only relieve
themselves and come back