Younes Basil
Muhammad, from Mosul
I neither study nor work
They detained me once
They came and took
me from the house
That was because my uncle
belonged to the intelligence service
They confiscated his house
And seized the belongings
Meaning they became theirs
When I came to take the
belongings, they considered me a thief
Interviewer: Did you come to take the house
belongings after they had written “confiscated” on it?
After they wrote on the house that it was
confiscated, I went in to take the belongings
Interviewer: Do you remember the
month and year you were detained?
Also the circumstances of your
detention — was it in winter or summer?
Did it happen in the afternoon or at sunset? And
how did they come to take you from the house?
They came to me in the morning
They came to my family’s house
And I wasn’t there then
I was at my friend’s
And when I returned home
My mother told me then that ISIS
had come to the house looking for me
And they asked about me
I asked her the reason,
but she didn’t know
I sat with my mother for
about fifteen to thirty minutes
Then they came again to
the house a second time
They knocked on the door and asked
for me, so I went down to see them
They asked me to go with
them to inquire about something
And I went with them
They took me to Dawasa Prison
I spent about ten days there
Then they transferred me to
the QaimaqamPrison
And from there
they brought me here
I spent here about one
month and twenty days
After the twenty days
They told me that I
had been released
They took me to the
hisba [religious police] car
They prepared an
anesthetic injection for me
And injected it into my arm
And before the people’s
eyes, they cut off my hand
Interviewer: Was that after the
twenty-first day of your detention?
No, after one month
and twenty days
Interviewer: After they took you
from the house to Dawasa Prison
Did they imprison
you there or here?
They imprisoned me there,
then transferred me here
Interviewer: Did they transfer you
here after they amputated your hand?
No, before that
They brought me here
Interviewer: Tell me about the
conditions of your arrival at this place.
What time was it?
Was it in the
afternoon or at sunset?
And was it winter or summer?
Who came with you? And were your
eyes blindfolded or your hands shackled?
My hands were shackled
And my eyes were blindfolded
There were about five
or six detainees with me
But their charges were different
They brought me here
around two in the afternoon
They transferred me
from the prison to here
Interviewer: Which
prison do you mean?
Dawasa Prison
Interviewer: How many ISIS
members were accompanying you?
Do you remember their
names or nationalities?
I don’t remember their
names or what they looked like
But there were about six
men who brought us here
Interviewer: When you
reached this entrance
The church that
had become a prison
Interviewer: Did they
blindfold your eyes?
Yes, my eyes were blindfolded
Interviewer: And your
hands were shackled?
Yes
Interviewer: Had you heard of this
prison or know anything about it before?
No, I had heard of the Hisba,
but I didn’t know what it was
Interviewer: You didn’t know that this church
had been turned into a prison and held prisoners?
No, I thought it was
just a regular house
And they used it for
flogging or punishing people
And then they would release them
I didn’t think it was a prison
Interviewer: How did you and the people with
you feel when you arrived at this entrance?
What did you feel, and what
thoughts went through your mind?
I was very afraid
I was scared they would kill me
even though I hadn’t done anything
When I arrived they took
me in through this door
They led me in with
five or six other people
Interviewer: Where
did they take you?
From here?
Yes, we came from
here and they led us in
There were prisoners inside
And the ISIS members
were flogging them
Some were brought here for
smoking cigarettes or for mobile phones
Others for writing slogans
like Long live Iraq on the walls
So they led us into the hall
Interviewer: Today, when you look
at the entrance you’re standing next to
What has changed in this entrance,
whether in features or appearance?
Since the time ISIS was here
until today, what has changed?
While standing here, do old
feelings come back to you?
Or do you feel that you’ve
become a free person?
When I came here I remembered
my hand and wished it were still here
Interviewer: Do you feel that the
entrance’s appearance has changed?
And has the place and your memories
of it changed, or is it still the same?
It’s still the same
Interviewer: Did the arrest
involve insults or beatings?
Or even kicking you with their
feet? Or was it a routine arrest?
They made us bow our heads
And our hands were
shackled behind us
And we walked one after another
Interviewer: Wasn't there any
cursing or beating with that?
Yes, they beat us
Interviewer: On the way?
Yes