When they brought me in through this door
Our hands were cuffed and our heads bowed
They made us walk like this, one after another
They brought me in here and took me up these stairs
Here by these stairs, I heard children’s voices
They had imprisoned women down here
I mean in the halls
And when they took me up these stairs to the door of that hall
At the hall door, they removed my blindfold, undid my handcuffs, and took me inside
After that I did not see anything
I stayed there until they took me out to amputate my hand
They also blindfolded me inside the hall
They took me down the stairs here
They walked me out and I got into the car
Interviewer: What sounds could you hear besides the voices of the children and the women?
What kind of sound was coming from inside?
Other than those sounds, what were you able to hear?
I could hear those being flogged and those being beaten
And people saying, I will not do it again, that was about cigarettes
And because of the phone
Interviewer: And the voices of the women and the children, what kind of sound was it?
There were also women selling cigarettes
Because cigarettes were forbidden
They would arrest her over cigarettes and flog her
And whoever did something wrong, they would bring her in and flog her too
Things like that