I left that room
and sat in this one
And this was a
corridor from here
Anyone who wanted to pray or
go to the bathroom
I met someone here
He said, If you
need anything
I said to him,
Why are you asking that?
He said, I will
be released today
I said, I want you to go to
my family and tell them I am fine
And that I am here and, God willing,
I will be released, and things like that
After that I went back and
moved to the first room
The ones they brought in and the
ones they disappeared, I saw them
And those who came from
ISIS were masked
At 9 or 10 at night,
we had to be asleep
They did not allow any
sound after that
Interviewer: When you were inside this room,
what sounds did you hear from outside?
And what did the
place smell like?
We heard whoever
was being flogged
And someone screaming and
saying, I will not do it again
Just this time, by God
I will not do it again
We used to hear
different things
Interviewer: About the people who
were with you inside this room
Did you make
friends with them?
Or only that person who would
deliver a message to your family?
No, only that person, because I did
not like to build relationships here
Interviewer: Those who were inside
this cell, what were their charges?
Did you know them, and were any
of them your neighbors in the area?
Only one person. He was
one of my neighbors
And he is now with
the security forces
They also detained him
because of cigarettes
They also flogged him
and released him
Interviewer: Is there an unforgettable
incident that happened to you in this room?
Tell us about it now
What happened, and
what made you leave?
It was prayer time and we
got up for ablution to pray
I went out from
here and heard sounds
And there was
metal here
A piece of metal
And there was a small
hole, so I looked through it
A person was standing here
in the middle of the courtyard
Holding a sword and
holding it like that
And he was masked
Interviewer: What did you feel
when you saw that scene?
I do not know what to tell you.
I was young, of course I felt afraid