The first room was full, about 75 to 100 people
And I came to this second room, it was full too
I came through this door
I entered from here, and I saw someone sitting here
I was young then
He said–What's your charge? I told him, Theft
He said–People accused of theft don't sit with me here in the hall
They go to the hall in front of me
We started shouting at each other, then he went quiet
I went in and sat here for a bit
Interviewer: Why were you shouting at each other?
He said to me–People who steal don't stay with me here in the hall
They don't sit here with us
So I sat here for a bit
So I moved away from him and sat here, where five to six people were sleeping
Wrapped in a blanket
The same as this one, and they had put it here
So I came here, laid my head down, and slept
I woke up at night, they brought us food and we ate
Interviewer: Did you spend the first night in this room?
Witness: Yes
Interviewer: When you woke up, did they bring you food after that?
They brought the food and woke me up
Interviewer: What kind of food did they give you on the first night?
It was rice and soup
Interviewer: And on the second day in the morning, what happened?
The guards came in carrying the Lakhdar Brahimi hose
Two came in here
And three were standing here
They were ISIS members
And they were here in the first hall
And there was a person standing here by the iron bars, watching
To see who had banged on the bars
Everyone said it wasn't them
So they beat three or four of us and left
Interviewer: Was this on the second day?
And after that they issued a general amnesty
Interviewer: After how many days?
After about a month