I spent four days here
They didn't move me to the room, I came here myself
I came and stayed here
Interviewer: How many days?
I spent the entire detention period here
I spent one day in Dawasa Prison, four days in that room, and I completed the rest of the time here
I stayed for a month and twenty days
We spent the time here sitting and praying
And some were learning how to pray
They taught them the Quran and prayer
The toilets were over there
We used them for wudu [ablution] or to relieve ourselves
Interviewer: Do you remember how many prisoners were with you in this room?
Interviewer: Do you remember their names, or did you know any of them?
No, I didn't know their names
I only got to know two or three people, but I don't remember their names
But the number of people here was around fifty
It ranged from fifty to seventy people
Interviewer: What kinds of charges were brought against the people here?
This place was designated for people with light charges
Like smoking cigarettes
Or theft
Like someone who had stolen a motorcycle
Or anything else
They would bring him here
As for the other hall inside
It was designated for people who used their mobile phones to pass information
Or those caught with a large quantity of cigarettes
Like a car full of cigarettes
Any vehicle carrying a load of cigarettes
Interviewer: How were the relationships among the prisoners?
A superficial relationship, no more than a few brief questions and answers
Interviewer: Let's talk about how you spent your time in this room
I spent most of my time sleeping
Just sleeping
When it was time for prayer, I got up to pray, then went back to sleep
And when they brought us food, I got up to eat, then slept again
Interviewer: Let's talk about the meals
Interviewer: What kind of meals were you given?
Interviewer: Were they served at regular times?
Interviewer: And were the meals filling?
Sometimes they brought us rice, and at other times soup
It was varied
We had tahini, cream, and samoon [bread roll]
When we felt hungry we ate tahini
Or cream
And samoon bread as well
We also had tea
Interviewer: Which jailer was responsible for bringing you the food?
There wasn't a specific person
They bring the food pots and leave them here at the door
Then they open the door and tell us to bring them into the room
And the prisoners divide the food
Interviewer: Were the meals served at regular times?
Interviewer: I mean breakfast, lunch, and dinner?
Interviewer: And were they filling?
Yes, they brought lunch on time
And dinner too
And breakfast as well
They brought us breakfast at the dawn prayer
Except during the month of Ramadan
So that was only on the days of iftar
As for the other days, we were fasting
Interviewer: What about suhur?
They brought us suhur, and then we would wait for the time of iftar
Interviewer: Did they respond to your requests?
Interviewer: And would you ask for specific things?
Interviewer: Like asking to increase the amount of food because it wasn’t enough?
Interviewer: Or to improve healthcare?
Interviewer: Or about the shortage of bedding used for sleep?
No one dared to talk to them about anything
No one could even reach the door
They stood next to the door here
If one of the officials wanted
To talk to a prisoner or interrogate him about something
They would take him to the hall
They interrogated him and then brought him back
That was all
Interviewer: Did ISIS members set up a display screen for you?
Interviewer: I mean, did they show you videos of the executions they carried out on it?
Interviewer: Or hand amputations?
Interviewer: And were these screens inside the prison?
There aren’t any here
There are no screens here
Meaning there was no showing of executions or any ISIS videos in this hall
Interviewer: What about inside the prison?
I have no idea, I wasn’t inside
Interviewer: Tell me what you used to hear
Interviewer: I mean what you heard  about the outside world while you were in the cell
Interviewer: Given that you were inside a closed world and a closed cell
Interviewer: What kinds of sounds did you hear from outside?
Interviewer: And did they let you know what was happening outside?
I used to hear sounds coming from the hall
For example, the sounds of women being beaten
Or people being flogged
Because they possessed a dozen or more cigarettes
Or someone who had stolen a motorcycle, so they flogged him
If the charge was light, they released him
They carried out the flogging sentence on him and then released him
Interviewer: During the time you were in these three cells where you slept
I spent four days here
They didn't move me to the room, I came here myself
I came and stayed here
Interviewer: How many days?
I spent the entire detention period here
I spent one day in Dawasa Prison, four days in that room, and I completed the rest of the time here
I stayed for a month and twenty days
We spent the time here sitting and praying
And some were learning how to pray
They taught them the Quran and prayer
The toilets were over there
We used them for wudu [ablution] or to relieve ourselves
Interviewer: Do you remember how many prisoners were with you in this room?
Do you remember their names, or did you know any of them?
No, I didn't know their names
I only got to know two or three people, but I don't remember their names
But the number of people here was around fifty
It ranged from fifty to seventy people
Interviewer: What kinds of charges were brought against the people here?
This place was designated for people with light charges
Like smoking cigarettes
Or theft
Like someone who had stolen a motorcycle
Or anything else
They would bring him here
As for the other hall inside
It was designated for people who used their mobile phones to pass information
Or those caught with a large quantity of cigarettes
Like a car full of cigarettes
Any vehicle carrying a load of cigarettes
Interviewer: How were the relationships among the prisoners?
A superficial relationship, no more than a few brief questions and answers
Interviewer: Let's talk about how you spent your time in this room
I spent most of my time sleeping
Just sleeping
When it was time for prayer, I got up to pray, then went back to sleep
And when they brought us food, I got up to eat, then slept again
Interviewer: Let's talk about the meals
What kind of meals were you given?
Were they served at regular times?
And were the meals filling?
Sometimes they brought us rice, and at other times soup
It was varied
We had tahini, cream, and samoon [bread roll]
When we felt hungry we ate tahini
Or cream
And samoon bread as well
We also had tea
Interviewer: Which jailer was responsible for bringing you the food?
There wasn't a specific person
They bring the food pots and leave them here at the door
Then they open the door and tell us to bring them into the room
And the prisoners divide the food
Interviewer: Were the meals served at regular times?
I mean breakfast, lunch, and dinner?
And were they filling?
Yes, they brought lunch on time
And dinner too
And breakfast as well
They brought us breakfast at the dawn prayer
Except during the month of Ramadan
So that was only on the days of iftar
As for the other days, we were fasting
Interviewer: What about suhur?
They brought us suhur, and then we would wait for the time of iftar
Interviewer: Did they respond to your requests?
And would you ask for specific things?
Like asking to increase the amount of food because it wasn’t enough?
Or to improve healthcare?
Or about the shortage of bedding used for sleep?
No one dared to talk to them about anything
No one could even reach the door
They stood next to the door here
If one of the officials wanted
To talk to a prisoner or interrogate him about something
They would take him to the hall
They interrogated him and then brought him back
That was all
Interviewer: Did ISIS members set up a display screen for you?
I mean, did they show you videos of the executions they carried out through it?
Or hand amputations?
And were these screens inside the prison?
There aren’t any here
There are no screens here
Meaning there was no showing of executions or any ISIS videos in this hall
Interviewer: What about inside the prison?
I have no idea, I wasn’t inside
Interviewer: Tell me what you used to hear
I mean what you heard while you were inside the cell about the outside world
Given that you were inside a closed world and a closed cell
What kinds of sounds did you hear from outside?
And did they let you know what was happening outside?
I used to hear sounds coming from the hall
For example, the sounds of women being beaten
Or people being flogged
Because they possessed a dozen or more cigarettes
Or someone who had stolen a motorcycle, so they flogged him
If the charge was light, they released him
They carried out the flogging sentence on him and then released him
Interviewer: During the time you were in these three cells where you slept
Each one was inside the other
Did you feel there was an ISIS spy among you?
No, I did not feel there was any spy with us in the hall
Interviewer: You never felt that at all?
Not at all
Interviewer: Did you write any memories on the walls?
Or did someone else try that while you were in these cells?
It was forbidden for anyone to write on the wall
We were not allowed to keep anything with us
That was to prevent cases of prisoners who might harm themselves
Or try to cut their wrists, and so on
So they did not allow us to keep any object
Interviewer: Do you remember the names of the jailers who used to come here?
Or even their nationalities or descriptions?
No, I do not remember them
Interviewer: You do not know them at all? Witness: No
Interviewer: Who was the jailer responsible for bringing you food?
I do not know
They would put the food near the door
Then the prisoners would pull it in and share it among themselves
Interviewer: Did you make any attempt to escape from the prison with other prisoners?
I wanted to escape on my own
I stood in this spot and looked at the fence
The fence was worn out and easy to push
But I felt afraid
That they would catch me and kill me
I hesitated, then I backed off and sat down
Interviewer: Could that attempt have succeeded?
Yes, it was possible
But I hesitated and feared they would kill me
So I stayed seated where I was
Interviewer: Were there surveillance cameras?
No, there were none
Interviewer: Was there a large number of ISIS members spread across the church cells?
Yes
Interviewer: Can you count them?
About twenty-five members
Interviewer: Who do you mean?
I mean, the ISIS members were twenty or twenty-five
Interviewer: Today, as you stand in the room where you were held
Tell me about the changes you notice in this room
How was it during the period of ISIS control?
What did it look like, and what did it contain?
And what has changed in it today?
Nothing has changed in it, only the fence that was here
They removed it
The same hall, the same place
There were sleeping mats here
And someone used to sleep here
And the curtain hung here
And there was also a mattress over there
And here we would put the cream and the samoon [bread roll], and so on
Interviewer: Tell me about the blankets used for sleeping
Or the items used for it, like pillows
Or the blankets and the mats
Were there enough of them?
Were they distributed in an orderly way, and were they clean?
The blankets were not enough
And there were no pillows
We would put the blanket on the floor
And shape it like a long pillow
And sleep on it, that is what we did
Interviewer: Was the space sufficient for sleeping?
Yes, but sometimes we suffered from cramped space