The curtain looks the same
Where we used to shower and wash
We had put it up for that purpose
Or for anyone doing wudu [ablution] for prayer as well
And the smell reached inside, even to the third room
Meaning whoever wanted to use the toilet or wash
Or whoever wanted to do wudu [ablution] to pray and make supplication
Would come here
Interviewer: Did the bathroom break down so you couldn’t use it?
No, it didn’t break down
Interviewer: Was the water available at all times?
Yes, it was always available
Interviewer: Tell me about cleaning supplies, soap and so on.
Only soap was available
Scrubbing gloves for the showers weren’t available, and we couldn’t shower daily
Only every three or four days
And sometimes every fifteen days
That’s how we used to shower
Interviewer: Did you feel privacy when you went to the toilet?
Or could people hear sounds from inside?
And did you suffer from that while washing or showering?
There was no privacy
And that was the reason we put this curtain here
It was hard for us even to use the toilet
Interviewer: Were you harassed by prisoners while you were in the toilet?
Did anyone harass you?
Okay, what happened?
An argument broke out among us and our shouting got louder
Interviewer: What was the reason?
Over access to the bathroom to use the toilet
It wasn’t just me, the other prisoners did too
It was hard for everyone to use the toilet, do wudu [ablution], or shower
Someone would sit here to keep count and police the prisoners
If a prisoner went in more than once to use the toilet or do wudu [ablution]
Interviewer: What changes have happened to the bathroom since then?
Nothing at all has changed
The bathroom is the same, and the sink is the same
We used to try to look through that window
We would look out of it toward the alley
And watch the civilians going back and forth
We used to see the children playing in the neighboring houses
We saw all that through that window
When I came, I heard children’s voices
I figured they were kids
So I snuck a look from here
Through a small opening in that metal
And I saw children standing in the next room by the window
And they were crying
And I felt afraid
So I sat still in my place without moving or making a sound
Someone asked me what I’d seen, and I said nothing
I stayed silent and frozen in place
Interviewer: Do you mean the prisoners’ children?
Or who were those children?
Their mother was detained for possessing cigarettes
So her children were watching from the window
Their mother was being beaten in front of them
They were flogging her here
In the middle of the yard
And her little children were watching her
Interviewer: What kind of sounds did you hear while you were in this room?
Did you hear sounds from outside?
And was that late at night?
No, there were no sounds at night
And there were no sounds of beating
But anyone who came on the charge of passing information over the phone
About the security forces, for example
They would bring him to the hall to hold him to account
And they would flog him or beat him
Interviewer: Did they ask you about the items you had stolen during the torture?
And how did they know you were the thief when you were this young?
And what items did you steal from your uncle’s house?
They said someone from the area had reported me
Saying that I had taken the items
They asked me where the items were, and I said I didn’t know
So they started torturing me and beating me
And they threatened to burn me with cooking oil
And they kept torturing me
And beating me with shoes and slaps
And even kicking or hitting me with a bamboo stick
They tortured me until the very last moment
They burned me here, in this spot
The burn mark is still there
Interviewer: What did they burn you with?
With a metal rod
They burned me with it here
And then they left me
After I’d confessed to stealing the items and where they were
Interviewer: What items did you take?
A whole home’s belongings
Interviewer: Like what?
The household furniture
Interviewer: Did you move it to your house?
Yes
Interviewer: Did they later confiscate it from your home?
Witness: No
Interviewer: Did they need it themselves?
When they confiscate a house, they consider it to have become theirs
For example, if they confiscated a home of one of the Rawafid [pejorative for Shia], they considered it theirs
Either they used it to live in
Or they took the household belongings as spoils
And they sold them in a large place designated for that