They came to call out the names
So they called my name
They told us that anyone under sixteen years old
Was ordered released by the one they called “the judge”
And indeed they took us down
We were seven or eight people
They took us down the stairs to here
There were prisoners here, blindfolded
They were right here
We stood with them and they started bringing us in one by one
Interviewer: How many were you?
We were about seven or eight people
And we were taken in one after another
My turn came, so I went in
They brought me in and made me sit there
One of them sat in front of me
He asked me about the charge against me, and I told him it was robbery
Then he asked me what kind of robbery
I told him it was robbery from my uncle’s house
And that the house had been confiscated
After he learned that
He ordered that we be sent back inside
Meaning upstairs
So they sent me back along with three others
And the rest were released
They took us back to the hall upstairs
The three halls upstairs were empty at the time
Only three of us remained
The others were also convicted of theft
We spent about two days in the hall
Then they told us the judge had ruled to release us, and they asked us to go with them
Interviewer: Before they released you
And specifically in the investigation room
Were you blindfolded while you spoke with the judge?
Could you see them, or did they prevent you?
I was blindfolded and did not see them
Interviewer: Were you able to identify the person who spoke with you?
And did the interrogation involve any kind of insults or abuse?
No, he just asked me about my charge, and I answered that it was theft
Then he asked me what kind of theft—whether it was a motorcycle
I told him, No, it was robbing a house with “confiscated” written on it
So he ordered that I be sent back upstairs
And they did
I stayed upstairs for two days
Then they came to take me when the release decision came out
And they asked me to go with them
Interviewer: Did they threaten you with execution or harming your family during the interrogation?
Or with long prison terms if you didn’t confess, for example?
They threatened to kill me if I did not confess
Meaning my execution
Interviewer: And that was when you were in prison?
Yes, in prison
Interviewer: Do you mean the previous prison?
Yes, they told me that if I didn’t confess, they would behead me
They said, "If you don’t confess, we’ll cut off your head"
Interviewer: When you entered the investigation room
Were you able to tell how many ISIS members were standing around you?
Could you see anything from under the blindfold?
What did you notice?
There were chairs here
And an ISIS member sat in front of me
So I tried to lift my head, but the ISIS member ordered me to lower it and not raise it again
I tried that twice, but he hit me and ordered me not to raise my head
So I stayed standing without moving
Interviewer: Was he the judge?
No, he was another member, while the judge sat in front of me
After some time, he ordered me to sit
So I sat on my knees
I sat on the floor
Interviewer: What went on between you?
He asked me about the type of charge
I answered that it was theft
There was a small bell next to him
He pressed the bell, so someone came
The judge ordered him to take me back upstairs, so he did
Interviewer: During the interrogation, did they offer you to work with them as a spy?
Whether outside or inside the prison
Meaning to become a spy among the prisoners or even outside the prison
As a condition for your release?
Did they threaten to harm your family members?
No, they didn’t threaten me like that
Interviewer: Did you feel anything unusual during the interrogation?
Were they recording your voice or filming you, for example?
Did you feel something like that while you were blindfolded?
I felt that when I was in prison
I felt they were recording my voice
I mean at Dawasa Prison
Then they transferred us here
Interviewer: And here you didn’t feel anything unusual
No, I didn’t feel that
Interviewer: What did this room look like then?
It was clean and furnished
And there was a TV screen
They showed ISIS videos on it
Videos and jihadi chants
Interviewer: What else was in the room?
The judge was sitting here
There were seats, bedding, and the TV screen
And the equipment and weapons were all here
Interviewer: What happened after they took you upstairs?
The halls were empty and I stayed there with two other people
Interviewer: What kind of theft were the ones with you accused of?
One of them broke into a shop
And the other had previously been sentenced to a hand amputation, but they brought him here again
For theft too, and this time they amputated his leg
Interviewer: Did you know them?
No, I didn’t
Interviewer: Do you remember how many ISIS members spoke with you?
Do you remember their nationalities?
And do you remember the nationality of the sharia judge?
Or their names, for example?
I don’t know them, but the one who was sitting here
He was heavily built
His beard was long and red
He had dyed it red
I don’t know what they called him
Interviewer: What was his nationality?
Syrian, I think
Interviewer: Did you sense that from the way he spoke?
Yes