My name is Younes
I was born in 1969
I work as a driver
My living conditions are average
My education only goes up
to sixth grade in primary school
Interviewer: In what year and how
were you detained in this prison?
And what was the charge
you were detained for?
In July 2016
I was detained because I’d driven a woman alone in the car,
without a mahram [male guardian]
They took my
personal papers, my ID
I came to get the ID,
so they detained me
I was detained for one day, then I
was whipped 100 lashes and released
I mean, I got my ID
In July
I came to get my ID, and
they brought me into this place
An ISIS member brought
me to the investigative judge
He interrogated me
He wrote on the slip, "Detained"
I stayed for one day
and was whipped there
And I walked out while
my hands were shackled
But my eyes weren't blindfolded
Because my charge wasn't
serious; it was just for arguing
Before I came here, I didn't
know about these places
The ones they detained me
in — I didn't know they existed
Interviewer: How did you feel
when you arrived at this place?
I arrived thinking they
would hand me my ID
And when the investigative judge
learned I had argued with that ISIS member
Their judge ruled that I
should spend the night in prison
And be whipped 100
lashes, then released
So I was released
on the second day
When I reached the prison,
they took me to the interrogator
He saw the slip and
asked, Why did you argue?
I told him I didn't argue
over anything, I'm a taxi driver
And the taxi is on the
street, anyone can ride
Whether a woman or a man
Anyone can ride,
that's why it's a taxi
He said, Without a
mahram, it's forbidden
She was alone, and I
argued with him, so he wrote
On the slip: Carries
a woman alone
And he says, We'll quit
working and sit at home
The interrogator asked me about that, and I told
him, Yes, then we'll quit working and sit at home
Because our work is the taxi
He told the ISIS member,
Take him to prison
And whip him 100 lashes
So the ISIS member took
me to the prison upstairs
Made me go up, and I
stayed until the second day
They called him Abu
Hurayra, not by his name
Each of them had a nom de
guerre they used for themselves
Abu So-and-so... Abu Hurayra
The one who interrogated
me was called Abu Hurayra
Bearded ISIS member
Interrogator
Interviewer: What kind of
questions did the interrogator ask?
He asked me for my ID
He asked, What did they
take from you? I told him, My ID
Then he asked, he
said, Why did they take it?
I answered, I told him, Because
of a woman who was alone
She was riding
with me in the car
I went upstairs and sat with
a group who were detained
I greeted them and sat down
We talked among ourselves, but we were afraid
there might be an undercover informant among us
No one could talk about ISIS
For fear of the undercover
informant inside the prisons
Who would pass the information
to ISIS if you talked about them
Like if you said, Tomorrow the liberation
will come, or The army will arrive
There is an undercover informant who tells
them that this person talked about them.
That is frightening; we did not
discuss anything specific about them.
We only talked about our release
Interviewer: How did you feel when you were
detained during that time and for that duration?
I arrived at noon, and the
next day at ten I was released
But a prisoner in a room
Meaning a door shut on you
How would I feel?
Interviewer: How did you
spend your time in the room?
We just sat, slept, or talked among ourselves
about the charges brought against us
About our charges and the
conversations going on in the hall
Interviewer: Didn’t you
feel that one of the people...
Wanted some information from
you, from the prisoners themselves?
No, no
No, there was nothing like that
You’re afraid to talk, you know
If your tongue
slipped with any words
They might cut off your head
if you spoke badly about them
I mean, they execute
the person on the spot
Anyone who crosses the
line and talks about them
Interviewer: Didn’t they stop
you from talking inside the room?
We could talk about anything among
ourselves, but not about them… ISIS
They have nothing to do with
you if you talk about something else
Or if you get to know one of them and ask
him how many children he has, and so on
Just conversations
to pass the time
When we talked among
ourselves as prisoners
Just to make the time pass
And he talks to you and
gets some things off his chest
To ease his mind
The smell of the room—the
stench of sweaty bodies
Of the detainees, some of whom
had been detained for four or five days
Because there were
no showers to bathe
You couldn’t bathe and the like
And sounds,
sounds—a lot of noise
Their voices, those of
ISIS, as they go in and out
These sounds
And the voices of people who
come on charges and accusations
In many matters
Those they bring into the
prison and those they take out
These sounds
And most of them here were ISIS,
the Hisba group [religious police]
They brought two
meals, morning and noon
They would bring rice
and broth, that was at noon
And in the morning they
gave you a samoon [bread roll]
Or a biscuit or some dates
That's what they gave
Or biscuit with dates
Because most of them ate dates
Dates with biscuit, or
dates with a samoon
And at noon, rice
They would bring it in large
dishes and everyone ate from them
Interviewer: Was there a
race for the food, for example?
To get your share from the big dish they
brought, or was there a portion for each person?
No, no, each person got a
disposable plate just for him
Interviewer: Was the
amount of food enough?
There was no choice. I
spent only one night here
And I ate one meal at noon
until the following morning
So they brought
us biscuit and dates
Of that small-sized biscuit
And a little bit of dates
with it, and that's all
After that I didn't
eat with them
Interviewer: So were
the meals regular?
They would bring
it at one or 2 p.m.
And they brought
breakfast to us at 9 a.m.
Dates and biscuit
I didn't eat anything else here
Even at night there
was no dinner meal
The last meal was lunch
If you were in great need, you
would knock on the door and call him
You would tell him, I want
to go to the washrooms
He would open the
door and let you out
But it wasn't your
choice to get out
Only at specific times
One by one, he would take them
to the toilet and bring them back
Interviewer: So
there was a schedule?
If someone needed
to go in the morning
He would knock on the door and tell
him, I just want to go to the washrooms
He would let him out to the washrooms
and then bring him back inside
Interviewer: How clean was
the place, and was there water?
There was water in the place
As for cleanliness,
the tiles were clean
There was no mattress to sleep
on. You slept directly on the floor
Meaning there was
no bedding under you
On the tiles
Interviewer: I mean the
cleanliness of the toilet?
Whoever goes in washes his spot
He cleans the toilet
area then leaves
As clean as he can manage.
Interviewer: Did you have privacy when you went to the
toilet, or was there only a short time to get in and out?
When we went to the
toilet, we went normally
But you had to let him
know when you needed to
You told him and he would let you out, but
if you didn't need to, you stayed seated
Interviewer: So when you went in, you spent
the time you needed and then came out?
Yes, yes
Interviewer: Some people said
they wanted to go to the toilet
Just to get a bit of
privacy to sit by themselves
To sit alone for a
moment inside the toilet
Did any prisoner go out to
take advantage of that time?
Some of them would go and stay
for 10 minutes or a quarter hour,
and then come back
The others would go out
and come back quickly
I mean, in the same place where
you're sitting, your mind wanders
In the same place you're
detained, in the prison itself
your mind drifts
from time to time
We were about 30
people in that room
Interviewer: Don't
you know their names?
There was Muhammad
and a guy called Ubaid
And Khaled. Those were the names
And one from the Zanjili area
and another from Yarmouk
From those areas
The ones next to me would
sit and I'd talk with them
Interviewer: What were the charges
most prisoners were detained for?
Most were paperwork-related
cases, evidence documents
Someone who had
argued with an ISIS member
and someone who had
given a woman a ride alone
These are the ones with files
against them, the ones kept in this room
I mean, light
sentences and so on
Interviewer: How was your
relationship with the prisoners?
Our relationship—well,
they're Iraqis from Mosul
Prisoners together, it was good
There were no problems with them
Interviewer: Was
there a spy among you?
We didn't know, but
there probably was
Because ISIS had secret
informants everywhere
It could be a child of seven to eight
years old acting as their informant
or an elderly man, or a young
man—they could all be informants
They had their own informants
Interviewer: Did any prisoner
try to escape from the prison?
No one could escape. Every door was
locked, so how could anyone run away?
Wherever you went,
there was an ISIS member
They didn't call you by
name, only by nicknames
And this jailer was Iraqi
Meaning he wasn't
from outside Iraq
But from the villages and countryside
outside Mosul, not from inside it
His accent was
from outside Mosul
Interviewer: Didn't you see
other nationalities in this prison?
No, I didn't
Interviewer: What types of
torture were common in this prison?
They flog people here
I mean, they sentence
people to flogging
Interviewer: What affected you more,
psychological torture or physical torture?
Honestly, the physical torture. My back was injured
and I had to sleep on my stomach for ten days
Because of the beating—I mean, a
hundred lashes isn’t a small number
Interviewer: Were there specific punishments,
like sukhra [forced labor] for example?
They would force prisoners
to do cleaning and other tasks
No, they wouldn’t let
them leave the prison at all
They wouldn’t let them out
Interviewer: When you entered the torture
room, did you see other torture tools?
I only saw the flogging—I
mean, the flogger
He was standing
there flogging me
Only the flogger was there
Interviewer: What’s the instrument?
Witness: This is the flogging instrument
A stick with a
leather belt—the whip
And he hits
With every lash he tells you,
Ask your Lord for forgiveness
With every lash he says, Ask your Lord for
forgiveness, and I repeat, I ask God’s forgiveness
Interviewer: How intense
were the lashes you received?
They flogged me lightly at first,
then the force of the lashes increased
So the body would go numb
first, then he started hitting hard
Interviewer: Did the torture include all
prisoners, or was there discrimination?
There were floggings and other things, but what
I know is that I was flogged and then released
But I didn’t see other
types of torture in front of me
But I heard about
other kinds of torture
Like the al-Adada [biting
clamp] and beatings.
There was also
kicking and slapping
As they wished
And according to
what the judge decided
The judge determines the number of
lashes, a hundred lashes or fifty lashes
And there are other
prisons with more torture
And their torture is very severe
Interviewer: Can you describe
the torture official who flogged you?
His age, appearance,
the way he talked?
His nationality?
He was about
twenty-five years old
He was Iraqi, from the
villages and countryside
It was clear he was Iraqi
And bearded
And wearing that
Kandahari outfit
And his accent was Iraqi
But not from inside Mosul, rather
from outside it, as his accent made clear
Honestly, the torture was painful. After he flogged
me a hundred lashes, my back hurt for ten days
It hurt from the beating marks
And my mental state
was affected a bit
I mean, an old
man getting flogged
They don’t respect age,
neither old nor young
They had no respect at all
Interviewer: As you told me, you spent ten days
sleeping on your stomach so your back wouldn’t be harmed
During that time after you were released
from prison, how were you able to sleep?
Didn't you have
dreams and nightmares?
No, but my back hurt
badly from the beating
I mean I couldn’t
sleep on my back
And on my side I couldn’t sleep
either—I could only sleep on my stomach
Even with medical ointments
With a skin-healing ointment,
because the body was severely damaged
It was as if you’d had a
severe sunburn on your back
Gradually the skin at the beating
marks started to peel off and regenerate
After that the skin
healed, thank God
To this day I remember
going into the prison
And how it happened
How the torture
was, and the release
That’s my story, and
it’s still on my mind
And how I appeared before
the Investigative Judge
And how we were taken up to
the prison and how I was flogged
I still remember
all of this story
From 2015 until now,
eight years have passed
That unemployment, the psychological
state, and the pressure on us
I used to work outside
Iraq in the oil sector
At Qaiwan Oil Company
I worked and traveled,
and my spirits were fine
I didn’t use any medicine back
then, not even paracetamol
But when ISIS came in,
we were left without work
And the mental state
deteriorated from the oppression
You need to provide for
your living and your family
And children—you have
to secure your livelihood
And we couldn’t leave
Because they threatened us
not to go out to the oil company
To work in oil
And they took a
written pledge from us
When we returned
from Iran to Erbil
And entered Iraq—via Mosul
They took a written pledge
that we wouldn’t go back there
To work
If we left, they
would kill our families
So we stayed in
Mosul and didn’t leave
And when the liberation
happened—we were liberated
Interviewer: Is there a story on
your mind that you’d like to mention?
Well, my story is that when
I came here, I’ve been sick
I’ve been sick for
about five or six years
Because of the psychological
trauma I went through because of them
I mean, since ISIS came and
because of the living conditions
I got sick, and to
this day I’m still sick
And suffering
I used to be a truck driver, both inside and
outside Iraq, traveling to different provinces
I had a tractor-trailer
under my control
I was happy and at ease
But since ISIS came in, and even now, my
mental state has deteriorated and I'm exhausted
How can I say this? A
person gets angry quickly
I mean, I start
reacting to anything
I had property, thank God
And all that was
lost during the ISIS days
My car burned
And they confiscated things
Thank God