In July
I came to get my ID, and
they brought me into this place
An ISIS member brought
me to the investigative judge
He interrogated me
He wrote on the slip, "Detained"
I stayed for one day
and was whipped there
And I walked out while
my hands were shackled
But my eyes weren't blindfolded
Because my charge wasn't
serious; it was just for arguing
Before I came here, I didn't
know about these places
The ones they detained me
in — I didn't know they existed
Interviewer: How did you feel
when you arrived at this place?
I arrived thinking they
would hand me my ID
And when the investigative judge
learned I had argued with that ISIS member
Their judge ruled that I
should spend the night in prison
And be whipped 100
lashes, then released
So I was released
on the second day