I went upstairs and sat with
a group who were detained
I greeted them and sat down
We talked among ourselves, but we were afraid
there might be an undercover informant among us
No one could talk about ISIS
For fear of the undercover
informant inside the prisons
Who would pass the information
to ISIS if you talked about them
Like if you said, Tomorrow the liberation
will come, or The army will arrive
There is an undercover informant who tells
them that this person talked about them.
That is frightening; we did not
discuss anything specific about them.
We only talked about our release
Interviewer: How did you feel when you were
detained during that time and for that duration?
I arrived at noon, and the
next day at ten I was released
But a prisoner in a room
Meaning a door shut on you
How would I feel?
Interviewer: How did you
spend your time in the room?
We just sat, slept, or talked among ourselves
about the charges brought against us
About our charges and the
conversations going on in the hall
Interviewer: Didn’t you
feel that one of the people...
Wanted some information from
you, from the prisoners themselves?
No, no
No, there was nothing like that
You’re afraid to talk, you know
If your tongue
slipped with any words
They might cut off your head
if you spoke badly about them
I mean, they execute
the person on the spot
Anyone who crosses the
line and talks about them
Interviewer: Didn’t they stop
you from talking inside the room?
We could talk about anything among
ourselves, but not about them… ISIS
They have nothing to do with
you if you talk about something else
Or if you get to know one of them and ask
him how many children he has, and so on
Just conversations
to pass the time
When we talked among
ourselves as prisoners
Just to make the time pass
And he talks to you and
gets some things off his chest
To ease his mind