If you were in great need, you
would knock on the door and call him
You would tell him, I want
to go to the washrooms
He would open the
door and let you out
But it wasn't your
choice to get out
Only at specific times
One by one, he would take them
to the toilet and bring them back
Interviewer: So
there was a schedule?
If someone needed
to go in the morning
He would knock on the door and tell
him, I just want to go to the washrooms
He would let him out to the washrooms
and then bring him back inside
Interviewer: How clean was
the place, and was there water?
There was water in the place
As for cleanliness,
the tiles were clean
There was no mattress to sleep
on. You slept directly on the floor
Meaning there was
no bedding under you
On the tiles
Interviewer: I mean the
cleanliness of the toilet?
Whoever goes in washes his spot
He cleans the toilet
area then leaves
As clean as he can manage.
Interviewer: Did you have privacy when you went to the
toilet, or was there only a short time to get in and out?
When we went to the
toilet, we went normally
But you had to let him
know when you needed to
You told him and he would let you out, but
if you didn't need to, you stayed seated
Interviewer: So when you went in, you spent
the time you needed and then came out?
Yes, yes
Interviewer: Some people said
they wanted to go to the toilet
Just to get a bit of
privacy to sit by themselves
To sit alone for a
moment inside the toilet
Did any prisoner go out to
take advantage of that time?
Some of them would go and stay
for 10 minutes or a quarter hour,
and then come back
The others would go out
and come back quickly
I mean, in the same place where
you're sitting, your mind wanders
In the same place you're
detained, in the prison itself
your mind drifts
from time to time