They brought two
meals, morning and noon
They would bring rice
and broth, that was at noon
And in the morning they
gave you a samoon [bread roll]
Or a biscuit or some dates
That's what they gave
Or biscuit with dates
Because most of them ate dates
Dates with biscuit, or
dates with a samoon
And at noon, rice
They would bring it in large
dishes and everyone ate from them
Interviewer: Was there a
race for the food, for example?
To get your share from the big dish they
brought, or was there a portion for each person?
No, no, each person got a
disposable plate just for him
Interviewer: Was the
amount of food enough?
There was no choice. I
spent only one night here
And I ate one meal at noon
until the following morning
So they brought
us biscuit and dates
Of that small-sized biscuit
And a little bit of dates
with it, and that's all
After that I didn't
eat with them
Interviewer: So were
the meals regular?
They would bring
it at one or 2 p.m.
And they brought
breakfast to us at 9 a.m.
Dates and biscuit
I didn't eat anything else here
Even at night there
was no dinner meal
The last meal was lunch