We were about 30
people in that room
Interviewer: Don't
you know their names?
There was Muhammad
and a guy called Ubaid
And Khaled. Those were the names
And one from the Zanjili area
and another from Yarmouk
From those areas
The ones next to me would
sit and I'd talk with them
Interviewer: What were the charges
most prisoners were detained for?
Most were paperwork-related
cases, evidence documents
Someone who had
argued with an ISIS member
and someone who had
given a woman a ride alone
These are the ones with files
against them, the ones kept in this room
I mean, light
sentences and so on
Interviewer: How was your
relationship with the prisoners?
Our relationship—well,
they're Iraqis from Mosul
Prisoners together, it was good
There were no problems with them
Interviewer: Was
there a spy among you?
We didn't know, but
there probably was
Because ISIS had secret
informants everywhere
It could be a child of seven to eight
years old acting as their informant
or an elderly man, or a young
man—they could all be informants
They had their own informants
Interviewer: Did any prisoner
try to escape from the prison?
No one could escape. Every door was
locked, so how could anyone run away?
Wherever you went,
there was an ISIS member