When I reached the prison,
they took me to the interrogator
He saw the slip and
asked, Why did you argue?
I told him I didn't argue
over anything, I'm a taxi driver
And the taxi is on the
street, anyone can ride
Whether a woman or a man
Anyone can ride,
that's why it's a taxi
He said, Without a
mahram, it's forbidden
She was alone, and I
argued with him, so he wrote
On the slip: Carries
a woman alone
And he says, We'll quit
working and sit at home
The interrogator asked me about that, and I told
him, Yes, then we'll quit working and sit at home
Because our work is the taxi
He told the ISIS member,
Take him to prison
And whip him 100 lashes
So the ISIS member took
me to the prison upstairs
Made me go up, and I
stayed until the second day
They called him Abu
Hurayra, not by his name
Each of them had a nom de
guerre they used for themselves
Abu So-and-so... Abu Hurayra
The one who interrogated
me was called Abu Hurayra
Bearded ISIS member
Interrogator
Interviewer: What kind of
questions did the interrogator ask?
He asked me for my ID
He asked, What did they
take from you? I told him, My ID
Then he asked, he
said, Why did they take it?
I answered, I told him, Because
of a woman who was alone
She was riding
with me in the car