Interviewer: What types of
torture were common in this prison?
They flog people here
I mean, they sentence
people to flogging
Interviewer: What affected you more,
psychological torture or physical torture?
Honestly, the physical torture. My back was injured
and I had to sleep on my stomach for ten days
Because of the beating—I mean, a
hundred lashes isn’t a small number
Interviewer: Were there specific punishments,
like sukhra [forced labor] for example?
They would force prisoners
to do cleaning and other tasks
No, they wouldn’t let
them leave the prison at all
They wouldn’t let them out
Interviewer: When you entered the torture
room, did you see other torture tools?
I only saw the flogging—I
mean, the flogger
He was standing
there flogging me
Only the flogger was there
Interviewer: What’s the instrument?
Witness: This is the flogging instrument
A stick with a
leather belt—the whip
And he hits
With every lash he tells you,
Ask your Lord for forgiveness
With every lash he says, Ask your Lord for
forgiveness, and I repeat, I ask God’s forgiveness
Interviewer: How intense
were the lashes you received?
They flogged me lightly at first,
then the force of the lashes increased
So the body would go numb
first, then he started hitting hard
Interviewer: Did the torture include all
prisoners, or was there discrimination?
There were floggings and other things, but what
I know is that I was flogged and then released
But I didn’t see other
types of torture in front of me
But I heard about
other kinds of torture
Like the al-Adada [biting
clamp] and beatings.
There was also
kicking and slapping
As they wished
And according to
what the judge decided
The judge determines the number of
lashes, a hundred lashes or fifty lashes
And there are other
prisons with more torture
And their torture is very severe
Interviewer: Can you describe
the torture official who flogged you?
His age, appearance,
the way he talked?
His nationality?
He was about
twenty-five years old
He was Iraqi, from the
villages and countryside
It was clear he was Iraqi
And bearded
And wearing that
Kandahari outfit
And his accent was Iraqi
But not from inside Mosul, rather
from outside it, as his accent made clear