Honestly, the torture was painful. After he flogged
me a hundred lashes, my back hurt for ten days
It hurt from the beating marks
And my mental state
was affected a bit
I mean, an old
man getting flogged
They don’t respect age,
neither old nor young
They had no respect at all
Interviewer: As you told me, you spent ten days
sleeping on your stomach so your back wouldn’t be harmed
During that time after you were released
from prison, how were you able to sleep?
Didn't you have
dreams and nightmares?
No, but my back hurt
badly from the beating
I mean I couldn’t
sleep on my back
And on my side I couldn’t sleep
either—I could only sleep on my stomach
Even with medical ointments
With a skin-healing ointment,
because the body was severely damaged
It was as if you’d had a
severe sunburn on your back
Gradually the skin at the beating
marks started to peel off and regenerate
After that the skin
healed, thank God