That unemployment, the psychological
state, and the pressure on us
I used to work outside
Iraq in the oil sector
At Qaiwan Oil Company
I worked and traveled,
and my spirits were fine
I didn’t use any medicine back
then, not even paracetamol
But when ISIS came in,
we were left without work
And the mental state
deteriorated from the oppression
You need to provide for
your living and your family
And children—you have
to secure your livelihood
And we couldn’t leave
Because they threatened us
not to go out to the oil company
To work in oil
And they took a
written pledge from us
When we returned
from Iran to Erbil
And entered Iraq—via Mosul
They took a written pledge
that we wouldn’t go back there
To work
If we left, they
would kill our families
So we stayed in
Mosul and didn’t leave
And when the liberation
happened—we were liberated
Interviewer: Is there a story on
your mind that you’d like to mention?
Well, my story is that when
I came here, I’ve been sick
I’ve been sick for
about five or six years
Because of the psychological
trauma I went through because of them
I mean, since ISIS came and
because of the living conditions
I got sick, and to
this day I’m still sick
And suffering
I used to be a truck driver, both inside and
outside Iraq, traveling to different provinces
I had a tractor-trailer
under my control
I was happy and at ease
But since ISIS came in, and even now, my
mental state has deteriorated and I'm exhausted
How can I say this? A
person gets angry quickly
I mean, I start
reacting to anything
I had property, thank God
And all that was
lost during the ISIS days
My car burned
And they confiscated things
Thank God
And praise be to God